<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section id="sample-1-using-the-swing-simple-adder" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                  xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Sample 1: using the Swing Simple Adder</title>
  <para>
    You can start the Swing SimpleAdder using the configurations for
    the <emphasis>SimpleAdder</emphasis> AUT. For Windows and Linux,
    you can choose whether you want to use the JRE installed with
    the ITE or your system JRE. Mac users can use the Mac
    configuration to start the SimpleAdder with their default Java
    version.
  </para>
  <section id="samplesteststeps">
    <title>Sample 1.1: creating a Test Case from Test Steps</title>
    <para>
      This category contains one Test Case. The Test Case contains
      four Test Steps, which test an addition in the Simple Adder.
      The parameter values in the Test Steps have been referenced,
      and a data set has been added.
    </para>
    <para>
      This is an example of a test written with Test Steps. However,
      we recommend using the library of Test Cases to write tests,
      as shown in the next examples.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="sampleslibrary">
    <title>Sample 1.2: creating a Test Case using the
    library</title>
    <para>
      This category contains one Test Case. The Test Case has
      referenced another Test Case, with four reused Test Cases,
      which have been reused from the Project
      <emphasis>unbound_modules_concrete</emphasis>. <para role="tip">Press
      <emphasis role="input">»F6«</emphasis> to find where a particular
      Test Case was originally specified. </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      The Test Cases carry out the same steps as in the previous example (<xref linkend="samplesteststeps"/>). The differences here are:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The steps to enter a value both reuse the same Test Case,
          with different referenced parameters, and a different
          component name.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The components used in the reused Test Cases are
          <emphasis>abstract</emphasis> components
          (<xref linkend="understanding-the-component-hierarchy"/>). This means that the Test Cases
          are easier to reuse, making tests more robust and
          maintainable.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      This Test Case is reused in the executable Test Case
      <emphasis>1.2_SIMPLE_ADDER_TEST</emphasis>, which is nested in
      the Test Suite of the same name.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="sample-1.3-using-event-handlers">
    <title>Sample 1.3: using Event Handlers</title>
    <para>
      This category has four subcategories. Each subcategory
      contains a test which reuses a Test Case to execute a
      calculation in the Simple Adder which will cause an error.
      After the error, a reset is carried out.
    </para>
    <para>
      An Event Handler has been specified in the
      <emphasis>bound_modules_samples</emphasis> Project. The Event
      Handler has been added to the Test Case, and checks that text
      in the result field is <emphasis>jackpot</emphasis>.
    </para>
    <para>
      The four tests are as follows:
    </para>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Continue</emphasis><?linebreak?>
      The Event Handler in this test has the reentry property <emphasis>continue</emphasis>. When the error occurs, the Event Handler is activated. Once the check has been carried out, the test continues, and the reset is performed.
    </para>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Exit</emphasis><?linebreak?>
      The Event Handler in this test has the reentry property <emphasis>exit</emphasis>. When the error occurs, the Event Handler is activated. Once the check has been carried out, the test finishes. The reset is not performed.
    </para>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Pause</emphasis><?linebreak?>
      The Event Handler in this test has the reentry property <emphasis>pause</emphasis>. When the error occurs, the Event Handler is activated. Once the check has been carried out, the test pauses. By un-pausing the Test Suite in the client, the test continues.
    </para>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Retry</emphasis><?linebreak?>
      The Event Handler in this test is different to the Event Handler in the other tests. It contains the same steps as the test itself, but the parameter references have been switched. This essentially changes the order in which the numbers are entered into the Simple Adder. The Event Handler has the reentry property <emphasis>retry</emphasis>. When the error occurs, the Event Handler is activated. The calculation is redone with the switched values. The failed Test Step (i.e. the original check) is retried, and there is no error. The test is marked as successful.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>