<section xml:id="new-features-and-developments-5.2" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                              xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>New Features and Developments</title>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Embedded gdagent</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you are starting your AUT and running your tests on your
        local machine, you can now connect to an embedded AUT Agent
        directly from the ITE.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This saves you having to start an AUT Agent on localhost.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This is also useful for testers working with Jubula as a
        feature in an Eclipse installation.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The embedded AUT Agent is started on port 60000 by default;
        this number can be changed in the preferences.
      </para>
      <figure xml:id="RNEmbeddedAgent">
        <title>Embedded AUT Agent</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/EmbeddedAgent.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>Embedded AUT Agent</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Refactor: Replace with Test
    Case</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the Test Case Editor and Test Suite Editor, there is a new
        option to replace one or more selected Test Cases with another
        Test Case from the library.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        A new wizard takes you step-by-step through the replacement
        process, letting you transfer component names, match
        parameters and add further information for the new Test Case.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This feature should help testers who want to restructure their
        tests after creating a reusable module to replace one or more
        Test Cases.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Object Mapping Editor: Cleanup unused
    component names</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the Object Mapping Editor, there is a new option in the
        context-sensitive menu.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Via <emphasis role="menuPath">Cleanup</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">unused component names</emphasis><?linebreak?>
        you can start a search for any component names that are no longer used in Test Suites for this AUT.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Once the search is finished, you can delete all of these
        unused names from the Object Mapping Editor. If they are then
        no longer used in the entire Project, they can be deleted from
        the Component Names Browser.
      </para>
      <figure xml:id="RNDeleteUnusedCN">
        <title>Deleting unused Component Names</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/DeleteUnusedCompNames.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>Deleting unused Component
          Names</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">HTML Test Result Reports can be expanded
    again</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Following changes made for the initial contribution to
        Eclipse, the HTML Test Result Reports could not be viewed
        properly in the previous version.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In this release, the nodes in the HTML reports can be expanded
        and collapsed to view the whole test progress.
      </para>
      <figure xml:id="RNHTMLReport">
        <title>HTML Reports</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/HTMLReport.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>HTML Reports</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para xml:id="RNCompRec">
    <emphasis role="strong">State of component recognition displayed
    when collecting technical names</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When a component (technical name) is collected from an AUT, it
        receives a colored dot corresponding to the accuracy of the
        object recognition for this component <emphasis>at the time of
        collecting</emphasis>.
      </para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            A green dot
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              signifies that the component could be found with an
              exact match, and was the only component above the
              threshold.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            A yellow dot
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              means that the component is an exact match, but that
              multiple other components were also above the threshold.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            A red dot
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
               means that this component cannot be relocated in the
              current state of the AUT
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        As a side effect, the colors on the component names (green)
        and technical names (red) that were displayed in previous
        versions are now no longer shown. Once the Object Mapping
        Editor has been saved, all names are shown with plain black
        icons.
      </para>
      <figure xml:id="RNColorDot">
        <title>Colored Dots for Object Mapping</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/ColorDot.png"/>
          </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>Colored Dots for Object
          Mapping</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Migration wizard re-enabled</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When migrating to the new version of Jubula, the migration
        assistant will automatically notify you that your database
        scheme is out-of-date.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can then select which Projects to import (these must have
        been exported from the database prior to migrating!).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The assistant will drop the tables in the database, recreate
        the necessary tables and import the Projects you specified.
      </para>
      <figure xml:id="RNMigration">
        <title>Migration Wizard</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Migration.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>Migration Wizard</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Copy ID to Clipboard also for Test
    Suites</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The ability to copy a unique ID to the clipboard to reference
        a Jubula element in external systems has also been implemented
        for Test Suites.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now copy the ID of a Test Case or a Test Suite to the
        clipboard, and also open an element based on its ID in the
        clipboard using <emphasis role="input">»Shift+F9«</emphasis>
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">The DBTool is more verbose</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The command line tool to import, export and delete Projects in
        the database, the DBTool, has been updated so that it is more
        verbose.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Progress View</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The ITE now uses the progress view to show longer-running
        activities such as test execution, connecting to AUTs etc.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Edit Parameters Dialog in Central Test
    Data Editor can be opened via double-click</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the Central Test Data Editor it is no longer necessary to
        open the Edit Parameters Dialog via context-menu, as it can
        now also be opened via double-click on the data set you wish
        to edit.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Mac keyboards now supported, new mechanism
    for adding keyboard layout files</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the AUT configuration dialog for SWT and RCP AUTs, the
        <emphasis>Keyboard Layout</emphasis> combo box now only offers
        layouts that have been defined for Jubula. German (DE) and
        English (US) are defined as standard.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        As well as being able to add keyboard layouts for other
        keyboards, you can also define platform-specific keyboard
        layouts (e.g. for Mac)
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The documentation has been updated to describe the new
        mechanism for adding keyboard layouts.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Object mapping: Degree of recognition
    accuracy for a test run can be viewed</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The Object Mapping Editor has been extended so that the
        accuracy of component recognition is persisted and can be
        displayed.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        As well as displaying the state of component recognition when
        a technical name is collected from the AUT <xref linkend="RNCompRec"/>,
        the degree of recognition accuracy is also noted for each test
        run.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can see the values for the recognition accuracy in two new
        BIRT reports in Jubula.
      </para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            OMNameQuality
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              shows a breakdown of the component names used in your
              test, and displays the degree of accuracy they were
              located during the test. You can use this report to see
              whether there are any component names that may need to
              be remapped (i.e. who are close to the threshold of not
              being found) before the test encounters a
              <emphasis>Component Not Found</emphasis> error. 
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            OMNameQualityChart
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This report is a visual (graph) representation of the
              accuracy with which components were located during the
              test run. You can use the report to help you decide
              which components may need to be remapped, as they may
              soon result in a <emphasis>Component Not
              Found</emphasis> error during the test.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Mylyn: Refactored Test Cases are added to
    context</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When working on a Mylyn task in app, Test Cases you create
        using the <emphasis>refactor</emphasis> function are now
        automatically added to the context.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Mylyn: Test Cases opened via
    <emphasis role="input">»Ctrl+Shift+T«</emphasis> are added to
    context</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When working on a Mylyn task in Jubula, Test Cases opened
        using the key combination
        <emphasis role="input">»Ctrl+Shift+T«</emphasis> are now
        automatically added to the context.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Mylyn: Test Cases added via Test Case
    reference dialog are added to context</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When working on a Mylyn task in Jubula, Test Cases added using
        the <emphasis>Add Test Case reference</emphasis> dialog are
        now automatically added to the context.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Teststyle: Rules can now be viewed via the
    Properties View</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When working with Teststyle, you can now open the Project properties dialog to see the rule that has been flouted via:<?linebreak?>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Show Teststyle Rule</emphasis><?linebreak?>
        from the Problems View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Changes to BIRT reports</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The BIRT report GUIdancerFULL has been removed.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        There are new BIRT reports:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis>GUIdancerComments</emphasis> shows a table of
            all failed relevant tests for the time specified,
            including the comment title that can be entered in the
            Test Result Summary View. This report is useful for
            delivering daily status reports of the tests.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis>GUIdancerDuration</emphasis> shows the duration
            of the chosen tests.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis>GUIdancerExecutionHistogram</emphasis> shows the
            proportion of executed, failed and non-executed Test Steps
            for a test. This report is most useful when one specific
            Test Suite is compared to see its progress over time.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis>TestresultSummary</emphasis> shows a table of
            the Test Result Summary View for the dates and tests
            chosen.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now also enter the Test Job as a parameter for the
        report. The Test Suites in the Test Job are still displayed
        individually, however.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">License Dialog: Restart prompt</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Once a license has been added via the Preferences, a dialog is
        shown to remind you to restart Jubula before continuing.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        From the dialog you can choose to restart Jubula
        automatically.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>