<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="the-test-result-view" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                 xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>The Test Result View</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="testResultViewContextId" xml:id="the-test-result-view.testResultViewContextId" xreflabel="Test Results View"/>
  <para>
    The Test Result View (<xref linkend="testresultview"/>) tracks the test progress for each Test
    Suite, marking each Test Step as successful or unsuccessful.
  </para>
  <para>
    When the test begins, the Test Steps to be executed appear in
    the Test Result View. As each Test Step is executed, it is
    marked with a question mark. If the Test Step is successful, it
    is marked with a green tick. Failed Test Steps are marked with
    red crosses. Test Steps which succeeded after retrying
    (<xref linkend="dealing-with-errors-in-tests"/>) are marked differently to show that
    they were successful after retrying.
  </para>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Navigating in the Test Result View</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Single click on an item in the Test Result View to see
        details for that item in the Properties View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Double-click on an item in the Test Result View to be taken
        to this item in the Test Suite.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can clear the Test Result View by clicking the
        ”<emphasis>clear</emphasis>” button in the tab of the view.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Use the arrows on the toolbar to spring to the next or
        previous error in the Test Result View (you can also use the
        combinations <emphasis role="input">»ALT+UP«</emphasis> and
        <emphasis role="input">»ALT+DOWN«</emphasis>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Each node in the Test Result View shows the amount of time
        taken to execute this node. You can turn this option off in
        the preferences (<xref linkend="label-decoration-preferences"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para role="tip">
    You can also see screenshots of errors that were taken by
    selecting the screenshot from the tree in the test result tree.
    You will need to have the Image View open to see the screenshot.
    From the Image View, you can also save the image to your file
    system.
  </para>
  
  <para>
     For preferences about the Test Result View, see the
    section on the preference pages (<xref linkend="test-result-preferences"/>).
  </para>
  <figure xml:id="testresultview">
    <title>Test Result View</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/testresultview.png"/>
      </imageobject>
      <textobject><phrase>Test Result View</phrase></textobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
</section>