<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="working-with-the-test-result-summary-view" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                      xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Working with the Test Result Summary View</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultViewContextId">Test Results View</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="prefPageTestResultContextId">Test Result Preferences</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
  <para>
    A test result summary and full details about the whole test are
    stored for each test run. Individual Test Suites within a Test
    Job are counted as one test run each.
  </para>
  <para>
    You can see the test result summaries in the Reporting
    Perspective, in the Test Result Summary View.
  </para>
  <section xml:id="re-opening-the-test-result-view-for-a-test-run">
    <title>Re-opening the test result view for a test run</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If the full details for a test run are still available
          (the column <emphasis>Details</emphasis> shows
          <emphasis>true</emphasis>), you can re-open the full test
          result by double-clicking on the entry in the Test Result
          Summary View or by clicking the button to open the report
          in the top right-hand corner of the view.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the test result, you can navigate through the test
          results using the mouse or using the toolbar buttons to
          spring to the next or previous error. In this way, you can
          view any screenshots in the Image View and details about
          errors in the Properties View.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Each node in the Test Result View shows the amount of time
          taken to execute this node and any parameter values that
          were used at this node. You can turn these options off in
          the preferences (<xref linkend="label-decoration-preferences"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para role="tip">
      In the Project properties, you can specify how often
      the full reports should be automatically deleted from the
      database (<xref linkend="editing-general-project-properties"/>).
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="filtering-and-sorting-in-the-test-result-summary-view">
    <title>Filtering and sorting in the Test Result Summary View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
    <para>
      The Test Result Summary View shows a summary of each Test
      Suite that has run.
    </para>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Sorting entries in the Test Result Summary View</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
      Click on a column header to sort the table according to the
      values in this column.
    </para>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Showing and hiding columns in the Test Result Summary View</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
      In the context-menu on the column headers in the Test Result
      Summary View, you can select which columns you want to show in
      the view. Your settings for this view are saved in your
      workspace.
    </para>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Filtering in the Test Result Summary View</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
      At the top of the Test Result Summary View there is a filter.
      Choose which column you want to filter, and enter the value
      you want to filter by (use <emphasis role="input">*</emphasis> as a wildcard).
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="changing-the-amount-of-result-summaries-shown-in-the-test-result-summary-view">
    <title>Changing the amount of result summaries shown in the Test Result Summary View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
    <para>
      In the test result preferences (<xref linkend="test-result-preferences"/>) you can
      alter the amount of days that a test result summary is shown.
      The top of the Test Result Summary View shows the amount of
      days that test result summaries are being shown for. Any
      unshown summaries are still present in the database and can be
      shown by increasing the amount of days.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="changing-the-relevance-of-a-test-run">
    <title>Changing the relevance of a test run</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
    <para>
      You can change the relevance of a test run (i.e. whether it is exported with the Project
      or not) in the Test Result Summary View.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select the test run whose relevance you want to change.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select:
        </para>
          
        <para>
          <emphasis role="menuPath">Toggle relevance</emphasis>
        </para>
        
        <para>
          from the context-sensitive menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="refreshing-the-test-result-summary-view">
    <title>Refreshing the Test Result Summary View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
    <para>
      Use the ”<emphasis>Refresh</emphasis>” button
      <mediaobject role="icon" file="images/refresh.png"/> at the top
      right hand corner of the Test Result Summary View to refresh
      the view after tests have been run.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="deleting-test-runs-from-the-test-result-summary-view">
    <title>Deleting test runs from the Test Result Summary View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
    <para>
      Select one or more rows in the Test Result Summary View and use the
      ”<emphasis>Delete</emphasis>” button <mediaobject role="icon" file="images/delete.png"/>
      in the top right hand corner of the view to delete these test runs.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="resetting-column-widths">
    <title>Resetting the column widths in the Test Result
    Summary View</title>
    <para>
      You can reset the standard column widths in the Test Result
      Summary View using the button in the top right hand corner
      of the view.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="exporting-test-results-from-the-test-result-summary-view-as-html-and-xml-reports">
    <title>Exporting test results from the Test Result Summary View as HTML and XML reports</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultViewContextId">Test Results View</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select one or more test reports and select
          <emphasis role="menuPath">Export</emphasis> from the context-sensitive menu or
          click the ”<emphasis>Export</emphasis>” button on the
          toolbar of the Test Result Summary View.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the dialog that opens, enter or browse to a directory
          where the test results should be saved.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you click ”<emphasis>Finish</emphasis>”, the result
          reports for the selected test runs will be exported to the
          directory you entered.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          For each test run, an XML and an HTML file are created.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para role="tip">
      In order to export test results from the Test Result
      Summary View, details for these reports must still be in the
      database. This will be shown as <emphasis>true</emphasis> in
      the <emphasis>Details</emphasis> column in the Test Result
      Summary View.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="entering-comments-for-test-runs-in-the-test-result-summary-view">
    <title>Entering comments for test runs in the Test Result Summary View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultViewContextId">Test Results View</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultSummaryAddCommentContextId">Add Comment Dialog</anchor>
    <para>
      You can add a comment to a test run in the Test Result Summary View by:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Selecting a test run in the Test Result Summary View and
          then selecting <emphasis role="menuPath">Edit comment</emphasis> from the
          context-sensitive menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the dialog that opens, enter a title for the comment
          and a longer description in the details area.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you click ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”, the title of the
          comment is shown in the <emphasis>Comment</emphasis>
          column.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can view the details for a comment by reselecting
          <emphasis role="menuPath">Edit comment</emphasis> from the context-sensitive menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</section>