<section xml:id="new-features-and-developments-6.0.1" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>New Features and Developments</title>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Chronon support</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Jubula now allows the use of an embedded Chronon recorder and
        also the production of Chronon recording files during
        automated tests (Jubula Feature users: this feature is
        currently only available in the standalone version).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Activating the embedded Chronon recorder in Jubula will result
        in your actions being recorded in a monitoring file which can
        be used for analysis purposes should you encounter any errors.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can also configure your AUT to use Chronon as a
        monitoring agent so that you can generate recording files from
        your automated tests.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The currently used version of Chronon is 2.0. There are some
        performance issues still in this version that may lead to test
        runs and performance being affected, particularly in larger
        AUTs and Projects. Please follow the instructions in
        the documentation for increasing heap size and ensuring the
        capability of your test machines.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We do not recommend having Chronon running at all times, due
        to possible performance degradations through the monitoring.
        Instead, we recommend that you activate the Chronon recorder
        when you are trying to reproduce an error.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Tests updated to newer versions of IE and
    Firefox</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The tested versions for web AUTs now include IE 9 and
        Firefox 10
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>