<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="reentry-types" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                          xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                          xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Reentry types</title>
  <para>
    The reentry type specifies how the test should continue once the Event Handler Test Case
    has been executed.
  </para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Break
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The test execution leaves the Test Case in which the error
          occurred and continues at the next Test Case or Test Step.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Continue
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The test execution carries on at the next Test Case or
          Test Step. This is a good option when the error is
          relatively unimportant and does not affect the following
          Test Steps. 
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Exit
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The test execution is stopped. Use this when the error is
          so severe that the test cannot be continued.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Return
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The test execution leaves the Test Case in which the
          activated Event Handler is nested. This could be the
          current Test Case or one higher up in the hierarchy. This
          option is useful if you have a use case, which contains
          Test Cases to test a particular area or function. You can
          decide to leave this part of the test, and carry on at the
          next use case. <emphasis>Return</emphasis> will continue
          at the next Test Suite in a Test Job if it is activated as
          a default Event Handler or if there are no further steps
          in the current Test Suite.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Pause
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The test execution is paused. To restart the test, click
          the <emphasis>pause</emphasis> button in the toolbar in
          the ITE.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Retry
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The failed Test Step is repeated as many times as you
          specify in the Properties View. If the Test Step is
          successful on repeating, it is marked as successful after
          retrying. If the Test Step fails on all retries, the error
          type is passed on to the next parent Test Case and this
          Test Step (and therefore the test) is marked as failed. 
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>