<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="configuring-code-coverage-for-an-aut" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                 xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Configuring code coverage for an AUT</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId" xml:id="configuring-code-coverage-for-an-aut.autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId" xreflabel="Configuring an AUT"/>
  <para>
    You can activate code coverage for an AUT configuration with the
    following steps:
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Open the AUT configuration dialog from the Project
        properties (<xref linkend="projectproperties"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Select the <emphasis>Expert</emphasis> configuration.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Select the code coverage agent you wish to use
        (<emphasis>JaCoCo</emphasis> is available out-of-the-box).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can then enter the AUT installation directory and the
        AUT source directory for the code coverage:
      </para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            The AUT installation directory
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
               is the directory containing the class files (compiled
              Java files) for your AUT. You must enter this
              directory to make code coverage possible for your test
              run.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            The AUT source directories
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
               are the directories where the source files (i.e. the
              program code) for your AUT are kept. Adding a
              directory for the source files is optional, however,
              if you don't add one, then you will not be able to
              view your code coverage results at the source file
              level. The AUT source directories must contain the
              source files in their Java package structure. The
              class files must have been compiled with debug
              information to make the lines of code executed visible
              in the code coverage report.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        To make sure you only monitor your own code, enter a package
        pattern to specify which packages should be monitored. The
        pattern must be a valid regular expression. If you do not
        enter a package pattern, all classes in the virtual machine
        will be considered for the code coverage value.
      </para>
      <para role="warning">
        Not entering a package pattern can result in extremely large
        messages being sent from the AUT Agent, which may cause
        memory problems (<xref linkend="increasing-the-java-heap"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Select whether you want the code coverage value to be reset
        when a new Test Suite starts (<xref linkend="resetting-and-accumulating-code-coverage"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        During code coverage class file id collision can happen, if different classes are found with the same name.
        If you don't want to allow the collision, be sure the 'Allow class file id collision' checkbox is unchecked. It's
        unchecked by default.
        If the feature is enabled, you will only get a log entry, if an error is occurred. Bear in mind in case of enabled
        state, the jacoco monitoring report can be invalid.    
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <section xml:id="increasing-the-java-heap">
    <title>Increasing the Java Heap Space for code coverage</title>
    <para>
      Running a test with a code coverage profiler leads to an
      increased memory requirement for the ITE. You can increase the
      heap space for the ITE and also enter a package pattern
      (<xref linkend="configuring-code-coverage-for-an-aut"/>) to reduce the amount of files considered
      for code coverage.
    </para>
    <para role="tip">
      Users working with a MySQL database should also follow
      the steps from the Installation Manual to increase the maximum
      allowed packet for the database.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>