<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="resetting-and-accumulating-code-coverage" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                     xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Resetting and accumulating code coverage</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="testResultSummaryViewContextId" xml:id="resetting-and-accumulating-code-coverage.testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
  <para>
    To make sure you get the correct results for your code coverage,
    it is important to be aware of which actions will accumulate the
    recorded code coverage and which actions will reset the value
    back to zero.
  </para>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Code coverage reset</emphasis>
  </para>
  <para>
    The following result in the code coverage value being reset:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Stopping the AUT. When the AUT is started again, the code
        coverage value is reset to zero. The test executor ensures
        that all monitoring information is collected before stopping
        the AUT.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para role="warning">
    If you stop the AUT while code coverage is being
    calculated, then the value will also be set to zero!
  </para>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Code coverage accumulation</emphasis><?linebreak?>
    The following result in code coverage information being accumulated:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Any actions you perform manually in an AUT that has been
        started with code coverage will contribute to the code
        coverage result.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Code coverage is accumulated across Test Suites by default.
        If you want to reset the code coverage at the beginning of
        each Test Suite, then select this option in the AUT
        configuration (<xref linkend="configuring-code-coverage-for-an-aut"/>).
      </para>
      <para role="tip">
        If you are working with Test Jobs, then do not opt to reset the code coverage
        at the beginning of a Test Suite.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you use the <emphasis>restart</emphasis> action during a
        test, this does <emphasis role="strong">not</emphasis>
        result in the code coverage value being reset.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>