<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section id="viewing-the-code-coverage-for-a-test-run" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                     xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Viewing the code coverage for a test run</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
  <para>
    Once a test with code coverage has run, the code coverage
    information must first be processed in order to show it in the
    Test Result Summary View.
  </para>
  <para>
    The following columns are available in the Test Result Summary
    View to show you code coverage information:
  </para>
  <para>
    <para role="tip"> If a column is not visible, you can show it by selecting
    it from the context-sensitive menu on the header row for the
    Test Result Summary View.</para>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The <emphasis>Profiling Agent</emphasis> column displays
        which code coverage agent was selected for the test run.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The <emphasis>Measured Value</emphasis> column shows the Instruction Coverage for the test run. You can see the values for other types of coverage in the Properties View when you select the test run. An overview of the meanings of the coverage types is available on the JaCoCo website:
        
        <para>
          <emphasis>http://www.eclemma.org/jacoco/trunk/doc/counters.html</emphasis>.
        </para>
        
        <para role="tip">The measured value will become visible once the code coverage information has been processed. You may need to refresh the Test Result Summary View. </para>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The <emphasis>Profiling Details</emphasis> column indicates
        whether the full details for the code coverage report are
        still in the database. Full profiling details are removed
        from the database at the same time as test run details
        (<xref linkend="re-opening-the-test-result-view-for-a-test-run"/>). The period of time that
        details remain in the database can be specified in the
        Project properties (<xref linkend="editing-general-project-properties"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Opening and viewing the code coverage report</emphasis>
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the Test Result Summary View, select the test run whose
        code coverage you want to see and click the ”<emphasis>Open
        Profiling Report</emphasis>” button at the top of the view.
        <para role="warning">The details about code coverage are available in the
        database for the same amount of time as the test result
        details (<xref linkend="re-opening-the-test-result-view-for-a-test-run"/>). After this time,
        the code coverage details are deleted along with the test
        run details.</para>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the editor that opens, you can see the details for the
        code coverage for the test run.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you specified a source file directory for your AUT
        (<xref linkend="configuring-code-coverage-for-an-aut"/>) and compiled your AUT classes with debug
        information, you will be able to navigate through your
        classes to see more detailed information about the code
        coverage through the whole AUT.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Once you have opened a code coverage report, it is saved
        into your workspace. You can reopen it from the Navigation
        View. <para role="tip">You should regularly remove old code coverage
        reports from your workspace to avoid overfilling it.</para>
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
</section>