<section id="editors" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Editors</title>
  <para>
    Editors appear in the editor area in the middle of the perspective
    when you double-click an item in one of the browsers or in the
    Navigation View.
  </para>
  <para>
    You can tell what sort of editor it is in two ways:
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The tab for each editor shows an ID-code for what type of
        editor it is:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            ”<emphasis>TC</emphasis>” for the Test Case Editor
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            ”<emphasis>TS</emphasis>” for the Test Suite Editor
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            ”<emphasis>OM</emphasis>” for the Object Mapping Editor
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            ”<emphasis>TD</emphasis>” for the Central Test Data Editor
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        The tab also shows the name of the item the editor is for.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <section id="test-case-editor">
    <title>Test Case Editor</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerSpecTestCaseEditorContextId">Test Case Editor</anchor>
    <para>
      You can open the Test Case Editor by double-clicking a Test Case in the Test
      Case Browser.
    </para>
    <para>
      In the Test Case Editor:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can create, modify and delete Test Steps.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can add and delete other Test Cases.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can add Event Handlers. They appear in the Event Handler
          area below the Test Case Editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can alter test data and component names for the Test
          Case.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      When you single-click items (Test Cases, Test Steps) in the Test
      Case Editor, the support views (Properties View, Component Names
      View and Data Sets View) show details about this item. Using
      these views, you can edit the properties, test data and
      component names for this item.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="test-suite-editor">
    <title>Test Suite Editor</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSuiteEditorContextId">Test Suite Editor</anchor>
    <para>
      You can open the Test Suite Editor by double-clicking a Test
      Suite in the Test Suite Browser.
    </para>
    <para>
      In the Test Suite Editor:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can add Test Cases to Test Suites.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can alter the Test Suite properties (e.g. the AUT it
          uses, the default Event Handlers).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can alter test data for the Test Cases shown.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">In the Test Suite Editor, you can only alter details for
      the top-level Test Cases for each subtree.</para>
    </para>
    <para>
      When you single-click Test Cases in the Test Suite Editor, the
      support views (Properties View, Component Names View and Data
      Sets View) show details about this Test Case. Using these views,
      you can edit the properties, test data and component names for
      this item.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="object-mapping-editor">
    <title>Object Mapping Editor</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="objectMapEditorContextId">Object Mapping</anchor>
    <para>
      Each AUT in a Project has an Object Mapping Editor. You can open
      the Object Mapping Editor by right-clicking on a Test Suite in
      the Test Suite Browser and selecting ”<emphasis>open with Object
      Mapping Editor</emphasis>”.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can also open the Object Mapping Editor by single-clicking
      the chosen Test Suite and clicking on the ”<emphasis>start
      Object Mapping Mode</emphasis>” button on the toolbar. This also
      starts the Object Mapping Mode.
    </para>
    <para>
      The Object Mapping Editor has four tabs, a split view, a tree
      view, a table view and configuration tab. In the Object Mapping
      Editor:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can see all the component names you have used in the
          Test Suite you selected, and any other Test Suites which use
          the same AUT.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can see any technical names you have collected from the
          AUT.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can see the component and technical names you have
          assigned to each other to complete mapping.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="central-test-data-editor">
    <title>Central Test Data Editor</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerCentralTestDataEditorContextId">Central Test Data</anchor>
    <para>
      You can open the Central Test Data Editor via the button on the
      toolbar.
    </para>
    <para>
      In the Central Test Data Editor:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can create, modify and delete central test data sets.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can search for places where central test data sets have
          been used.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</section>