<section id="views" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                  xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Views</title>
  <para>
    The ITE has the following views:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Properties View
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Data Sets View
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Component Names View
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Test Result View
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Problem View
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Search result view
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Navigator View
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Console
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Inspector View
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Test Result Summary View
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Running AUTs View
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Image View
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Progress View
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    The first three views are <emphasis>support views</emphasis>.
    Their content changes depending on the current selection – they
    show details corresponding to the currently selected item.
  </para>
  <para>
    Use <emphasis role="menuPath">Window</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Show View</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Other</emphasis> to see a full list of views
    that can be opened in the ITE.
  </para>
  <section id="the-properties-view">
    <title>The Properties View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerPropertiesViewContextId">Properties View</anchor>
    <para>
      The Properties View is in the upper right-hand corner of each
      perspective. The Properties View shows details about the
      selected item in a browser or editor.
    </para>
    <para>
      If you select something from a browser, you can see its details
      in the Properties View, but you can’t edit them. You can only
      edit details from within an editor. Read-only fields in the
      Properties View have a lock icon
      <mediaobject role="icon" file="../images/readonly.png"/>
      at their left-hand side.
    </para>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Test Suite details</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
      If you select a Test Suite, you will see the following:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Test Suite name.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Any comments for the Test Suite.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The step delay for this Test Suite.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The name of the AUT this Test Suite uses.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The reentry properties for the default Event Handlers.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Test Case details</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
      If you select a Test Case, the Properties View shows the
      following:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Test Case name.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Any comments for the Test Case.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The data source details for this Test Case
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Any parameters/parameter values if references have been used
          in the Test Case.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Test Step details</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
      If you select a Test Step, you will see the following:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Test Step name.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Any comments for this Test Step.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Details about the component in the Test Step:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The component type.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The component name (given by you).
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Details about the action in the Test Step.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Details about the parameters in the Test Step. For each
          parameter you will see:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The parameter name.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The parameter type (e.g. if it is an integer, a string
              etc).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The parameter value (either a concrete value or a
              reference).
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Test result details</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
      If you select an item from the Test Result View, you will see
      the following:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The result details:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The name of the item.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              What type of item it is.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Any comments for the item.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The test result – if it passed or failed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          For Test Steps, you can also see the component, action and
          parameter details. If the Test Step failed, you can also see
          the error details.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          For Event Handlers, you can see the type of Event Handler it
          was, and what the reentry property was.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Icons in the Properties View</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
      When the Properties View contains data (i.e. a filled-in
      <emphasis>parameter value</emphasis> field), there are certain
      icons to help you understand the data.
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Values which are the same as in the original specification
          display a small gray diamond <mediaobject role="icon" file="../images/originalData.png"/>
          to the left of the field.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Values which have been overwritten at a place of reuse show
          a small yellow diamond <mediaobject role="icon" file="../images/overwrittenData.png"/>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="the-data-sets-view">
    <title>The Data Sets View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerDataSetViewContextId">Data Sets View</anchor>
    <para>
      The Data Sets View is in the lower right-hand corner of the
      Functional Test Specification Perspective by default. It lets you add, modify,
      delete and see any data for Test Cases. For each Test Case
      containing references or for each central test data set, you can
      add data sets in this view. This is also the view where you can
      translate your data and overwrite data when you reuse a Test
      Case. When data in the Data Sets View are uneditable, they are
      shown in gray. Values in black may be edited.
    </para>
    <para>
      To make entering data easier, pressing
      <emphasis role="input">»ENTER«</emphasis> will spring to the next
      cell or row, or to the ”<emphasis>Add</emphasis>” button if no
      more rows have been added. The
      <emphasis role="input">»Tab«</emphasis> key springs to the
      ”<emphasis>Add</emphasis>” button.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-component-names-view">
    <title>The Component Names View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="compNameViewContextId">Component Names</anchor>
    <para>
      The Component Names View is in the lower right-hand corner of the
      Functional Test Specification Perspective by default, just behind the Data Sets
      View. It lets you see the component names used in a reused Test
      Case, and add more component names. This means that you can use
      a Test Case to execute the same actions on different components.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-test-result-view-1">
    <title>The Test Result View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testResultViewContextId">Test Results View</anchor>
    <para>
      The Test Result View is in the middle of the Execution
      Perspective by default. It can also be displayed in the bottom
      right-hand corner of the Functional Test Specification Perspective via the
      preferences. It follows and displays the results of the test
      execution. Each Test Step and Test Case is marked with a green
      tick or a red cross depending on if it passed or failed.
    </para>
    <para>
      If you select an item in the Test Result View, you can see its
      details in the Properties View. If the Project is open and the
      item is still available, you can double-click on a Test Step or
      Test Case in the Test Result View, to highlight it in the Test
      Suite Browser. Double-clicking on this item in the Test Suite
      Browser will open the editor for this item in the Functional Test Specification
      Perspective.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-problems-view-1">
    <title>The Problem View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="problemViewContextId">Problem View</anchor>
    <para>
      The Problem View is by default at the bottom of the Functional Test
      Specification Perspective, under the editor area. The Properties View
      helps you to work with the ITE by giving you information, warnings and errors.
      Double-clicking on a message will either carry out the necessary
      action or open a dialog/editor to sort out the problem, if this
      is possible.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-search-result-view">
    <title>The search result view</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="searchResultViewContextId">Search Result View</anchor>
    <para>
      The search result view (<xref linkend="showresultview"/>)
      is at the bottom of the Functional Test Specification Perspective, under the
      editor area, and just behind the Problem View by default. If you perform
      searches, the results are shown here. For most searches, if you
      double-click on an item in the search result view, the
      corresponding item is highlighted in the Test Case Browser or
      Test Suite Browser. You can see a history of previous searches,
      and re-run them directly from within the view. You can also
      refresh the current search.
    </para>
    <figure id="showresultview">
      <title>Search Result View</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/showresultview.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Search Result View</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section id="the-description-view">
  <title>The Description View</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="editDescriptionDialogContextId">The Description View</anchor>
 	 <para>
 	 The description view is placed in the lower right hand corner of the 
  	Specification Perspective when it is opened. The description 
	view displays the text of any descriptions you have added for 
	Test Cases, Test Suites and Test Jobs. 
  	</para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-navigation-view">
    <title>The Navigator View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="org.eclipse.ui.resource_view_context">Navigator View</anchor>
    <para>
      The Navigator View is at the top right-hand corner of the
      workspace perspective by default. The Navigator View gives you
      a view of your workspace and the files in it.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-console">
    <title>The console</title>
    <para>
      The console is shown in the bottom right-hand corner of the Functional Test
      Specification Perspective. It lets you follow certain processes,
      for example, the import of Projects.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-inspector">
    <title>The Inspector View</title>
    <para>
      The Inspector View can be used to help you test RCP AUTs which use
      the GEF framework. When the inspector is activated, figures can
      be clicked in the GEF canvas, and their textpath (used to
      identify them in the test) is shown. The Inspector View is shown by
      default in the bottom right-hand corner of the Functional Test Specification
      Perspective.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-test-result-summary-view">
    <title>The Test Result Summary View</title>
    <para>
      The Test Result Summary View offers an overview of all tests
      that have run in this database. It can be filtered and sorted.
      The Test Result Summary View is displayed in the Functional Test Reporting
      Perspective.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-running-auts-view">
    <title>The Running AUTs View</title>
    <para>
      The Running AUTs View is above the Test Suite Browser in the
      Functional Test Specification Perspective. It shows an overview of all running
      AUTs and can be used to stop AUTs and to start Test Suites.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-image-view">
    <title>The Image View</title>
    <para>
      The Image View is used to see automatically generated
      screenshots of errors that have occurred in tests.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="the-progress-view">
    <title>The Progress View</title>
    <para>
      The progress view shows which longer-running actions are
      currently being executed. These can include starting AUTs,
      connecting to the AUT Agent, and executing tests.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>