<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="connect-aut-agent" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                              xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Connecting to the AUT Agent</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testExecViewContextId">Test Suite Browser</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="problemViewContextId">Problem View</anchor>
  <para>
    You can connect to an AUT Agent you have started
    (<xref linkend="start-aut-agent"/>) on a local or remote machine, or you
    can connect an embedded AUT Agent on your local machine.
  </para>
  <para role="tip">
    When using a separate AUT Agent, you must wait for the
    AUT Agent to be running before you can connect to it.
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        On the toolbar, click on the arrow next to the
        ”<emphasis>Connect to AUT Agent</emphasis>” button
        <mediaobject role="icon" file="images/startServer.png"/>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the drop down list, you can choose an AUT Agent to
        connect to:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select the embedded AUT Agent option to connect to an
            AUT Agent that is automatically started for you on your
            machine.
          </para>
          <para role="tip">
            The embedded AUT Agent uses port 60001
            by default in the ITE. You can change the port that
            should be used for the embedded AUT Agent in the
            preferences (<xref linkend="embedded-aut-agent-preferences"/>).
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select an AUT Agent host and port number to connect to
            from the list. The list of hosts and ports available in
            this list can be configured in the preferences
            (<xref linkend="aut-agent-preferences"/>). If you have set the environment
            variable <emphasis>TEST_AUT_AGENT_PORT</emphasis>, then
            you will also see the port number you set for that
            variable in the drop-down list.
          </para>
          <para role="warning">
            If you are not working with the embedded AUT Agent, you must have
            started an AUT Agent on a machine in the network
            (<xref linkend="start-aut-agent"/>) to be able to connect to it.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para role="tip">
    To work with the embedded AUT Agent, you do not need to
    start an AUT Agent on your machine. However, you can only work
    with the embedded AUT Agent for local testing (i.e. on the same
    machine as the ITE). The embedded agent is started in
    <emphasis>lenient</emphasis> mode (<xref linkend="testing-aut-launched-by-other"/>).
  </para>
</section>