<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="configuring-test-suites-in-the-properties-view" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                           xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                           xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Configuring Test Suites in the Properties View</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="guidancerPropertiesViewContextId" xml:id="configuring-test-suites-in-the-properties-view.guidancerPropertiesViewContextId" xreflabel="Properties View"/>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="testSuiteEditorContextId" xml:id="configuring-test-suites-in-the-properties-view.testSuiteEditorContextId" xreflabel="Test Suite Editor"/>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="testExecViewContextId" xml:id="configuring-test-suites-in-the-properties-view.testExecViewContextId" xreflabel="Test Suite Browser"/>
  <para>
    To configure a Test Suite, you must first create one
    (<xref linkend="creating-a-test-suite"/>).
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Open the Test Suite Editor by double-clicking on the Test
        Suite you want to configure.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the Properties View, you can:
      </para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Change the Test Suite name by entering a new name in the
            <emphasis>Test Suite name</emphasis> field.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Add a comment to the Test Suite
            (<xref linkend="adding-comments-to-items-in-editors"/>).
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Enter a value in the <emphasis>step delay</emphasis>
            field. The step delay is the time left between each Test
            Step during test execution. The default is 0
            milliseconds (<xref linkend="altering-the-speed-of-test-execution"/>).
   		</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
        <para>
        Set whether this Test Suite should be relevant or not. 
        If a Test Suite is marked as non-relevant, test results for this Test Suite are created but are not 
        exported with the Project, are not considered for any BIRT reports 
        (<xref linkend="generating-birt-reports"/>).
        </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select the AUT for this Test Suite. To be able to select
            an AUT (and object map, and execute your test) you must
            have added at least one AUT to the Project
            (<xref linkend="define-aut"/>).
          </para>
          <para role="tip">
            You don’t have to choose an AUT for a Test Suite
            as soon as you have created it, but you will have to
            choose one before object mapping, for example.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Choose a default reentry type for each of the four error
            types from the combo-boxes.
          </para>
          <para>
            Event Handlers are Test Cases used to deal with errors
            during test execution. When an error occurs, the current
            Test Case is searched for an Event Handler for that
            error type. If none is found, the parent Test Case is
            searched, and so on. If no Event Handler for the test is
            found, then a default Event Handler (specified in the
            Test Suite properties)is activated.
          </para>
          <para>
            As a general rule, you should avoid default Event
            Handlers being executed. See the sections on Event
            Handlers for information on the event types
            (<xref linkend="event-types"/>), reentry types (<xref linkend="reentry-types"/>) and
            creating your own Event Handlers.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Save the changes in the Test Suite Editor.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
</section>