<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<chapter xml:id="glossary" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                     xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <?dbhtml dir="glossary"?>
  <title>Glossary</title>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Action</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A method which is carried out on a Component. An
          <emphasis>Action</emphasis> is part of a Test Step, and serves to either execute a
          command (e.g. click, enter text), or verify property or state
          information about a <emphasis>Component</emphasis> (e.g. check <emphasis>Component
          name</emphasis>, check visibility).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>AUT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Application Under Test. The AUT is the entire program that you wish to test.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>AUT Conﬁguration</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The information required in order to locate and start an AUT in the conﬁguration
          desired by the user. An <emphasis>AUT Conﬁguration</emphasis> includes program information
          such as <emphasis>JRE</emphasis> location and class path, and AUT conﬁguration information such as
          command-line parameters and environment variables. Details about the AUT are given
          when a project is created, and are entered into the relevant ﬁelds in the Test Suite
          Editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CAP</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The three parts of a Test Step : Component, Action, Parameter.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Classname for AUT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The fully qualiﬁed classname which contains the main method of the AUT.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Classpath for AUT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          An environment variable that informs <emphasis>Java</emphasis> where to look for the class ﬁles
          which are needed to run the AUT.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Component</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A user interface object. Each component has a set of actions that can be carried
          out upon it.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Component Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The symbolic name you choose for a component in the AUT and use in a Test Step or
          Test Case.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Component Names View</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In this view, component names in reused Test Cases can be reassigned to create
          multiple component names for one Test Step. This allows many components of the
          same type or within the same group or family to be mapped to the same Test Step.
          The default position of the Component Names View is in the lower right-hand corner
          of the perspective.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Component Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The type of graphical user interface object which will be acted upon in a Test Step,
          e.g. ”Menu Bar” or ”Combo Box”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Data Sets View</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The view in which multiple parameter values for a Test Case can be deﬁned and edited.
          The default position of the Data Sets View is the right-hand side of the perspective,
          in the middle.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Empty string</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To enter an empty string as a parameter (i.e. nothing at all), use backslash \.<?linebreak?>
          To actually write a backslash, you must enter two backslashes.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Escape character</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The character used to cancel any special function that the following symbol may have.
          The default escape character is \.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Event Handling</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The process by which errors are dealt with during the execution of a test. If no 
          user-deﬁned Event Handler has been speciﬁed, a default Event Handler is activated.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Graphical User Interface</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A means of interacting with a computer by the use of a graphically oriented (as
          opposed to text-oriented) display. Modern graphical user interfaces (GUI’s) are
          controlled by a mouse as well as a keyboard, and consist of windows, buttons, text
          areas, and other manipulable objects which are designed to make computer operation
          simpler and more intuitive.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ITE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Short for <emphasis>Integrated Test Environment</emphasis>. By this we mean the application where tests
          are written.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>JAR</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The <emphasis>Java</emphasis>™Archive ﬁle format. It allows multiple classes and other program ﬁles and
          data to be combined into one compressed ﬁle, which often represents a complete
          program. In this context, a JAR describes the <emphasis>Java</emphasis>™Archive of the AUT.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Object mapping</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The process by which component names you created in your test are attached to the
          technical names used in the AUT.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Parameters</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The information that is given to an action to perform a Test Step, such as name, value,
          etc. A parameter consists of:
          
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                a name
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                a type
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                a value
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          
          Most actions require one or more parameters.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Parameter Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A name which describes a parameter which is sent to an action.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Parameter Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The type of value which is sent as a parameter to an action. The following parameter
          types are supported:
          
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                String
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Integer
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Boolean
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Parameter Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The contents of the parameter which is sent to an action. A parameter value can either
          be a static value (e.g. <emphasis role="input">Hello</emphasis>, 123), a reference (e.g.
          <emphasis role="input">=REFERENCE</emphasis>) or a variable.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Port Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A software address used to identify and communicate between individual programs or
          services on a single computer or between multiple computers on a network. A hostname
          and port number must be given in order to connect to an AUT Agent.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A Project contains all the information for the test, including Test Suites and Test
          Cases, AUT’s and data. Projects are stored in the database.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project Properties</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Information pertaining to the active project, including the name (all projects in the
          database must have unique names).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Propagation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When references are entered, the parameter they replace is carried up into the next
          Test Case in the hierarchy. This is propagation.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Properties View</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The view for displaying and editing the properties of selected Test Steps or Test
          Cases, located by default in the top right-hand corner of the perspective. Test Steps
          and Test Cases can be edited in the Properties View by clicking on their icon in their
          respective editor. The Properties View is also used to display detailed results of a
          Test Suite once it has been executed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reference Symbol</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The character used to denote a reference within a parameter. The default reference
          symbol is =.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Speciﬁcation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The method by which test details and instructions are entered by the user in the ITE.
          Tests are not <emphasis>programmed</emphasis>, but rather <emphasis>speciﬁed</emphasis>
          in plain language, then object-mapped to the program’s technical names.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Step Delay</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The time to wait between Test Steps, given in milliseconds. A step delay causes a
          slower test execution.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Technical Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A name given to a graphical user interface object of an AUT by a software developer.
          Technical names are used to uniquely identify an object within an application and are
          mapped to a component name as deﬁned by the user in a Test Step.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Case</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A reusable test object which contains Test Steps or other Test Cases.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Case Browser</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A view which shows the hierarchy of Test Cases as entered and deﬁned by the user.
          The Test Case Browser is by default in the bottom left-hand corner of the perspective.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Case Editor</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          An editor area used to create and alter Test Cases and Test Steps. The Test Case
          Editor is located by default in the center of the perspective.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Data</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Values which are entered into parameters for an action in Test Steps. Test data may
          be entered directly into a parameter or referenced.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Job</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A Test Job is a collection of Test Suites which are designed to be executed after each
          other. The Test Suites can test the samme AUT, different instances of the same AUT, or
          different AUT’s entirely.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Result View</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The view which displays the results of an executed Test Suite.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Result View</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The view which displays the results of an executed Test Suite.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Step</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The smallest test object. A Test Step belongs to a Test Case. A Test Step consists of

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                a <emphasis role="strong">C</emphasis>omponent
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                an <emphasis role="strong">A</emphasis>ction
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                a <emphasis role="strong">P</emphasis>arameter
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Suite</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A Test Suite uses an AUT conﬁguration and contains all Test Cases and their respective
          Test Steps, in the order in which they are to be tested.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Suite Browser</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The view containing the Test Suite tree, where the Test Cases in a Test Suite can be
          seen. The Test Suite Browser is situated by default in the top left-hand corner of the
          perspective.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Test Suite Editor</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          An editor pane used to view the properties of the Test Suite and the Test Cases used
          in it, and to edit their parameter values and names. The Test Suite Editor is located
          by default in the center of the perspective.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Workspace</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Personal preferences relating to the client layout and actions are saved in a Workspace.
          All changes made in the <emphasis>”Preferences”</emphasis> dialog are stored here.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</chapter>
