<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section id="mapping-components-in-winformsauts" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                               xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                               xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Mapping components in WinFormsAUTs</title>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Composite components may be mappable as separate parts</emphasis><?linebreak?>
    For some components that consist of other components (e.g. combo boxes that consist of a textfield and a button), it may be possible to collect the individual components (textfield, button) as well as the whole composite (the combo box). When performing mapping, you should make sure that you are collecting the component that it makes sense to perform your chosen action on. For example, you can only perform a <emphasis>Select from Combo Box</emphasis> on a combo box. While it may be possible to perform a <emphasis>Replace Text</emphasis> on the textfield included in the combo box, it will almost always make more sense to deal with the logical component as opposed to its parts.
  </para>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Mapping of dynamic content items in components</emphasis><?linebreak?>
    It may be possible to map individual items within components that are addressed as a whole component in the test specification. For example, it may be possible to map individual list entries. Even when this is the case, we recommend mapping the <emphasis>list</emphasis> component and performing actions on the whole component that deal with its content (e.g. <emphasis>Select entry from list</emphasis>, <emphasis>Check existence of entry in list</emphasis>). This makes tests more robust and able to deal with dynamic data.
  </para>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Mapping components in tabbed panes</emphasis><?linebreak?>
    When mapping a component that is contained in a tabbed pane, it is important to move the mouse cursor quickly and directly to the component you want to map, to avoid collecting the tabbed pane itself.
  </para>
</section>