<section id="Samplesdvdtests" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                            xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                            xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>DVD Tool Tests</title>
  <section id="sample-2.1-testing-the-menu-bar-and-dialog-boxes">
    <title>Sample 2.1: testing the menu bar and dialog boxes</title>
    <para>
      This category and the ones following it contain Test Cases which
      are used in the executable Test Case
      <emphasis>2_DVD_TOOL_FULL_TEST</emphasis> and the Test Suite of
      the same name.
    </para>
    <para>
      The Test Case in this category contains a reused Test Case from
      the <emphasis>bound_modules_samples</emphasis> Project. It
      contains Test Cases to add a category to the DVD Tool via the
      menu. The parameter for the category name has been referenced,
      as has a variable to read the category name entered for use
      later in the test.
    </para>
    <para>
      The original Test Case in the
      <emphasis>bound_modules_samples</emphasis> Project had no data.
      When it was reused here, three data sets were added. This means
      that the Test Case is executed three times, each time entering a
      different category name, and storing the name as a variable.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="sample-2.2-testing-trees">
    <title>Sample 2.2: testing trees</title>
    <para>
      This category contains a Test Case which checks that a tree node
      exists, based on its textpath. Three data sets have been
      entered, which use the variables stored in the previous Test
      Case to complete the textpath.
    </para>
    <para>
      For example, one of the stored variables was
      <emphasis>CATEGORY1</emphasis>. The textpath to test is entered
      as <literal>Category/${CATEGORY1}</literal>.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="sample-2.3-testing-tables">
    <title>Sample 2.3: testing tables</title>
    <para>
      This category contains a Test Case which contains two Test
      Cases. The first selects a category node in the tree and then
      selects the option from the context menu to add a DVD. The
      second Test Case enters text into the cells in the table. This
      Test Case has four data sets, so that the four cells can be
      filled with one Test Case.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="sample-2.4-testing-tabbed-panes-lists-combo-boxes">
    <title>Sample 2.4: testing tabbed panes, lists, combo
    boxes</title>
    <para>
      This category contains four Test Cases. The first two,
      <emphasis>Fill in the Content Tab</emphasis> and <emphasis>Fill
      in the Technics Tab</emphasis> contain Test Cases reused from
      the <emphasis>unbound_modules_concrete</emphasis> Project and
      the <emphasis>bound_modules_samples</emphasis> Project. These
      Test Cases execute various actions on the tabbed panes in the
      DVD Tool. There is a lot of reuse of Test Cases, especially on
      different components. The <emphasis>Enter a Text
      Detail</emphasis> Test Case, for example, is reused three times,
      with a different component name each time. The <emphasis>Fill in
      the Technics Tab</emphasis> Test Case also contains an Event
      Handler to check a checkbox if it isn’t already done so. Many of
      the parameters in these Test Cases have been referenced so that
      values can be entered for them later.
    </para>
    <para>
      The last two Test Cases each contain a Test Case to select a
      DVD, and then contain the <emphasis>Fill in the Content
      Tab</emphasis> and <emphasis>Fill in the Technics Tab</emphasis>
      Test Cases. Because the values in these Test Cases were left
      empty, different data can be entered for each Test Case.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>