<section xml:id="new-features-and-developments-6.1" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                              xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>New Features and Developments</title>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Multiple Test Case Browser instances now
    supported</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now open the Test Case Browser multiple times.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can designate one Test Case Browser as the main browser.
        This browser will be used for actions such as show
        specification etc.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Workspace dialog now allows remembering of
    workspace</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now select the option to remember your default
        workspace in the workspace chooser.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Remember password and auto-login for
    database</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the database login dialog, you can select the option to
        remember your password.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you have selected this option, you can also specify that
        the database should be used as the default database you will
        be automatically logged in when a database connection is
        required.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The above options are not available for the embedded database.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        To change the database you are connected to, or to change your default database login, use:<?linebreak?>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Select Database</emphasis>
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Auto-load for default Project</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the <emphasis>Open Project</emphasis> dialog, you can now
        identify the selected Project and version number as your
        default Project.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can have one default Project per workspace.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When you have a default Project set, then selecting:<?linebreak?>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Open</emphasis><?linebreak?>
        will automatically load this Project.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can remove the default loading in the
        <emphasis>Test</emphasis> preferences.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Testexec and DBTool can use -dburl instead
    of workspace (-data) parameter</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        To make working with the testexec and dbtool easier, you can
        now use the dburl parameter to specify which database to
        connect to during the process.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This removes the need to specify which workspace to use (via
        <emphasis role="input">-data</emphasis>) when working with the testexec and
        dbtool.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can still enter the workspace and the -dbscheme
        information if you prefer not to use the -dburl parameter.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Selenium version and tested browsers
    updated</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Jubula now uses a newer version of Selenium that supports
        newer versions of Firefox.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We have updated our tests to run on Firefox version 15.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Frames and iFrames now supported for Web
    Testing</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        AUTs that contain Frames and iFrames can now be tested by
        Jubula
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">HTML:<emphasis>pre</emphasis> tags now
    supported as component with text</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In HTML AUTs, you can now map components that use the
        <literal>&lt;pre&gt;</literal> tag and perform e.g. check text
        actions on them.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Chronon: Embedded recorder no longer needs
    to be commented in</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now start the embedded Chronon recording in Jubula
        without having to comment it in in the .ini file.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The only exception to this is on Linux systems, where you must
        comment Chronon in for the ITE in the .ini file by removing
        the hash signs from the two lines in the .ini file, and then
        restart Jubula. If you are starting Jubula from the command
        line with Chronon on Linux, please ensure that your current
        directory is the Jubula directory, otherwise Jubula will not
        start.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Chronon: New preference page and options
    for ITE Chronon</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the preferences dialog, there is now a Chronon category. In
        this category, you can select the <emphasis>ITE
        Chronon</emphasis> page.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        On this page, you can configure options for the embedded
        Chronon in the ITE. You can configure the output directory for
        the Chronon recording, as well as any include or exclude
        patterns that should be included and / or ignored for the
        recording.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Chronon: Support for Chronon server
    installation for use with AUTs</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When you use Chronon with your AUT, you now have two choices –
        you can use the integrated Chronon to record your AUT or you
        can specify where your Chronon installation is, thus allowing
        you to use the Chronon Recording Server. This is the
        recommended choice for working in continuous integration
        processes.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Chronon: Support for exclude patterns in
    AUT configurations</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you are using the integrated Chronon support for testing
        your AUT, then you now have the option to specify exclude
        patterns for the recording as well as include patterns.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Chronon: Jubula now uses Chronon
    3</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Jubula now uses Chronon version 3 to perform embedded
        recording (in Jubula itself) and also for the integrated
        recording in AUTs.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">JRE version updated</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Jubula now uses version 1.6.0_33 of the Java runtime
        environment.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Jubula supports the testing of .NET
    AUTs</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now also test .NET AUTs with Jubula.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Currently, WinForms AUTs can be tested.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Further information is available in the section on Toolkits in
        the User Manual.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New metric in Jubula: Waits and Delays</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        There is a new metric in Jubula that analyzes the waits and
        delays used in a test that has run.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can start the metric from a Test Result Report and enter a
        parameter for the minimum amount of waited time (in
        milliseconds) that should be considered.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The Search Result View displays all the static waits within
        the node you selected. They are sorted according to the action
        they belong to, and you can see how much time each type of
        wait accumulates to over the test.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New BIRT Report: Test Execution
    Overview</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        There is a new BIRT report available to give an overview of
        the test execution.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This report shows a list of executed, relevant Test Suites
        over the time period selected. For each day in the time
        period, there is a colored block for the Test Suite to display
        its status. Green means that the test ran without any errors.
        Red means that the test ran, but with errors. Yellow means
        that the test ran more than once on that day. White means that
        the Test Suite did not run on this day. This report is useful
        for teams with large amounts of Test Suites who need to ensure
        on a daily basis that all Test Suites were started.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New JaCoCo version used</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Jubula now uses JaCoCo version 0.5.9 for code coverage.
        Further information on the changes in the new JaCoCo version
        can be found in the JaCoCo release notes.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>