<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="adding-descriptions-to-items-in-editors" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Adding descriptions to items in editors</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="editDescriptionDialogContextId">Description Dialog</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="guidancerSpecTestCaseEditorContextId">Test Case Editor</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testSuiteEditorContextId">Test Suite Editor</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="guidancerTestJobEditorContextId">Test Job Editor</anchor>
  <para>
    Descriptions are longer pieces of text that provide information about nodes in your tests. 
    You can add descriptions in the ITE to Test Cases, Test Suites and Test Jobs 
    via the editor for these items. 
    You can add descriptions to the item itself, or to other items used in it.
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Open the editor containing the item you want to add a description to.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Select the item you want to add, and select from the context-sensitive menu:
      </para>
      <para>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Edit description</emphasis>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the dialog that opens, you can enter text in the upper field. 
        The text you enter can use the syntax of various markup languages (e.g. TracWiki, MediaWiki). 
        You can set the language for your Project in the Project properties 
        (<xref linkend="projectproperties"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the lower field, you can see the preview of the text as it will appear in the description view. 
        The preview is updated after a short pause in typing.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Click "<emphasis>OK</emphasis>" to close the dialog. 
        You will see the description you have entered in the description view. 
        If the description view is not open, you can open it by selecting:
      </para>
      <para>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Window</emphasis> --&gt; 
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Show View</emphasis>--&gt; 
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Description</emphasis>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The changes to your descriptions are saved when you save the editor.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can add a description for the original specification of a Test Case or a Test Suite, and 
        also at places where a Test Case or Test Suite has been reused. 
        You can add a new description to overwrite an existing one when you reuse an item.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Descriptions are not displayed in test results.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
</section>