<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="deleting-from-the-object-mapping-editor" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Deleting from the Object Mapping Editor</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="objectMapEditorContextId">Object Mapping</anchor>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can delete items from the Object Mapping Editor using
        the ”<emphasis>delete</emphasis>” option from the
        context-sensitive menu.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can also select the item you want to delete and press
        <emphasis role="input">»DELETE«</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you delete a component name that is still used in a Test
        Case for this Test Suite it will reappear when you select
        ”<emphasis>refresh</emphasis>” from the context-sensitive
        menu.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para role="tip">
    If you want to remove all unused mappings from the Object
    Mapping Editor, then use the <emphasis>Cleanup</emphasis> option
    (<xref linkend="removing-unused-component-names-from-the-object-mapping-editor"/>).
  </para>
  <section xml:id="removing-unused-component-names-from-the-object-mapping-editor">
    <title>Removing unused component names from the Object Mapping Editor</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="objectMapEditorContextId">Object Mapping</anchor>
    <para>
      Over time, your Project will change, and these changes may
      mean that component names you had previously used in Test
      Suites, then mapped to technical names via the Object Mapping,
      are no longer used. This results in object mappings in which
      the component name is no longer used in the test for this AUT.
      Such component names can be recognized by the fact that
      <emphasis>Show corresponding specification</emphasis> in the
      Object Mapping Editor (<xref linkend="searching-for-places-where-a-component-name-has-been-used"/>)
      returns no search results in the search result view (i.e. the
      component name is no longer used in the test), or if the
      search result view shows only Test Cases that are used in
      other AUTs. If you perform <emphasis>Show where
      used</emphasis> in the Component Names Browser
      (<xref linkend="searching-for-places-where-a-component-name-has-been-used"/>) and the
      only search result is a mapping, then this is also a component
      name that is no longer used in the test.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can delete any component names from the Object Mapping
      Editor that are unused in the Project for this AUT:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Object Mapping Editor, select:
        </para>
        
        <para>
          <emphasis role="menuPath">Cleanup</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">unused component names</emphasis>
        </para>
        
        <para>
          from the context-sensitive menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The cleanup operation starts, and a progress dialog is
          shown while unused names are being searched for. Depending
          on the size of your Project, this search may take some
          time.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If the Object Mapping Editor contains component names that
          are not used in any of the Test Suites for this AUT
          (either component names that are already mapped, or are
          still unassigned), then they are shown in a
          <emphasis>Delete unused component names</emphasis> dialog.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          If no component names are found, then you will see
          a message informing you of this.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the dialog to delete unused component names, you can
          see which component names have been identified for
          deletion. You can deselect individual component names to
          opt not to delete them. Once you have specified which
          component names should be deleted, click
          ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The component names you specify will be deleted from the
          Object Mapping Editor. Save the editor to save the
          changes.
        </para>
        <para role="warning">
          Removing component names from the Object
          Mapping Editor does not mean that the component names are
          deleted from the Project. However, if the deletion from
          the object map means that the component name is now used
          nowhere in the Project, then it will appear under the
          <emphasis>Unused Component Names</emphasis> category in
          the Component Names Browser and can be deleted from the
          whole Project (<xref linkend="deleting-unused-component-names"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
</section>