<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="object-mapping-editor" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                  xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Working with the Object Mapping Editor</title>
  <section xml:id="opening-the-object-mapping-editor">
    <title>Opening the Object Mapping Editor</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" condition="testExecViewContextId" xml:id="object-mapping-editor.testExecViewContextId" xreflabel="Test Suite Browser"/>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open the Object Mapping Editor by selecting the Test Suite whose components you want to map and selecting:
        </para>
        
        <para>
          <emphasis role="menuPath">Open with</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Object Mapping Editor</emphasis>.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          The Object Mapping Editor also opens automatically when you start the Object Mapping Mode via the toolbar.
        </para>
        <para>
          The Object Mapping Editor for the AUT used by this Test Suite will appear (see (<xref linkend="objectmappingeditor"/>)).
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          You can see the name of the AUT you are mapping in
          the tab of the editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="the-object-mapping-editor">
    <title>The Object Mapping Editor</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" condition="objectMapEditorContextId" xml:id="the-object-mapping-editor.objectMapEditorContextId" xreflabel="Object Mapping"/>
    <para>
      The Object Mapping pane in the Object Mapping Editor is where you perform your object mapping. 
      It contains three areas for the three main categories. IHere, you can:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Assign (map) technical names to component names
          (<xref linkend="mapping-assigning-collected-technical-names-to-component-names"/>) by dragging component names onto
          technical names (either assigned or unassigned).
         </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Create new component names for your tests
          (<xref linkend="creating-new-component-names"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Rename component names (<xref linkend="renaming-component-names"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Create categories and map into them (<xref linkend="working-with-categories-in-the-object-mapping-editor"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="working-with-categories-in-the-object-mapping-editor">
    <title>Working with categories in the Object Mapping Editor</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" condition="objectMapEditorContextId" xml:id="working-with-categories-in-the-object-mapping-editor.objectMapEditorContextId" xreflabel="Object Mapping"/>
    <anchor role="helpid" condition="dialogOMCategoryNewContextId" xml:id="working-with-categories-in-the-object-mapping-editor.dialogOMCategoryNewContextId" xreflabel="New Object Mapping Category Dialog"/>
	<para>
	There are three areas in the Object Mapping Editor, corresponding to the three types of names.
	</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Unassigned component names:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            these are the names you have used in your Test Cases or
            component names that you have created
            (<xref linkend="creating-new-component-names"/>). They are unassigned
            because they have not yet been mapped to a technical
            name.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Unassigned technical names:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            these are the names that you have collected from the AUT
            (<xref linkend="collecting-components-technical-names-from-the-aut"/>), but not yet assigned to
            component names.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Assigned names:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            there are pairs of names that have been mapped to each
            other. Each technical name can be mapped to one or more
            component names. This mapping tells the ITE which actual
            components you are referring to in your Test Cases.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Creating categories in the Object Mapping Editor</emphasis><?linebreak?>
      We recommend creating categories in the Object Mapping Editor to make your mapping work easier.
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can create categories and subcategories in the assigned names area in the lower part of the Object
          Mapping Editor by:
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Selecting one of the assigned names in the Object Mapping Editor.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Selecting ”<emphasis>create category</emphasis>” from
              the context-sensitive menu.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Entering a name for the category
            </para>
            <para role="warning">
              You can’t have
              two categories with the same name at the same level.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you are mapping, you can choose which category to map
          into. See the next <xref linkend="working-with-categories-in-the-object-mapping-editor"/> for details.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Mapping into categories in the Object Mapping Editor</emphasis><?linebreak?>
      Once you have created categories in the Object Mapping Editor, you can choose to map technical names collected from the AUT directly into a category. This can help if you have created a category for each dialog/window, and you want to map all of the components from it into one category.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you are in the Object Mapping Mode, right-click onthe category you want to map into and select:
        </para>
        
        <para>
          <emphasis role="menuPath">Map components into this category</emphasis>
        </para>
        
        <para>
          to make the technical names you collect from the AUT appear in this subcategory.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          If you have already mapped the technical name, the name will be shown in the Object Mapping Editor, but not moved into the category.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          The status bar displays which category you are mapping into.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="the-configuration-view-in-the-object-mapping-editor">
    <title>The configuration view in the Object Mapping Editor</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" condition="objectMapEditorContextId" xml:id="the-configuration-view-in-the-object-mapping-editor.objectMapEditorContextId" xreflabel="Object Mapping"/>
    <para>
      In the configuration view in the Object Mapping Editor you can
      alter the object recognition for the test execution.
    </para>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Understanding object recognition</emphasis><?linebreak?>
      Object recognition during test execution is based on a calculation which takes various factors into account. For some applications, some factors may be more important than others, and you can change their weighting accordingly.
    </para>
    <para>
      The object location is a <emphasis>heuristic</emphasis>
      process. During test execution, a calculation is made for each
      component in the AUT to see how similar it is to the
      originally mapped component. This calculation is based
      primarily on the component type – if you mapped a combo box,
      only combo boxes will considered. For each component of the
      same type, the similarity to the original is calculated using
      weighted properties. The factors used in the calculation are:
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Name:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The name of the object within the AUT code, as given by
            the developer (if a name was given). 
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Path:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The route through the AUT hierarchy to get to this
            component.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Context:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The components in the vicinity of this component.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Threshold:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            This determines what percentage value a component in the
            AUT must have in order to be considered as the
            originally mapped component. Components with a value
            under the threshold are not considered. The component
            with the highest value above the threshold is chosen
            during execution.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Options for object
      recognition</emphasis> You can change the profile used during
      test execution using the combo box:
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Standard:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            This is the default profile. It has a high value for
            name weight and lower values for context and path. The
            threshold is 85%.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Strict:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            In this profile, the values for name, path and context
            are the same as in the standard profile. The threshold
            is at 100%. This means that a component must exactly
            correspond to the originally mapped component.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Given names:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            In this profile, only the component name is considered.
            A component will only be selected if it has the same
            name as the originally mapped component. This profile
            can be used when you are sure that all of the components
            in the AUT have unique names.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Custom:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            This profile lets you move the sliders yourself. You can
            lock sliders to stop them being affected by other
            sliders.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <figure>
      <title>Object Mapping Configuration</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/objectmappingpref.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Object Mapping
        Configuration</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para role="warning">
      Take care when manually customizing the object mapping
      settings. You may have test execution problems if you have set
      the values too strictly, or not strictly enough.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="refreshing-the-object-mapping-editor">
    <title>Refreshing the Object Mapping Editor</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" condition="objectMapEditorContextId" xml:id="refreshing-the-object-mapping-editor.objectMapEditorContextId" xreflabel="Object Mapping"/>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select <emphasis>refresh</emphasis> from the
          context-sensitive menu in the Object Mapping Editor or
          press <emphasis role="input">»F5«</emphasis> to refresh the
          Object Mapping Editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Confirm that you want to want to refresh the editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      When you refresh the Object Mapping Editor, any new component
      names which have been added to Test Suites for this AUT are
      collected.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="finding-components-in-the-aut-via-the-object-mapping-editor-highlight-in-aut">
    <title>Finding components in the AUT via the Object Mapping Editor: highlight in AUT</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" condition="objectMapEditorContextId" xml:id="finding-components-in-the-aut-via-the-object-mapping-editor-highlight-in-aut.objectMapEditorContextId" xreflabel="Object Mapping"/>
    <para>
      In the Object Mapping Editor, you can search for:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          All the places where a component name has been used in the
          test (<xref linkend="searching-for-places-where-a-component-name-has-been-used"/>)
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The specific place where a particular component name comes
          from in the test (<xref linkend="searching-for-places-where-a-component-name-has-been-used"/>)
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The technical component in the AUT (see below).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Highlighting a component in the AUT</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
      To search for components in the AUT, the Object Mapping Editor
      must be open (<xref linkend="opening-the-object-mapping-editor"/>),
      and the AUT must be running (<xref linkend="starting-the-aut"/>) in the
      Object Mapping Mode (<xref linkend="collecting-components-technical-names-from-the-aut"/>).
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Object Mapping Editor, right-click on the technical name whose component you want to find in the AUT and select:
        </para>
        
        <para>
          <emphasis role="menuPath">Highlight in AUT</emphasis>
        </para>
        
        <para>
          from the context-sensitive menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The component whose technical name you selected will be
          highlighted with a green border in the AUT.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          You can
          only highlight components that are currently visible in
          the AUT.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
</section>