<section id="architecture" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                         xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Architecture</title>
  <para>
    This is a client-server application. We refer to the client part
    as the Integrated Test Environment or ITE, and the server
    component as the AUT Agent.:
  </para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        The ITE
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          is where tests are specified and evaluated.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        The AUT Agent
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          controls the application under test (AUT) and executes the
          specified tests. 
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>
    You can install the ITE and AUT Agent on different machines; even
    on different platforms. This lets you specify and run your tests
    on different machines, and means that you can run the same test on
    different platforms.
  </para>
  <section id="ite">
    <title>ITE</title>
    <para>
      The ITE is the interface between you and the AUT. It provides you with browsers
      to see Test Cases and Test Suites, and editors to modify them.
    </para>
    <para>
      In the client, you specify your tests without any programming.
      You can write tests modularly, structure them to fit your needs,
      and easily change them to follow developments in the AUT.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="aut-agent-1">
    <title>AUT Agent</title>
    <para>
      The AUT Agent is the link between your specified tests and the AUT. Once the AUT Agent has
      started the AUT, object mapping can take place, and tests can be observed and executed.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can install the AUT Agent on the same machine as the client
      or on any other machine in the network, as long as the AUT can
      also run on the machine. The AUT Agent can even run on a
      different platform than the client.
    </para>
    <para>
      This separation of the client and AUT Agent means that you don’t
      have to sacrifice control of your machine during test execution.
      It also means that you can test your AUT on different systems
      using the same test, and from the same client.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="working-with-the-ite-and-aut-agent-on-different-machines">
    <title>Working with the ITE and AUT Agent on different
    machines</title>
    <para>
      You can install the ITE on any machine in the network, and then
      install the AUT Agent on various other machines in the network.
    </para>
    <para>
      Within the ITE, you can define configurations for your AUT. The
      configurations specify where the AUT jar or exe file is, the JRE
      binary etc., and on which machine it should look.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can specify different AUT Agent hosts and port numbers to
      connect to.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>