<section id="database-structure" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                               xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                               xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Database structure</title>
  <para>
    You can store your Projects in a single-user database or in a
    multi-user database (recommended).
  </para>
  <section id="supported-systems">
    <title>Supported systems</title>
    <para>
      The ITE uses <emphasis>Eclipse Link</emphasis>
      as an object relational mapping layer.
    </para>
    <para>
      The ITE is tested with <emphasis>Oracle</emphasis>. Other
      database solutions supported by <emphasis>Eclipse
      Link</emphasis> may also be used as a database, though these
      have not been tested by our team.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="single-user">
    <title>Single-user</title>
    <para>
      If you work on a single-user database, only one tester can work
      on a specific Project at a time. This also applies to the test
      executor – the ITE and the test executor cannot access a
      single-user database at the same time.
    </para>
    <para>
      This method reduces the complexity of the system and its
      configuration, and should really only be used for demo purposes.
      Project sharing remains possible, however, through
      import/export.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="multi-user">
    <title>Multi-user</title>
    <para>
      When using a multi-user database, multiple testers can work on a
      single Project concurrently.
    </para>
    <para>
      Within such a scenario, all testers currently working on a
      Project may view and execute all parts of it. As soon as one
      tester alters a part of the Project, a lock is placed on that
      unit to disallow other users from making changes of their own.
      They are, however, still able to view and execute a locked test
      unit. Once the user with the lock has saved all changes, the
      lock is removed, and the test unit is once again available for
      editing.
    </para>
    <para>
      This database scenario is well-suited for larger testing
      operations, allowing for tight collaboration among testers and
      reducing the overall time needed to specify complex testing
      projects.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>