<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="conditions_overview" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                               xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                               xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Overview of Conditional Statements and Loops</title>
  <para>
    There are four special nodes for altering normal test execution, called Controllers:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Conditional Statements (If - Then - Else)
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Do - While loops
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        While - Do loops
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Repeat loops
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    You can add the aforementioned nodes to Test Cases through the Add submenu of the
    context menu in a Test Case Editor.
  </para>
  <para>
    These nodes have a fixed list of children (so-called Containers) which in
    turn can contain only non-Controller nodes (so they can contain only
    Test Steps, Test Case References and Comments).
  </para>
  <para>
    Conditional Statements, Do - While loops and While - Do loops have a Condition
    child (called While for the latter two) whose behavior is the following:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Conditions cannot be empty, so they must always contain at least one active node.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Conditions are determined by Checks. So a Condition is considered to be false as
        soon as such a Check Fail is encountered in any of its children which is not handled by
        a Check Fail handler. If a Condition (and its executed children) does not contain any Checks,
        then it is considered to be false.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    For example in the following IfThenElse Test Case, the Condition references a Test Case which
    has its own Handler for Check Fails, so even if the actual Check in that Test Case fails,
    this failure will be caught by the Handler, so it will not make the Condition to become false.
  </para>
  <figure xml:id="samplecondition">
    <title>A sample Condition</title>
       <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
             <imagedata fileref="images/samplecondition.png"/>
          </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>Condition</phrase></textobject>
       </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para>
    Test Result Nodes corresponding to Test Steps making a Condition fail are marked by error markers,
    but these markers are not propagated up to their ancestors.
  </para>
</section>