<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<chapter xml:id="toolkits" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                     xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <?dbhtml dir="toolkits"?>
  <title>Toolkits</title>
  
  <section>
    <title>Abstract Toolkit</title>
  	<para>
  		The abstract toolkit contains component types which are available on all toolkits
  		supported, and which have been specially adapted to be able to test various different
  		components which share a set of values. These components are the 
  		<emphasis>abstract components</emphasis>
  		available to make Test Steps more general. 
  	</para>
  	
  </section>
  <section>
  	<title>Concrete Toolkit</title>
    <para>
  		The concrete toolkit contains components and actions which are available in most
  		toolkits. An action from the concrete toolkit may therefore be used in a test 
  		for Swing, SWT and JavaFX applications. 
  	</para>
  </section>
  <section>
  	<title>GEF Toolkit</title>
    <para>
  		The GEF toolkit can be used to test components within a figure canvas in RCP applications.
  		You must set the toolkit to 
  		<emphasis>RCP</emphasis> 
  		in the Project properties to be able to use the GEF actions. 
  	</para>
  </section>
  <section>
  	<title>JavaFX Toolkit</title>
  	<para>
  		The JavaFX toolkit contains components which are specific to JavaFX applications. You will 
  		only have access to these components in your tests if you select JavaFX as your AUT Toolkit.
  	</para>
  </section>
  <section>
  	<title>RCP Toolkit</title>
  	<para>
  		The RCP toolkit contains components that are only found in SWT applications. You will
  		only have access to these components in your tests if you choose RCP or SWT as the project
  		toolkit. 
  	</para>
  	<para>
  		Most of the RCP components are covered in the section on SWT. Components in GEF AUT´s are 
  		are described in the section on GEF.
  	</para>
  </section>
  <section>
  	<title>Swing Toolkit</title>
  	<para>
  		The Swing toolkit contains components that can be used on Swing applications. All the Swing 
  		components are also concrete components and can be found in the section on concrete 
  		components.
  	</para>
  </section>
  <section>
  	<title>SWT Toolkit</title>
  	<para>
  		The SWT toolkit contains components specific to SWT applications. You will only have access 
  		to these components if you select SWT as the toolkit for your AUT.
  	</para>
  </section>
</chapter>