<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2016 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
  
  Contributors:
      BREDEX GmbH - initial API and implementation and/or initial documentation
-->
<section xml:id="new-features-and-developments-8.5.0" version="5.0"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <title>New Features and Developments</title>
<para>
 <emphasis role="strong">Moving tree table actions to the concrete toolkit</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
    <para>
        We have moved the JavaFX and SWT tree table actions to the concrete toolkit.
        As a consequence, the relevant modules in the <emphasis>unbound_modules_javafx</emphasis>
        and <emphasis>unbound_modules_swt</emphasis> projects have been deprecated. Please
        replace these modules by their counterparts from the project <emphasis>unbound_modules_concrete</emphasis>.
        Also note that some of the tree table actions are still only implemented for the JavaFX toolkit (e.g. Check
        Existence of Value in Column). These actions now result in an <emphasis>Action not supported by selected
        toolkit</emphasis> error if executed on SWT Tree Tables.
    </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
 <emphasis role="strong">Upgrading Selenium to 3.3.1</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
    <para>
        We have upgraded the used Selenium Webdriver version to 3.3.1.
        As a consequence, the browser webdrivers may also need upgrading.
        The new Selenium version has been tested using ChromeDriver
        version 2.28, GeckoDriver (Firefox) version 0.15 and IEDriver
        version 3.3.0.
    </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
 <emphasis role="strong">Export JUnit reports</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
    <para>
        When generating TestResult XML/HTML files from Test Results, the generated files
        will now include an additional lightweight JUnit report.
        You can now define referenced Test Cases as TestSuites for the generation of the
        JUnit report with a newly added parameter called "JUnitTestSuite".
    </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
 <emphasis role="strong">Deletion with Orphans</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
    <para>
        We introduced a new feature in the Test Case Browser called <emphasis>Delete with Orphans</emphasis>.
    </para>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
    <para>
        When tidying up a project, there are Test Cases that are no longer required or used.
        The <emphasis>Delete with Orphans</emphasis> feature allows you to show all Test Cases
        that would remain unused if a certain Test Case were deleted. It then offers you
        to delete the Test Case with all its remaining "Orphans".
    </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
  <emphasis role="strong">Import project files by drag and drop</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
     <para>
       It is now possible to import <emphasis>.jub</emphasis> project files
       by dragging them to the Test Suite Browser View of the ITE. If only
       one project is imported this way, it is automatically opened. Please note
       that this feature is not supported on some Linux distributions.
     </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
  <emphasis role="strong">Highlight components at which an error occures</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
     <para>
       It is now possible to highlight the component at which an error occured in
       the screenshot, that is being taken when an error occurs.
       This will only happen if the corresponding checkbox in the
       expert section of the AUT configuration window is selected.
     </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
<emphasis role="strong">Improved Replace Test Case References operation</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
    <para>
        It is now possible to choose default values for unmatched parameters in the Replace Test Case Reference operation (the non-Editor version).
        These default values can not contain references, but all other types are usable (e.g. variables and functions).
    </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Added the possibility to use a static IP Address and port for the AUT - Client connection.</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This is possible by setting the JVM properties <emphasis>jubClientAddr</emphasis> and <emphasis>jubClientPort</emphasis> in either
        the <emphasis>jubula.ini</emphasis> or the <emphasis>testexec.vmoptions</emphasis> configuration files.
        You can also use command-line arguments to achieve the same (e.g. by something like <literal>testexec.exe -jubClientPort 11111</literal>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Double clicking on Test Case Editor root nodes</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        To help navigating between Editors, we added a new feature: when double-clicking a Test Case Editor's root node, if
        there is a single Editor open which references the given Test Case, that Editor is activated. If there are more than one
        such Editors open, you can choose one to activate in a dialog. And if there is no such Editor open, you can
        choose a Test Case or Test Suite which references the Test Case, and open its Editor. 
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Added the possibility to jump to a referenced data set from the Properties View.</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        It is now possible to try to jump to a data set which is referenced by a parameter through the getCentralTestDataSetValue
        function. In case the row and cell are identifiable from the arguments of the function then they are also selected in the Data
        Sets View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
         We improved the Check / Store Property actions for HTML AUTs using a Webdriver.
         It is now possible to access any (specifically, CSS) attributes and properties of HTML elements.
         To access a CSS property, simply use its name (e.g. <literal>background-color</literal>).
         Please note that the actual value returned is strongly browser-dependent.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The background of browsers now change their color when filtering is active. We introduced this to remind you about the active filtering so you don't get confused about not finding elements that are
        currently hidden by the filter.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
<para>
  <emphasis role="strong">Update site for the RCP Accessor</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
     <para>
       We added a P2 update site for the RCP Accessor to the file
       <emphasis>&lt;installation-directory&gt;/development/rcp-accessor-repo.zip</emphasis>.
       You can use this site in the <emphasis role="menuPath">Help</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">
       Install new software...</emphasis> menu of an RCP AUT to
       add the RCP Accessor. Of course this option is only available if your AUT provides
       this feature.
     </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
  <emphasis role="strong">New navigation feature in HTML reports</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
     <para>
       Similarly to the ITE, it is now possible to navigate between errors in an HTML report.
       The navigation always starts from the active (currently selected)
       node of the result tree. This active node is distinguished by a lightgray background.
     </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
  <emphasis role="strong">Update in the Jubula API</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
     <para>
       ActionHandlers are now returning Result objects so the return value can be
       extracted. This is useful for actions like readValue which e.g. has the text of
       a component as return value.
     </para>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
     <para>
       Two new actions have been added to the Jubula API. <emphasis>getProperty</emphasis> can now
       be used to get a property of a component and <emphasis>isSelected</emphasis> can be used to
       check whether a checkbox or a toggle button is selected.
     </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>
