<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="waits-and-delays" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                             xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                             xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Waits and delays</title>
  <para>
    This analysis can be performed on Test Result Reports in the Execution Perspective and in the Reporting Perspective. Select a node you want to analyze and select:
  </para>
  
  <para>
    <emphasis role="menuPath">Analyze</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Waits and delays</emphasis>
  </para>
  
  <para>
    from the context-sensitive menu.
  </para>
  <para>
    The analysis examines the selected node and the nodes below it
    in the Test Result Report for all instances where a wait is
    performed. This can be the action ”<emphasis>Wait</emphasis>” or
    it could also be the parameters ”<emphasis>Delay
    after...</emphasis>” or ”<emphasis>Delay before...</emphasis>”.
    Basically, any time a static wait (i.e. not a timeout) is
    performed, then this is analyzed.
  </para>
  <para>
    You can define a parameter for the analysis which specifies the
    minimum value of waits to be analyzed (in milliseconds). If you
    enter e.g. 5000, then only waits above 5000ms will be shown in
    the results.
  </para>
  <para>
    Once the results have been calculated, they are shown in the
    Search Result View. They are organized according to the action
    that the wait is contained in. The amount of waits corresponding
    to each action is shown in brackets behind the action name. On
    the right hand side of the Search Result View, the cumulative
    values for the amount of waits for each action are shown. The
    number on the left is the total amount of waits that correspond
    to the parameter value entered. The number on the right shows
    the total amount of waits for this action, regardless of the
    parameter. In this way, it is easier to see whether your tests
    have a few very large waits, or many smaller waits.
  </para>
  <para role="tip">
    Double click on one of the wait actions to jump to this
    place in the test Result View.
  </para>
</section>