<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="using-chronon-when-testing-your-aut" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Using Chronon when testing your AUT</title>
  <para>
    You can configure your AUT to run with Chronon recording so that
    you can analyze any errors that occur during your automated test
    runs. See the section later (<xref linkend="analyzing-the-generated-reports"/>) on
    analysing the reports for information on the tooling required to
    do this.
  </para>
  <para role="tip">
    Jubula Feature users: The support for Chronon recording
    in AUTs is currently only available in the standalone software.
  </para>
  <section xml:id="adding-chronon-information-in-the-aut-configuration">
    <title>Adding Chronon information in the AUT configuration</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" condition="autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId" xml:id="adding-chronon-information-in-the-aut-configuration.autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId" xreflabel="Configuring an AUT"/>
    <para>
      You can select Chronon as a monitoring agent and configure it
      in the Expert Settings in the AUT configuration.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open the AUT configuration dialog from the Project
          properties (<xref linkend="projectproperties"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select the <emphasis>Expert</emphasis> configuration.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select <emphasis>Chronon (separate
          installation)</emphasis> as a monitoring agent
          (<xref linkend="configuring-the-separate-chronon-installation-for-use-with-your-aut"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can then enter the configuration details for the
          monitoring.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="configuring-the-separate-chronon-installation-for-use-with-your-aut">
    <title>Configuring the separate Chronon installation for use with your AUT</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" condition="autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId" xml:id="configuring-the-separate-chronon-installation-for-use-with-your-aut.autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId" xreflabel="Configuring an AUT"/>
    <para>
      Enter the following configuration details:
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Java Agent JAR:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Enter the path to the Chronon recorder JAR you have
            installed.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Native Agent File:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The path to the platform-specific native recorder agent
            library.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Config file:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Enter the absolute path to the configuration file for the recorder. The configuration file has the same setup as a Java properties file. It must contain the following properties:
          </para>
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="input">servermode</emphasis> (set to true)
          </para>
            
          <para>
            <emphasis role="input">name</emphasis> (the AUT name as it will be displayed in the Chronon Recording Server UI)
          </para>
            
          <para>
            <emphasis role="input">autostartwithconfig</emphasis> (if you want the recording to start automatically (recommended) then the recording parameters need to be set in the Chronon application.)
          </para>
            
          <para>
            <emphasis role="input">port</emphasis> (optional – if none is entered, 8042 is used.).
          </para>
            
          <para>
            The documentation for the configuration file is available on the Chronon site:
          </para>
          
          <para>
            <link xl:href="http://chronon.onconfluence.com/\&#10;display/DOC/Recorder+Configuration+File">http://chronon.onconfluence.com/<?linebreak?>
display/DOC/Recorder+Configuration+File</link>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para role="tip">
      You can also refer to the Chronon documentation for information on the required parameters to run your tests with the Recording Server. :
      
      <link xl:href="http://chronon.onconfluence.com/display/\&#10;DOC/Recording+outside+Eclipse">http://chronon.onconfluence.com<?linebreak?>
/display/DOC/Recording+outside+Eclipse</link>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="adapting-tests-to-improve-data-collection">
    <title>Adapting tests to improve data collection</title>
    <para>
      You should bear the following in mind when using Chronon for recording information in automated tests.
    </para>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Performance in the AUT may be
      affected</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The recordings that Chronon performs are very
          memory-intensive. For this reason, you may notice
          performance differences in your AUT. It may also be
          necessary to increase the step delay for your tests, and /
          or add extra synchronization to compensate for the
          performance differences when Chronon is running.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          For these reasons, we do not recommend having Chronon
          configured as a part of your standard AUT configuration.
          Instead, we suggest running tests with Chronon monitoring
          when needed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          We also strongly suggest ensuring that your AUT and the
          machine it is running on have sufficient memory to cope
          with the increased monitoring activity.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Stopping or restarting the AUT will
      cause the previously recorded information to be
      lost</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The recording files are written when the AUT is stopped.
          This means either stopping the AUT by hand, using the
          ”<emphasis>Stop AUT</emphasis>” button in on the toolbar
          in the ITE or when you use the
          <emphasis>restart</emphasis> action.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Because of this, we recommend executing individual Test
          Cases (use cases) in Test Suites that you want to analyze
          with Chronon. You should ensure that any Event Handlers in
          the Test Suite will not cause the AUT to restart.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="analyzing-the-generated-reports">
    <title>Analyzing the generated reports</title>
    <para>
      To analyze the reports generated, you will require the Chronon
      Time Travelling Debugger from Chronon Systems. You can
      download a trial version of this tool. The link to the trial
      version is provided in the expert AUT configuration.
    </para>
    <para>
      Open source projects may contact Chronon Systems for free
      licenses.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>