<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="starting-ios-auts" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                              xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Starting iOS AUTs</title>
  <section xml:id="connecting-to-the-aut-agent">
    <title>Connecting to the AUT Agent</title>
    <para>
      The AUT Agent does not need to be started on the simulator or
      device for testing iOS AUTs. It does, however, need to be
      started to ensure that the communication can take place. The
      actual communication with the simulator or the device is
      accomplished using a port that is defined in the test AUT
      (<xref linkend="setting-up-ios-aut"/>) and configured in the AUT
      configuration (<xref linkend="configuring-ios-aut"/>).
    </para>
    <para role="tip">
      Since the place where the AUT Agent is started is not
      important, we recommend starting it on localhost.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="configuring-ios-aut">
    <title>Configuring an iOS AUT</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter the basic configuration details as described earlier
          (<xref linkend="basic-configuration-info"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The working directory currently has no effect.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter the iOS Device Host: this is the address of the
          device or simulator in the network that the AUT will run
          on. The host will either be a hostname or an IP address.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter the iOS Device Port: this is the port number that is
          available for communication between the AUT and the ITE.
          It is defined as a part of the setup of the AUT. If no
          port number has been specified in the AUT, the default of
          11022 will be used, and you should enter this number.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para role="warning">
      Starting iOS AUTs with <emphasis>autrun</emphasis> is
      not supported.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="starting-and-connecting-to-ios-auts">
    <title>Starting and connecting to iOS AUTs</title>
    <para>
      Unlike other AUTs, iOS AUTs are not
      <emphasis>started</emphasis> via the ITE, nor by the testexec.
      Instead, the AUT must have been made testable
      (<xref linkend="setting-up-ios-aut"/>), had component naming added
      (<xref linkend="design-for-testability-ios-auts"/>) and also be started on the simulator or
      device that it will be tested on. Once these prerequisites
      have been completed, you can connect to the AUT from the ITE
      by selecting the AUT from the list in the ”<emphasis>Start
      AUT</emphasis>” button on the toolbar. This does not start the
      AUT but connects to it.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>