<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section id="starting-web-auts" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                              xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Starting Web AUTs (HTML)</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId">Configuring an AUT</anchor>
  <para>
    The AUT configuration dialog for HTML has three different levels
    of detail: basic, advanced and expert.
  </para>
  <para>
    See the sections below for information on the different levels.
  </para>
  <section id="basic-html-aut-configuration">
    <title>Basic HTML AUT configuration</title>
    <para>
      Use the basic setting to specify the URL and Browser you wish
      to start this AUT configuration on.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter the basic configuration details as described earlier
          (<xref linkend="basic-configuration-info"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can optionally create a working directory to store
          files in (<xref linkend="using-working-dir-aut-config"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter the URL of your AUT. <para role="warning">Relative paths to the
          URL cannot be used!</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select the browser you want to start the AUT in.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      For information on the advanced properties for the AUT
      configuration, see the next
      <xref linkend="advanced-html-aut-config"/>.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="advanced-html-aut-config">
    <title>Advanced HTML AUT configuration</title>
    <para>
      You can use the advanced dialog to enter the browser path for
      your browser. This lets you use a specific version of the
      browser (not available for Internet Explorer).
    </para>
    <para>
      You can also specify whether you want to be able to use the
      multi-window support in your tests for this AUT. If your AUT
      has functions that open new windows, then deactivate the
      <emphasis>Single Window Mode</emphasis> checkbox. Any AUTs
      that are running in multi-window mode show the Selenium
      console as well as the AUT when the AUT is started. The Object
      Mapping Editor for multi-window AUTs has a button to allow
      switching between multiple open windows for mapping
      components, and there are actions in the HTML unbound modules
      to allow you to switch between windows during the test.
    </para>
    <para>
      For information on the expert properties for the HTML AUT
      configuration, see the next
      <xref linkend="expert-html-aut-config"/>.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="expert-html-aut-config">
    <title>Expert HTML AUT configuration</title>
    <para>
      You can use the expert dialog to enter an <emphasis>ID
      attribute name</emphasis> (<xref linkend="design-for-testability-html-auts"/>). If you have used a
      specific tag to name components in your application, enter the
      tag in the Expert Configuration area. This information is then
      used instead of the <emphasis>name attribute in the object
      recognition</emphasis>.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can also select an activation method for your AUT. See the
      section on AUT activation (<xref linkend="aut-activation"/>) for more
      details.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>