<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="configuringaut" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                           xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                           xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Configuring AUTs to be started from the ITE</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId" xml:id="configuringaut.autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId" xreflabel="Configuring an AUT"/>
  <para>
    Once you have created a Project (<xref linkend="newproject"/>) and
    defined an AUT (<xref linkend="define-aut"/>), you can add and edit
    AUT configurations.
  </para>
  <para>
    The details in the AUT configuration provide information on
    how to start the AUT, e.g. on which machine.
  </para>
  <para>
    An AUT can have multiple configurations (for example, for
    local and remote testing). A configuration contains all the
    information required to start the AUT, and may contain
    platform- or installation-specific information such as paths to
    working directories, AUT arguments, Java versions, browser
    choices and activation methods.
  </para>
  <para>
    In the AUT Configuration Dialog, it is possible to try to start the AUT using the entered
    configuration. This way it is possible to quickly check whether the configuration is correct.
    Use the <literal>Try AUT</literal> button for this. If the ITE is connected to an AUT Agent,
    that agent is used to start the AUT, otherwise the embedded Agent is started.
  </para>
  <para role="tip">
    If you want to start your Java AUT yourself, and have the ITE connect to it, then use the <emphasis>autrun</emphasis> command to start the AUT (<xref linkend="starting-java-with-the-command"/>). In this case, you do not need to create an AUT configuration.
  </para>
  <section xml:id="aut-activation">
    <title>AUT activation</title>
    <para>
      Activation makes sure that the AUT is in focus at the
      beginning of test execution. This is acheived by clicking
      somewhere in the AUT window. You can specify the
      activation method (i.e. where to click) as part of a
      configuration for an AUT, or you can create a Test Step
      within a test to do the same thing.
    </para>
    <para>
      The advantage of specifying an activation method here is that
      it is central and affects each test execution started on this
      AUT with this configuration.
    </para>
    <para>
      Bear in mind that you may need to activate your AUT in
      order for tests to work, especially if the AUT runs on
      the same machine as the ITE.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>