<section id="working-with-test-cases" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Working with Test Cases</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="testSpecificationViewContextId">Test Case Browser</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="problemViewContextId">Problem View</anchor>
  <para>
    Test Cases are the ”building blocks” (keywords) for testing. They
    can:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        contain other (referenced) Test Cases (<xref linkend="adding-items-to-editors"/>)
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        contain Test Steps (<xref linkend="specsteps"/>)
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        be used in Test Suites (<xref linkend="adding-items-to-editors"/>)
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        be used as Event Handlers (<xref linkend="dealing-with-errors-in-tests"/>)
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <section id="creating-test-cases">
    <title>Creating Test Cases</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testcaseNewContextId">New Test Case Dialog</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerSpecTestCaseEditorContextId">Test Case Editor</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSpecificationViewContextId">Test Case Browser</anchor>
    <para>
      Most of the time spent writing tests will involve creating and
      editing Test Cases.
    </para>
    <para>
      To create a Test Case, you must have created or opened a Project
      (<xref linkend="working-with-projects"/>).
    </para>
    <para>
      The Test Case Browser must also be visible. If it is not visible, change to the Specification Perspective perspective and select:
      
      <para>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Window</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Show View</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Test Case Browser</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">You can also have multiple instances of the Test Case
      Browser open (<xref linkend="opening-the-test-case-browser-multiple-times"/>).</para>
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Create a Test Case by using the context-sensitive menu in the Test Case Browser:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">New</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">New Test Case</emphasis>. <para role="tip">You can also create Test Cases with a double-click on the ”<emphasis>Test Cases:</emphasis>” root entry or on a category in the Test Case Browser.</para>
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A dialog to name the Test Case will appear
          (<xref linkend="newtestcasedialog"/>). Because the testing approach
          is keyword-driven, it is important to name Test Cases
          meaningfully – you will be able to read your tests easily
          and quickly choose which Test Case you need.
        </para>
        <figure id="newtestcasedialog">
          <title>New Test Case Dialog</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/newtestcasedialog.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>New Test Case
            Dialog</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          This creates a new Test Case with that name in the Test Case
          Browser (<xref linkend="newtestcaseinbrowser"/>).
        </para>
        <figure id="newtestcaseinbrowser">
          <title>Test Case in Test Case Browser</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/newtestcaseinbrowser.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>Test Case in Test Case
            Browser</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="strong">Next steps</emphasis><?linebreak?>
      The next step is to add Test Cases from the library of Test Cases to this Test Case (<xref linkend="creating-tests-from-the-library-of-pre-defined-test-cases"/>).
    </para>
    <para>
      You can also:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Reuse this Test Case to form other Test Cases
          (<xref linkend="adding-items-to-editors"/>)
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Edit its content in the Test Case Editor
          (<xref linkend="working-with-editors"/>)
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Add this Test Case to a Test Suite to be executed
          (<xref linkend="adding-items-to-editors"/>)
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Use this Test Case as an Event Handler
          (<xref linkend="dealing-with-errors-in-tests"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="creating-tests-from-the-library-of-pre-defined-test-cases">
    <title>Creating tests from the library of pre-defined Test Cases</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerSpecTestCaseEditorContextId">Test Case Editor</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testCaseAddExistingContextId">Existing Test Case Dialog</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSpecificationViewContextId">Test Case Browser</anchor>
    <para>
      Everything you need to create tests is already available for you
      in each Project. The library of Test Cases which appears
      automatically in each new Project contains all the actions
      supported for testing as well as some examples of more complex
      keywords. For general information about the library, read the
      section later on (<xref linkend="library-information"/>). To learn how to
      use the library to create tests, read the next 
      <xref linkend="using-the-library"/>.
    </para>
    <section id="using-the-library">
      <title>Using the library to create tests</title>
      <para>
        Creating tests with the ITE is really just a matter of:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Deciding how to structure your tests (i.e. what keywords
            to create and how to combine them).
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Choosing the Test Cases from the library (or from your own
            set of Test Cases) that you need to create these keywords.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        To use the Test Cases from the library, you will first need to
        create a Test Case of your own (<xref linkend="creating-test-cases"/>).
      </para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Open the Test Case Editor by double-clicking on the
            Test Case you want to edit in the Test Case Browser.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            In the Test Case Browser, browse to a Test Case that
            you want to add. For help on finding your way around the
            library, see the later
            <xref linkend="tips-and-tricks-library"/>.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can add the Test Case by dragging and dropping from the Test Case Browser to the Test Case Editor or you can right click on the Test Case in the Test Case Editor and select:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="menuPath">Reference Existing Test Case</emphasis>
            </para>
            
            to see a list of all Test Cases that you can add to this Test Case.
          </para>
          <para>
            <para role="tip">You can filter in this dialog using the field at the top. Use star <emphasis role="input">*</emphasis> as a wild card.</para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <para role="tip">You can open the dialog to reference an existing Test Case by pressing <emphasis role="input">»ENTER«</emphasis> on a Test Case in the Test Case Editor.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Once you have added the Test Case, you will need to enter
            a component name in the Component Names View
            (<xref linkend="entering-and-reassigning-component-names-in-the-component-names-view"/>) and you will need to enter
            data for the Test Case in the Properties View
            (<xref linkend="working-with-data"/>).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="library-information">
      <title>Information about the library</title>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can use a highly reusable library of Test Cases to
            specify tests.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The Projects containing the Test Case libraries are located under:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis>examples/testcaseLibrary</emphasis>.
            </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The Projects available are:
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                unbound_modules_concrete
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                unbound_modules_web
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                unbound_modules_swt
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                unbound_modules_rcp
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            These Projects contain reusable Test Cases which have
            been created in advance so you do not have to specify them
            yourself.
            <para role="tip">Refer to the chapter on Components, Actions, and Parameters for information on components, the
            actions they support, and their parameters.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The library is split into categories of <emphasis>actions</emphasis>
            on components. To select something in your AUT, open
            the <emphasis>select</emphasis> category and then open the category
            for the type of component you want to select something
            from.
          </para>
          <para>
            <para role="tip">The names for these Test Cases all begin with ”<emphasis>ub</emphasis>”. This means that they are <emphasis>unbound</emphasis> -- they are not in any way dependent on an AUT. </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Each Test Case in the library contains one Test Step which
            corresponds to the action in the Test Case name. The
            component name is a placeholder, and the parameters have
            been referenced so that you can enter your own data.
          </para>
          <para>
            <para role="tip">The unbound modules Projects which correspond to your chosen Project toolkit are automatically imported into the database and reused in your Project.</para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <para role="warning">We do not recommend making changes to the installed unbound module Projects, for compatibility reasons. If you have Test Cases you want to reuse in other Projects, we advise creating your own library Project.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="tips-and-tricks-library">
      <title>Tips and tricks for using the Test Case library</title>
      <para>
        The Test Cases in the library are organised into actions. In
        the <emphasis>basic</emphasis> category, you will find the various actions
        offered for testing. The <emphasis>complex</emphasis> category contains
        some example keywords which are built up of more than one
        Test Case.
      </para>
      <para>
        When specifying your tests, you need to find and choose which
        actions you will need. This takes some practice, but there are
        some hints which can help you:
      </para>
      <para>
        <emphasis role="strong">High-Level Actions</emphasis><?linebreak?>
        During a test, <emphasis>high-level</emphasis> actions are executed. This means that if you want to select something from a menu using the menupath, for example, you need to look in the category:
        
        <para>
          <emphasis>Actions (basic)/Select/Menu Bar</emphasis>
        </para>
        
        and select the Test Case:
        
        <para>
          <emphasis>ub_mbr_selectEntry_byTextpath</emphasis>
        </para>
        
        The Test Case finds the menu, opens it, and clicks the item you specify.
      </para>
      <para>
        <emphasis role="strong">Abstract components</emphasis><?linebreak?>
        There are some actions which are executable on many different components. Clicks, for example can be executed on pratically all components in the interface. You can also check text on labels, combo boxes and text fields. Obviously, it makes sense to specify your Test Cases as abstractly as possible so that they can be reused in more places. This helps keep the maintenance low later.
      </para>
      <para>
        You will notice in the library that there is no
        <emphasis>Button</emphasis> category under the <emphasis>Click</emphasis> category.
        Instead, you will find various click actions specified for
        <emphasis>Graphics Component (grc)</emphasis>. This is because all
        components which support clicks belong to the
        <emphasis>Graphics Component</emphasis> group.
      </para>
      <para>
        In the same way, you will find the category <emphasis>Check/Component with Text</emphasis>. You can use the check actions from this category to check text on any component with text – buttons, text fields, combo boxes, labels.
      </para>
      <para>
        <emphasis role="strong">Parameters</emphasis><?linebreak?>
        Different actions require different data. Some Test Cases in the library have been pre-configured with data to make test specification easier (look in the category <emphasis>Input via Keyboard/Application/Key Combination</emphasis> for a long list).
      </para>
      <para>
        Some actions let you choose whether you want to enter data
        using an <emphasis>indexpath</emphasis> or a <emphasis>textpath</emphasis>. We
        recommend using the textpath so that you are not dependent on
        the order of e.g. menu entries or tabbed panes.
      </para>
      <para>
        To make text-based parameters more robust, you can often
        choose an <emphasis>operator</emphasis>. You can choose between
        <emphasis>equals, matches, simple match, not equals</emphasis>. Using
        matches lets you use regular expressions so that you don’t
        have to hard-code the whole text parameter.
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="opening-existing-test-cases">
    <title>Opening existing Test Cases</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerSpecTestCaseEditorContextId">Test Case Editor</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testCaseOpenExistingContextId">Open Existing Test Case</anchor>
    <para>
      You can open an existing Test Case without having to select it
      from the Test Case Browser using the <emphasis>Open Test
      Case</emphasis> dialog.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          This dialog can be opened using the shortcut <emphasis role="input">»CTRL+SHIFT+T«</emphasis> or from the menu:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Edit</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Open Test Case</emphasis>
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the dialog, you can search for a Test Case or Test Cases
          in the tree or using the filter (<xref linkend="using-filters-in-the-ite"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select the Test Cases you want to add, and click
          ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The selected Test Cases will be opened in indidivual Test
          Case editors.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">You can use this option to open a Test Case even if a
      filter is active in the Test Case Browser.</para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="editing-test-cases">
    <title>Editing Test Cases</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSpecificationViewContextId">Test Case Browser</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerSpecTestCaseEditorContextId">Test Case Editor</anchor>
    <para>
      From the Test Case Editor, you can edit a Test Case. You can:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          add other Test Cases (<xref linkend="adding-items-to-editors"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          add and edit Test Steps (<xref linkend="specsteps"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          rename the Test Case (<xref linkend="renaming-items-in-browsers"/>) or the Test
          Cases it contains (<xref linkend="renaming-items-in-editors"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          add a comment to the Test Case
          (<xref linkend="adding-comments-to-items-in-editors"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          add, edit or translate data for the Test Case
          (<xref linkend="using-the-data-sets-view"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          extract Test Cases from within this Test Case to make
          reusable modules (<xref linkend="extracting-test-cases-from-editors-refactoring"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          deactivate specific Test Cases in this Test Case so they are
          ignored during execution (<xref linkend="commenting-out-items-in-editors"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          replace one or more Test Cases in it with another Test Case
          (<xref linkend="replacing-test-cases-in-editors-refactoring"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="adding-and-inserting-new-test-cases-to-a-test-case">
    <title>Adding and inserting new Test Cases to a Test Case</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="dialogTestcaseAddNewContextId">Add New Test Case Dialog</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="dialogTestcaseInsertNewContextId">Insert New Test Case Dialog</anchor>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open the Test Case Editor by double-clicking on the Test
          Case you want to edit in the Test Case Browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          From the context-sensitive menu, select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Add</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">New Test Case</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          (This places the Test Case after any other items in the Test Case Editor.) or
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Insert</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">New Test Case</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          (This places the Test Case above the currently selected item in the Test Case Editor.)
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the dialog that appears, enter a meaningful name for the
          new Test Case.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Test Case appears in the Test Case Editor in the parent
          Test Case and also appears in the Test Case Browser. The
          Test Case is marked with a small arrow to show that it is
          reused here. The name of the Test Case is contained in
          angled brackets (<emphasis role="input">&lt; &gt;</emphasis>) to show that it
          is the same name that you used when you specified the Test
          Case.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Save the changes in the editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="moving-test-cases-to-external-projects">
    <title>Moving Test Cases to external Projects</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testCaseMoveExternalContextId">Move Test Cases to an External Project</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSpecificationViewContextId">Test Case Browser</anchor>
    <para>
      If you are reusing a Project or Projects in your currently
      opened Project (<xref linkend="reuseproject"/>), you can move Test Cases you
      create to these reused Projects to make them a part of that
      Project.
    </para>
    <para>
      This lets you add useful Test Cases to external libraries to be
      reused in other Projects.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Test Case Browser, select the Test Case, Test Cases
          or categories you want to move to an external Project that
          you are currently reusing in the open Project.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Right click on the selected items and select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Move to external Project</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          from the context-sensitive menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          From the dialog which appears, select which reused Project
          to move them to.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The items you selected will appear in the blue colored
          category of the reused Project you selected and will
          disappear from their original place.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The structure of your Project stays the same – the moved
          Test Cases are not deleted from places where you have reused
          them, for example.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="warning">If you move Test Cases containing referenced Test Cases
      from other Projects, make sure that the Project the Test Cases
      are dependent on is also reused in your external Project.</para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="replacing-a-specific-test-case-at-places-where-it-has-been-reused">
    <title>Replacing a specific Test Case at places where it has been reused</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="searchResultViewContextId">Search Result View</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="searchRefactorReplaceExecutionTestCaseWizardContextId">Replace Test Case</anchor>
    <para>
      If you have reused a Test Case at multiple places in your
      Project, and later create a new Test Case that should replace
      it, then you can perform a mass replace via the Search Result
      View. If you just want to replace one single place where a Test
      Case has been reused, then you can either select that Test Case
      in the Search Result View or use the in-editor replace
      (<xref linkend="replacing-test-cases-in-editors-refactoring"/>).
    </para>
    <para>
      <para role="warning">In order to perform a mass replace, all Test Cases to be
      changed must not be in use by anyone else using the Project –
      you should ensure that this is the case before performing the
      replace, otherwise the replace cannot be carried out. You should
      also be aware before performing this action that it cannot be
      undone.</para>
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Search for all places where the Test Case you want to
          replace is used e.g. <emphasis>Show where used</emphasis>
          (<xref linkend="searching-for-places-where-a-test-case-or-test-suite-has-been-used"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Search Result View, you will see all places where the
          selected Test Case is reused in this Project, including in
          other Test Cases, in Test Suites and anywhere you have used
          the Test Case as an Event Handler. Select all entries, or
          just the Test Case references you want to replace with a new
          Test Case reference. <para role="warning">You will only be able to perform
          the replace if all selected Test Case references use the
          same original Test Case. The context-menu entry will be
          disabled if the Project is protected, or any of the selected
          Test Cases are missing (e.g. from reused Projects)</para>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          From the context menu, select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Replace with another Test Case</emphasis>
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The first page of a wizard will appear. Here, you can choose
          the Test Case you want to use as a replacement at the places
          you selected. It is a good idea to select a Test Case that
          ”fits well” (in terms of any component names it propagates
          and parameters it references) to the Test Case you are
          replacing. You will be able to map any compatible components
          and parameter names in the next steps.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Press ”<emphasis>Next</emphasis>” to continue to the next
          page of the wizard.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          On this page, you can match any component names propagated
          (<xref linkend="propagating-component-names"/>) from the newly selected Test
          Case to already existing propagated component names from the
          old Test Case. On the left-hand side, you can see names that
          are propagated from the newly chosen Test Case. On the
          right-hand side, you can:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              match the new names to existing names if there are
              compatible names available in the existing Test Case.
              The information for names you match in this way will be
              transferred from the existing Test Case to the new Test
              Case when the replacement occurs. Any new names entered,
              or further propagations at the places of reuse, will
              also be transferred. This is the best way of ensuring
              that your Project structure is the same after the
              replace.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              choose to leave any combo boxes empty. In this case, no
              match for that component name will take place, and the
              new component name will be used.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              see if there are no names available, either because
              there is no compatible type for matching in the existing
              Test Case, or because the existing Test Case had no
              propagated component names. In such cases, the new
              component name will be used.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>
          <para role="warning">For any non-matched (or non-matchable) component
          names, the new names from the new Test Case will be used.
          This may result in incomplete object mapping for your
          tests.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Once you have matched any component names, press
          ”<emphasis>Next</emphasis>” to continue to the next page of
          the wizard.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          On this page, you can match any referenced parameter names
          (<xref linkend="using-references-for-data-in-test-cases"/>) from the newly selected Test
          Case to already existing referenced parameter names from the
          old Test Case. On the left-hand side, you can see parameters
          that are referenced from the newly chosen Test Case. On the
          right-hand side you can:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              match the new parameter to existing parameters if there
              are compatible types available in the existing Test
              Case. The data for any parameters you match in this way
              will be transferred from the existing Test Case to the
              new Test Case when the replacement occurs. Any test data
              entered locally, any test data referenced from the
              original specification, and any central test data sets
              or Excel tables used, will also be transferred. This is
              the best way of ensuring that your Project structure is
              the same after the replace.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              choose to leave any combo boxes empty. In this case, no
              match for that parameter will take place, and the new
              parameter will be used.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              see if there are no names available, either because
              there is no compatible type for matching in the existing
              Test Case, or because the existing Test Case had no
              referenced parameters. In such cases, the new parameter
              will be used after the replace.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>
          <para role="warning">For any non-matched (or non-matchable) parameters,
          the new parameters from the new Test Case will be used. This
          may result in incomplete test data for your tests.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Once you have finished matching the parameters, press
          ”<emphasis>Finish</emphasis>” to perform the replace.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">The Test Case reference names and any comments that were
      used for the original Test Case references, will be transferred
      to each new Test Case reference. If the original Test Case
      reference was commented out, the replacement Test Case reference
      will be as well. If you had used the original Test Case as an
      Event Handler, the Event Handler details will also be
      transferred.</para>
    </para>
  </section>
</section>