<section id="define-aut" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                       xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                       xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Defining applications under test (AUTs)</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="autSettingWizardPagePageContextId">Defining an AUT</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="runningAutsViewContextId">Running AUTs View</anchor>
  <para>
    Once you have created a Project, you can define (and edit) AUTs.
    You can define a new AUT straight after creating the Project in
    the Project wizard or you can do it later on via the Project
    properties (<xref linkend="projectproperties"/>).
  </para>
  <para>
    <para role="tip">If you will be starting your Java AUT with the
    <emphasis>autrun</emphasis> command (<xref linkend="starting-java-with-the-command"/>), then you
    can automatically define your AUT (<xref linkend="create-aut-def"/>)</para>
  </para>
  <para>
    The AUT dialog (<xref linkend="autdialog"/>) appears when you define or
    edit an AUT.
  </para>
  <figure id="autdialog">
    <title>AUT Dialog</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="../images/autdialog.png"/>
      </imageobject>
      <textobject><phrase>AUT Dialog</phrase></textobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para>
    <para role="tip">If you know that you will be working with multiple versions
    of the same AUT (e.g. a version for Windows and Linux, or two
    versions that use different databases), then define
    <emphasis>one</emphasis> AUT here and create multiple
    configurations (<xref linkend="configuringaut"/>) for this AUT. This means
    that your different configurations will all share one object map.
    If you are working with multiple completely different AUTs, then
    define the different AUTs here.</para>
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Enter a meaningful and unique AUT name. This is used to easily
        identify the AUT later.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Select the toolkit the AUT uses from the combo box.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you choose RCP, decide whether or not you want to generate
        names for components in the AUT which have not been named by
        your developers (<xref linkend="rcp-component-name-generation"/>). We recommend leaving this
        option checked, as it increases the robustness of your tests.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you are starting a Java AUT and will be starting it using the <emphasis>autrun</emphasis> command (<xref linkend="starting-java-with-the-command"/>), or if the AUT will be launched from another AUT during the test (<xref linkend="testing-aut-launched-by-other"/>), then enter the ID(s) for these AUTs here.
      </para>
      <para>
        <emphasis role="strong">IDs for AUTs started by the <emphasis>autrun</emphasis> command</emphasis><?linebreak?>
        Enter the AUT IDs you will use for any AUTs started by the <emphasis>autrun</emphasis> command (the AUT ID for the AUT is given as a parameter in the <emphasis>autrun</emphasis> command (<xref linkend="starting-java-with-the-command"/>).
      </para>
      <para>
        <emphasis role="strong">IDs for AUTs launched by other AUTs</emphasis><?linebreak?>
        The AUT ID will take a specific form (<xref linkend="testing-aut-launched-by-other"/>) and must be defined as such in the AUT definition.
      </para>
      <para>
        <para role="tip">If you will be starting your AUT from the ITE (i.e. via
        an AUT configuration (<xref linkend="configuringaut"/>)) then you do
        not need to enter any IDs here.</para>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        From the list of Project languages, select which languages are
        supported by the AUT.
      </para>
      <para>
        The languages you select are the languages the AUT can be
        started in. You will be able to translate the data in your
        Test Cases into these languages so that a Test Suite will test
        the AUT in the right language.
      </para>
      <para>
        <para role="warning">If you are editing the AUT and remove an AUT language
        for which you have already specified data, this will result in
        the data for that language being lost. </para>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you want to start this AUT from the ITE, you can do so in
        the Project properties (<xref linkend="configuringaut"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para>
    If you do not require an AUT configuration, because you will be
    starting the AUT using the <emphasis>autrun</emphasis> command
    (<xref linkend="starting-java-with-the-command"/>), then you do not need to create an AUT
    configuration.
  </para>
</section>