<section id="working-with-browsers" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                  xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Working with browsers: renaming, deleting, using IDs,
  multiple browsers</title>
  <para>
    Select an item in a browser to see read-only details in the
    Properties View, Data Sets View and Component Names View for this
    item.
  </para>
  <para>
    You can rename items from the Test Case Browser, Test Suite
    Browser or Component Names Browser.
  </para>
  <para>
    You can open editors for items in certain browsers. See the later
    <xref linkend="working-with-editors"/> for more details.
  </para>
  <para>
    You can also save the ID of Test Cases and Test Suites in browsers
    to the clipboard, in order to link these elements with external
    systems.
  </para>
  <section id="renaming-items-in-browsers">
    <title>Renaming items in browsers</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="dialogRenameContextId">Renaming</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSpecificationViewContextId">Test Case Browser</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testExecViewContextId">Test Suite Browser</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerComponentNameBrowserContextId">Component Name Browser</anchor>
    <para>
      To rename an item in the Test Case Browser, Test Suite Browser
      or Component Names Browser:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select the item you want to rename in the browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Rename</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          from the context-sensitive menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the dialog which appears, enter a new name and click
          ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">You can also press <emphasis role="input">»F2«</emphasis> to
      rename an item.</para>
    </para>
    <para>
      When you rename a Test Case or Test Suite, you change its
      specification name.
    </para>
    <para>
      If you have reused this Test Case or Test Suite in other Test
      Cases, Test Suites or Test Jobs, the name will also be changed
      in the places where you have reused it but not renamed it.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="deleting-items-from-browsers">
    <title>Deleting items from browsers</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSpecificationViewContextId">Test Case Browser</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testExecViewContextId">Test Suite Browser</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerComponentNameBrowserContextId">Component Name Browser</anchor>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To delete a Test Case, Test Suite, Test Job or component
          name, select it in the browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select ”<emphasis>delete</emphasis>” from the
          context-sensitive menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can also delete items by pressing
          <emphasis role="input">»DELETE«</emphasis>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="warning">If the item you want to delete is referenced somewhere in
      your test, you must first remove it from the place where it is
      reused before deleting it.</para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="working-with-ids-for-test-cases-and-test-suites">
    <title>Working with IDs for Test Cases and Test Suites</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSpecificationViewContextId">Test Case Browser</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testExecViewContextId">Test Suite Browser</anchor>
    <para>
      Each Test Case and Test Suite in a Project has a unique ID which
      can be used to refer to this Test Case or Test Suite within the
      Project and from external systems.
    </para>
    <section id="copying-the-id-of-a-test-case-or-test-suite-to-the-clipboard">
      <title>Copying the ID of a Test Case or Test Suite to the
      clipboard</title>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select the Test Case or Test Suite whose ID you want to
            use from the Test Case Browser or Test Suite Browser.
            <para role="tip">Make sure you select the original specification of
            the element, not a place where it has been reused. Press
            <emphasis role="input">»F6«</emphasis> to find the original
            specification of a selected element.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="menuPath">Copy ID to clipboard</emphasis>
            </para>
            
            from the context-sensitive menu.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can now paste the ID into your external system.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="opening-an-element-based-on-an-id-in-the-clipboard">
      <title>Opening an element based on an ID in the
      clipboard</title>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Copy the ID you want to find from your external system.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            In the ITE, press <emphasis role="input">»Shift+F9«</emphasis>
            to open the Test Case Editor or Test Suite Editor for the
            element with the ID from the clipboard.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="opening-the-test-case-browser-multiple-times">
    <title>Opening the Test Case Browser multiple times</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSpecificationViewContextId">Test Case Browser</anchor>
    <para>
      To make navigation in larger Projects easier, you can open
      multiple instances of the Test Case Browser. You can filter each
      Test Case Browser separately to give you different views of your
      Test Cases at the same time. All instances of the Test Case
      Browser are kept up-to-date with any changes to Test Cases in
      the Project.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To open a new Test Case Browser, select <emphasis>New Test
          Case Browser</emphasis> from the small arrow menu in the
          Test Case Browser. A new Test Case Browser will open.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you have multiple browsers open, one of them will
          always be marked as the main browser in its title. This is
          the default browser for actions such as ”<emphasis>Show
          Specification</emphasis>” and for the displaying of any
          search results. You can switch the main browser using the
          button in the toolbar. If you close the Test Case Browser
          you have marked as being the main browser, another Test Case
          Browser will automatically be marked as the new main
          browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="opening-the-task-editor-for-items-in-browsers">
    <title>Opening the task editor for items in browsers</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSpecificationViewContextId">Test Case Browser</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testExecViewContextId">Test Suite Browser</anchor>
    <para>
      Each Test Case, Test Suite and Test Job in a Project can be
      joined to a task in an external repository via a task ID
      (<xref linkend="working-with-external-task-repositories"/>). You can open the task for an item from the
      browser:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select the item whose task you want to open in the browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Right click and select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Open with</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Mylyn Task Editor</emphasis>
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The task from the external repository will open in the ITE.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="warning">If no repository has been defined for the Project, or the
      task ID does not exist, or the repository is not configured in
      the workspace, then the task will not open.</para>
    </para>
  </section>
</section>