<section id="working-with-projects" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                  xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Working with Projects</title>
  <para>
    The first step once the ITE has been started is to create, open or
    import a Project. Once you have done this, you can specify Test
    Suites, Test Cases and Test Steps.
  </para>
  <section id="newproject">
    <title>Creating a new Project</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="projectWizardContextId">Creating a Project</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="problemViewNoProjectContextId">Project Options Dialog</anchor>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          From the ITE, select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">New</emphasis>.
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If you haven’t already logged into the database, a dialog will appear to ask you to do so.
          See the previous (<xref linkend="tasksdblogin"/>) for details.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A wizard to create a new Project will appear
          (<xref linkend="projsettings"/>).
        </para>
        <figure id="projsettings">
          <title>New Project Dialog</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/newprojectdialog.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>New Project
            Dialog</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the <emphasis>project name</emphasis> field, enter a
          meaningful and unique Project name. Do not use any special
          characters in Project names.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Activate the ”<emphasis>reusable project</emphasis>”
          checkbox if you want to be able to reference the Test Cases
          from this Project in other Projects. This will let you use
          the Test Cases in this Project as the basis or library for
          other Projects (see the section later for more details on
          this (<xref linkend="reuseproject"/>)).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose whether this Project should be protected. In a
          protected Projects, you cannot delete Test Cases, edit
          parameters for Test Cases, or make any changes to the column
          usage of central test data sets. This is only necessary if
          the Project is reused in another Project – the protection
          ensures that irreversible changes cannot be made to the
          reused Project that would adversely affect its dependent
          Projects.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select the toolkit your Project will use from the combo box.
          The toolkit is the library used to create the GUI.
        </para>
        <para>
          <emphasis role="strong">Toolkits for Projects</emphasis><?linebreak?>
          The default toolkit is <emphasis>concrete</emphasis>. Choose this if you want to write Test Cases that can be used for different applications (e.g. for Swing and for RCP).
        </para>
        <para>
          Choose another toolkit if you want to write Test Cases just
          for a Swing, SWT, RCP, iOS, Windows or HTML application.
        </para>
        <para>
          The choice of toolkit you make here will determine what
          actions are available to you to specify your tests. If you
          choose <emphasis>concrete</emphasis>, you will not be able
          to specify tests for components specific to e.g. HTML or
          SWT.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          From the list of available languages, select the languages
          supported by your AUT and move them into the
          ”<emphasis>project language</emphasis>” box using the arrow
          button. Use <emphasis role="input">»CTRL«</emphasis> to select
          multiple languages.
        </para>
        <para>
          You will be able to start the AUT in these languages, and
          translate test data into these languages.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select a default language from the combo box. The default
          language is the language your Project is started in.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can now click ”<emphasis>Next</emphasis>” to define an
          AUT for this Project (<xref linkend="define-aut"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      If you want to define the AUT later, you can click
      ”<emphasis>Finish</emphasis>” to create the Project as it is.
      You can define an AUT later via the Project properties under
      <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Properties</emphasis>.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can also edit the Project details later in the Project
      properties dialog (<xref linkend="projectproperties"/>). 
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="projectproperties">
    <title>Editing the Project and AUT properties</title>
    <para>
      You can open the Project properties dialog (<xref linkend="projectsettingsdialog"/>) via:
      
      <para>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Properties</emphasis>
      </para>
    </para>
    <figure id="projectsettingsdialog">
      <title>Project Properties Dialog</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/general_projproperties.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Project Properties
        Dialog</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
      The Project properties dialog lets you see and, in some cases,
      edit information about:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          the Project in general (<xref linkend="editing-general-project-properties"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          the Project languages (<xref linkend="editing-the-languages-for-a-project"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          the AUTs (<xref linkend="editing-the-auts-in-a-project"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          the Projects that you have reused in this Project
          (<xref linkend="reuseproject"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          the connection to application lifecycle management (ALM)
          repositories in this Project
          (<xref linkend="configuring-a-task-repository"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <section id="editing-general-project-properties">
      <title>Editing general Project properties</title>
      <anchor role="helpid" id="projectSettingsPageContextId">Project Properties</anchor>
      <para>
        Select ”<emphasis>General</emphasis>” from the tree on the left-hand
        side of the Project properties dialog. In the screen that appears, you can:
      </para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Edit the Project name.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Enter a comment for the Project. The comment is visible in
            the Properties View when you select the Project node in
            the Test Suite Browser.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Edit the toolkit used by the Project (see the following
            (<xref linkend="changing-toolkit-settings"/>) for details
            on this).
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
        <para>
        Edit the markup language used for descriptions in the Project 
    	(<xref linkend="adding-descriptions-to-items-in-editors"/>)
        If you edit the markup language after you have entered descriptions, 
        you may need to adapt the description texts to conform to the newly chosen markup language.
        </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Edit whether the Project can be referenced (reused) in
            other Projects.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Edit the protected status of the Project. A protected
            Project does not allow deletion of Test Cases or editing
            of parameters.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            See the Project version. This is useful if you have more
            than one version of a Project.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            See the GUID (global unit identification). This is a
            unique ID for the Project.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Specify how often the full test result details
            (<xref linkend="re-opening-the-test-result-view-for-a-test-run"/>) should be automatically
            deleted from the database.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Configure the tracking of changes in this Project (see the
            section later (<xref linkend="tracking-changes-in-a-project"/>) for details on
            this).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="changing-toolkit-settings">
      <title>Changing the toolkit settings for a Project</title>
      <para>
        If you want to change the toolkit of a Project in the Project
        properties dialog, the following rules apply:
      </para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can change at any time from the
            <emphasis>concrete</emphasis> toolkits to a more specific
            toolkit (e.g. RCP, HTML).
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            If your previous choice of toolkit was RCP, SWT or HTML,
            you can only change to another toolkit if your Project
            does not use any components specific to the originally
            chosen toolkit.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="editing-the-languages-for-a-project">
      <title>Editing the languages for a Project</title>
      <anchor role="helpid" id="projectSettingsPageContextId">Project Properties</anchor>
      <para>
        To see and edit the Project languages, select ”<emphasis>Project languages</emphasis>”
        from the tree on the left-hand side of the Project properties
        dialog.
      </para>
      <para>
        You can add and remove Project languages and change the
        default language in this screen.
      </para>
      <para>
        <para role="tip">You can’t delete a language which is being used as an
        AUT language.</para>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section id="editing-the-auts-in-a-project">
      <title>Editing the AUTs in a Project</title>
      <anchor role="helpid" id="autSettingsPageContextId">Adding/editing AUT's</anchor>
      <para>
        To see and edit your AUTs for a Project, select
        ”<emphasis>AUTs</emphasis>” from the tree on the left-hand
        side of the Project properties dialog.
      </para>
      <para>
        In the screen that appears, you can see any AUTs you have
        already added to the Project (<xref linkend="autsettingsdialog"/>).
        You can choose to edit them, delete them or add a new AUT.
      </para>
      <figure id="autsettingsdialog">
        <title>AUT Properties Dialog</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/autsettingsdialog.png"/>
          </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>AUT Properties
          Dialog</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        Defining and editing AUTs from here involves the same steps as
        defining an AUT in the Project wizard (<xref linkend="define-aut"/>).
      </para>
    </section>
    <section id="duplicating-aut-configurations">
      <title>Duplicating AUT configurations</title>
      <anchor role="helpid" id="autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId">Configuring an AUT</anchor>
      <anchor role="helpid" id="autSettingsPageContextId">Adding/editing AUT's</anchor>
      <para>
        You can duplicate an existing AUT configuration from the
        Project properties dialog:
      </para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select ”<emphasis>AUTs</emphasis>” from the tree on the
            left-hand side of the Project properties dialog.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select the AUT configuration you want to duplicate.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click ”<emphasis>Duplicate</emphasis>”.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The AUT configuration dialog will open. The AUT
            configuration name and the AUT ID are automatically
            changed so that they remain unique. We recommend writing
            more meaningful names for the configuration and the ID,
            however.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="editing-aut-configurations">
      <title>Editing the AUT configurations in a Project</title>
      <anchor role="helpid" id="autConfigPropDialogContextId">Adding/editing AUT configurations</anchor>
      <para>
        Select ”<emphasis>AUTs</emphasis>” from the tree on the
        left-hand side of the Project properties dialog.
      </para>
      <para>
        In the screen that appears, you can see the AUTs you have
        added to this Project. Select the AUT you want to add a
        configuration to, and click ”<emphasis>Edit</emphasis>”.
      </para>
      <para>
        In the next screen there is a box labelled ”<emphasis>AUT
        configurations</emphasis>”. You can choose to add, edit or
        delete AUT configurations.
      </para>
      <para>
        Adding and editing AUT configurations from here involves the
        same steps as adding an AUT configuration in the Project
        wizard (<xref linkend="configuringaut"/>).
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="reuseproject">
    <title>Reusing (referencing) whole Projects in a Project</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="projectUsedPropertyPageContextId">Used Projects Properties</anchor>
    <para>
      You can reuse (reference) Projects as libraries of Test Cases in
      other Projects.
    </para>
    <para>
      To reuse Projects:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Make sure that the Project you want to reuse is in the
          database.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Properties</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          and select <emphasis>Used Projects</emphasis> from the tree on the left of the dialog that appears (<xref linkend="reuseprojectdialog"/>).
        </para>
        <figure id="reuseprojectdialog">
          <title>Reused Projects</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/reuseproject.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>Reused Projects</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A list of Projects you can reuse will be offered on the
          left-hand side of the dialog. You can only reuse Projects
          which support the same toolkit as your current Project (e.g.
          Swing, Concrete). <para role="tip">To be able to reuse a Project, you
          must have checked the <emphasis>reusable</emphasis> box in
          the Project properties for the Project
          (<xref linkend="editing-general-project-properties"/>).</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          From the list of reusable Projects, select a Project and its
          version to reuse in the current Project. Use the arrows to
          move it to the list of reused Projects.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Test Cases from the Project you chose to reuse will
          appear in the Test Case Browser, under a category with the
          same name as the reused Project. The Test Cases will be
          colored blue to distinguish them from other Test Cases in
          this Project.
        </para>
        <para>
          <para role="tip">You cannot edit these Test Cases here – but you can
          reuse them in your Test Cases for this Project and edit
          certain details (referenced parameters, component names)
          when they are reused in other Test Cases.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can change the version of the reused Project via the
          <emphasis>Used Projects</emphasis> Properties dialog, by
          clicking on the ”<emphasis>change used version</emphasis>”
          button (<xref linkend="changing-the-version-of-a-reused-project"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <section id="changing-the-version-of-a-reused-project">
      <title>Changing the version of a reused Project</title>
      <anchor role="helpid" id="databaseMigrationAssistantContextId">Database Migration</anchor>
      <anchor role="helpid" id="projectUsedPropertyPageContextId">Used Projects Properties</anchor>
      <para>
        You can change the version of the reused Project you are using
        in your tests. This is useful to update to a new version of
        the unbound modules, for example.
      </para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            In the <emphasis>Used Project properties</emphasis>,
            select the currently reused Project version from the list
            on the right.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select the new version of this Project from the list on
            the left. <para role="tip">In order to be able to see and select the
            new version of the Project, it must be in your database!</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click the ”<emphasis>Switch version</emphasis>” button,
            marked with the opposing arrows.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The version of the reused Project will be switched.
            <para role="tip">If changes have taken place, it may be necessary to
            update your test. You should especially check for any
            actions that have become deprecated since the last
            version, and replace them with new actions.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="loadproject">
    <title>Opening Projects</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="openProjectDialogContextId">Opening Projects</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="problemViewNoProjectContextId">Project Options Dialog</anchor>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To open a Project from the database, select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Open</emphasis>.
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If you haven’t already logged into the database, a dialog
          will appear to ask you to do so. See the previous section
          (<xref linkend="tasksdblogin"/>) for details.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose the Project you want to open from the combo box in
          the dialog which appears (<xref linkend="loadfromdb"/>).
        </para>
        <figure id="loadfromdb">
          <title>Open Project from database</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/loadfromdb.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>Open Project from
            database</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If the Project has more than one version, choose which
          version you want to open. For more information on Project
          versions, see the section later (<xref linkend="projectversion"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Project is opened in the ITE.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <section id="auto-loading-default-project">
      <title>Auto loading a default Project</title>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Use the checkbox in the <emphasis>Open Project</emphasis> Dialog to specify that you want to open this Project in this version automatically when you select:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="menuPath">Project</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Open</emphasis>
            </para>
            
            This is useful if you only have one Project that you work with.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Per workspace, you can have one default Project. If you
            are connected to a database which does not contain the
            Project, or if the Project is no longer in the database,
            then you will be shown the <emphasis>Open
            Project</emphasis> Dialog and can choose another Project.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            In the Test preferences (<xref linkend="gdprefs"/>), you can disable the auto load of the Project. Doing this will mean that you see the normal <emphasis>Open Project Dialog</emphasis> when you select
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="menuPath">Project</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Open</emphasis>
            </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="refreshproject">
    <title>Refreshing Projects</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testExecViewContextId">Test Suite Browser</anchor>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To refresh a Project, first select the Project in the Test
          Suite Browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">File</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Refresh</emphasis>.
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          This reloads the data for the Project from the database,
          ensuring in a multi-user environment that all Project data
          is current.
        </para>
        <para>
          <para role="tip">If a Project which your current Project reuses has
          been changed, then you must refresh the current Project for
          the changes to take effect. </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="deleteproject">
    <title>Deleting Projects</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="deleteProjectDialogContextId">Deleting Projects</anchor>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To delete a Project from the database, select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Delete</emphasis>.
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If you haven’t already logged into the database, a dialog
          will appear to ask you to do so. See the previous section
          (<xref linkend="tasksdblogin"/>) for details.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose the Project you want to delete from the combo box in
          the dialog (<xref linkend="deleteprojectdialog"/>).
        </para>
        <figure id="deleteprojectdialog">
          <title>Delete Project dialog</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/deleteproject.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>Delete Project
            dialog</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If there is more than one version of the Project, choose
          which version you want to delete.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select whether you want to keep the test result summaries
          associated with this Project or not. <para role="tip">In productive
          databases where you wish to evaluate test results over
          longer periods of time, we recommend selecting the option to
          keep the summaries.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>” to delete the selected
          Project.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Confirm the deletion in the dialog which appears.
          <para role="warning">Deleting a Project from the database cannot be
          undone!</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="saveproject">
    <title>Saving a Project as a new Project</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="dialogProjectSaveAsContextId">Saving Projects under a different name</anchor>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To save the currently opened Project as a new Project, select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Save as...</emphasis>.
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter the new name for the Project in the dialog that
          appears.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          This creates a new Project in the database, saved under the
          name you entered.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If no changes have been made since the previous Project
          save, the new Project has the same content as the previous
          one.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Otherwise, any modifications are saved under the new Project
          name, and the old Project is kept in the state of its last
          save.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The new Project becomes active in the ITE. <para role="tip">Any test
          result summaries for the Project are not duplicated in the
          new Project. Tests that ran for previous versions of the
          Project are, however, still in the database to be used for
          long term analysis.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="importproject">
    <title>Importing Projects</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="problemViewNoProjectContextId">Project Options Dialog</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="dialogProjectImportRenameContextId">Project Import Rename Dialog</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="importProjectDialogContextId">Importing Projects</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="openProjectImportAllRequiredProjectsContextId">Importing Dependent Projects</anchor>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To import Projects, select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Import</emphasis>.
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the dialog which appears (<xref linkend="Import"/>), enter or
          browse to the Projects you want to import.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If you have entered the path to a Project, click
          ”<emphasis>Add</emphasis>” to add it to the list of Projects
          to be imported.
        </para>
        <para>
          <para role="tip">Note that the ”<emphasis>Add</emphasis>” button will
          only be activated if the path you have entered is correct.</para>
        </para>
        <para>
          If you add multiple Projects to be imported, you can change
          the order they are imported in using the arrows next to the
          list of Projects. You can also remove a Project from the
          list of Projects to be imported.
        </para>
        <para>
          <para role="tip">If you are importing Projects that are dependent on
          other Projects (i.e. they reuse other Projects), import the
          supporting Projects first.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If you only want to import one Project, you can select the
          option to open the Project once it has been imported.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you have finished your selection, click
          ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”. The Projects you selected will be
          imported in the order specified.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <figure id="Import">
      <title>Import Dialog</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/Import.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Import Dialog</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section id="exportproject">
    <title>Exporting Projects</title>
    <para>
      You can choose to export the currently opened Project
      (<xref linkend="exportsingle"/>) or all of the Projects in the database
      (<xref linkend="exportall"/>). Projects are exported in .xml format so that
      they can be added to e.g. version control systems.
    </para>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">Projects are exported along with all their test result
      summaries.</para>
    </para>
    <section id="exportsingle">
      <title>Exporting the currently opened Project</title>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            To export a single Project from the database, the Project
            you want to export must be open.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Export</emphasis>.
            </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Choose the location to save your Project, and the name you
            want to save it under.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The Project (including the test result summaries
            (<xref linkend="working-with-the-test-result-summary-view"/>)) will first be refreshed and then
            exported. It is saved as an .xml file.
          </para>
          <para>
            <para role="tip">When you export a single Project, only the
            currently opened version is exported.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="exportall">
      <title>Exporting all of the Projects from the database</title>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Export all</emphasis>.
            </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Choose or create a folder where you want the Projects to
            be stored.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The Projects (including the test result summaries
            (<xref linkend="working-with-the-test-result-summary-view"/>)) will be saved as .xml files.
            <para role="tip">When you export all Projects, all versions of each
            Project are exported.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="projectversion">
    <title>Versioning Projects</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="openProjectDialogContextId">Opening Projects</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="dialogProjectCreateNewVersionContextId">Versioning Projects</anchor>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To create a different version of a Project, select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Create new version</emphasis>.
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          An automatic suggestion for the next version number is
          provided.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can accept this version number or enter a different one.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>” to create the new version.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The new version of the Project becomes active in the client.
          <para role="tip">Any test result summaries for the Project are not
          duplicated in the new version. Tests that ran for previous
          versions of the Project are, however, still in the database
          to be used for long term analysis.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">You can also create a new version using the dbtool
      (<xref linkend="creating-new-versions"/>)</para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="tracking-changes-in-a-project">
    <title>Tracking changes in a Project</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="projectSettingsPageContextId">Project Properties</anchor>
    <para>
      In order to see when changes were made to a Test Case, Test
      Suite or Test Job in a Project, you can activate the change
      tracking option in the Project properties.
    </para>
    <para>
      When this option is activated, each Test Case, Test Suite and
      Test Job shows information on the timestamp of a change, and the
      type of change (created or modified). You can optionally enter a
      property which should be displayed alongside the change type to
      track e.g. the user that made the change. The changes that lead
      to change information being shown are:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The creation of a node.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Any time an editor is saved (renaming within an editor,
          adding Test Cases to an editor, removing Test Cases from an
          editor, adding data or component names, using the refactor
          actions from within an editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      Project-wide refactor actions, such as those started from the
      search result view, and any renaming in browsers, are not shown
      in the change information.
    </para>
    <section id="activating-change-tracking">
      <title>Activating change tracking</title>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Open the Project properties:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Properties</emphasis>
            </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select <emphasis>General</emphasis> from the tree on the
            left-hand side.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Activate <emphasis>Track changes</emphasis> to activate
            change tracking for this Project.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Choose whether you want to track a certain number of
            changes per node, or whether you want to keep changes for
            a specific time span. Enter the amount of changes or days.
            <para role="tip">The display for each node is updated on saving. If
            there are too many changes, or some changes are outside of
            the specified time span, they will be removed on saving.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can (optionally) enter a system or environment
            property that is displayed in the Properties View as
            additional information about the change (e.g. the user
            that made the change).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>
        When change tracking is activated, the Properties View for the
        original specification (not places of reuse) for Test Cases,
        Test Suites and Test Jobs displays information on the changes
        made (<xref linkend="TasksTrackChangesPropView"/>).
      </para>
      <figure id="TasksTrackChangesPropView">
        <title>Tracking Changes</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/ChangeTrackingPropView.png"/>
          </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>Tracking Changes</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        You can deactivate change tracking via the Project properties.
        To remove all current information about changes, use the
        <emphasis>delete</emphasis> option
        (<xref linkend="removing-change-tracking-information"/>).
      </para>
    </section>
    <section id="removing-change-tracking-information">
      <title>Removing change tracking information from a
      Project</title>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            To remove all information on all nodes about changes made, open the Project properties:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Properties</emphasis>
            </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select <emphasis>General</emphasis> from the tree on the
            left-hand side.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click the button ”<emphasis>Delete all tracked
            data</emphasis>” and confirm when asked.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            All data will be removed from the Project that were
            collected for the change tracking. <para role="warning">If a node is
            currently locked, then the data for this node will not be
            removed. You will see which nodes are affected in a
            dialog. We recommend deleting change tracking data when
            you are sure that no one else is using the Project.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</section>