<section id="launch-configurations" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                  xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Launch Configurations</title>
  <section id="intro">
    <title>Intro</title>
    <para>
      If you are using the the Eclipse Jubula Feature in your Eclipse
      installation, you can start AUTs from within Eclipse, similar to
      the way in which you would debug an application using Eclipse.
      This section describes how to start your AUT directly from the
      IDE.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="requirements">
    <title>Requirements</title>
    <para>
      The following Features need to be installed in order to start
      Swing AUTs:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Jubula Launch Support for Java / Swing
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Java Developer Tools (JDT)
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      The following Features need to be installed in order to start
      RCP AUTs:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Jubula Launch Support for Eclipse RCP
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Java Developer Tools (JDT)
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Eclipse Plug-in Development Environment (PDE)
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">You can find an update site containing the Jubula Feature
      and the Launch Integration in the correct version for each
      standalone version in the installation directory in the
      <emphasis>development</emphasis> folder.</para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="customizing-the-perspective">
    <title>Customizing the Perspective</title>
    <para>
      In most cases, the button to start AUTs is not included in the
      main toolbar. The following steps describe how to add this
      button to a Perspective’s toolbar:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Window</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Customize Perspective...</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          from the main menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the dialog that appears, select the <emphasis>Command
          Groups Availability</emphasis> tab.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Ensure that the entry <emphasis>Start AUT</emphasis> in the
          section <emphasis>Available command groups:</emphasis> is
          checked.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Close the dialog by pressing the <emphasis>OK</emphasis>
          button.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      Once you have completed the steps listed above, the
      <emphasis>Start AUT</emphasis> button <mediaobject role="icon" file="../images/startAUT.png"/> 
      should be visible in the main toolbar of the active Perspective.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="starting-the-aut-1">
    <title>Starting the AUT</title>
    <para>
      The <emphasis>Start AUT</emphasis> button <mediaobject role="icon" file="../images/startAUT.png"/>
       can be used, just like the <emphasis>Run</emphasis> or <emphasis>Debug</emphasis>
      buttons, to launch an application or configure application
      launches. Applications started in this way are always started in
      debug mode. Furthermore, <emphasis>Start AUT</emphasis> adds
      additional information to the launch process, allowing the
      started application to be tested.
    </para>
    <para>
      Some of the additional information that makes the started
      application testable can be configured from the
      <emphasis>Test</emphasis> tab of the <emphasis>Start AUT
      Configurations</emphasis> dialog.
    </para>
    <para>
      The <emphasis role="strong">AUT ID</emphasis> can be assigned or left blank. If left blank,
      the configuration name (ex. <emphasis>New_configuration</emphasis>) will be used.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="aut-agent">
    <title>AUT Agent</title>
    <para>
      Although the automatic AUT Agent selection generally selects the
      correct AUT Agent, it can be useful to know what criteria go
      into the selection process. These rules are followed when
      deciding with which AUT Agent the starting AUT should be
      registered:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If the ITE is currently connected to an AUT Agent, then that
          AUT Agent will be used.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If an embedded AUT Agent is running, the ITE will connect to
          the embedded AUT Agent and use that for AUT registration.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          An embedded AUT Agent will be started, and the connection
          will be made and used for AUT registration.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="additional-information-for-rcp-auts">
    <title>Additional information for RCP AUTs</title>
    <section id="keyboard-layout">
      <title>Keyboard Layout</title>
      <para>
        The Keyboard Layout for the AUT can be defined in the
        <emphasis>Start AUT Configurations</emphasis> dialog. The
        entered value must represent a locale and must represent a
        defined keyboard layout.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section id="rcp-remote-control-plug-in">
      <title>RCP Remote Control Plug-in</title>
      <para>
        In order to start an RCP AUT, the RCP Remote Control plug-in
        (org.eclipse.jubula.rc.rcp) must be included in the launch
        configuration. The list of plug-ins for the launch
        configuration can be viewed and modified from the
        <emphasis>Plug-ins</emphasis> tab of the <emphasis>Start AUT
        Configurations</emphasis> dialog when an <emphasis>Eclipse
        Application</emphasis> launch configuration is selected.
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="common-pitfalls">
    <title>Common Pitfalls</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Breakpoints may alter the timing of tests. This can have
          consequences such as timeouts, tests failing when they
          should succeed, and tests succeeding when they should fail.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Actions that affect the lifecycle of the AUT such as
          restarting it cannot be used in tests that use an AUT
          started via a launch configuration.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</section>