<section id="remote-debugging" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                             xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                             xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Remote Debugging</title>
  <para>
    You can remote debug an AUT by simply modifying or creating a
    AUT configuration. The following options must be added to
    your JRE Arguments:
  </para>
<programlisting>
-Xdebug 
-Xnoagent 
-Xrunjdwp:transport=dt_socket,server=y,suspend=y,address=4711 
-Djava.compiler=NONE 
</programlisting>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The ”suspend=y/n” option determines whether the JVM waits with
        the execution of the program until the debugger has connected
        itself or not.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The ”address=&lt;portNo&gt;” determines the port the debugger
        has to connect to.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <para role="tip">Not all JREs support the arguments listed above. If you are not using a Java Standard Edition JRE to start your AUT, you will likely not be able to use this method to remotely debug your AUT.</para>
  </para>
  <section id="configuring-eclipse-for-remote-debugging">
    <title>Configuring Eclipse for remote debugging</title>
    <para>
      Create a new <quote>Remote Java Application</quote> in the
      <quote>Launch configuration</quote> dialog and enter the
      hostname for the computer on which the AUT Agent is running.
      The specified port has to be the same which you used in the
      AUT configuration (e.g. 4711).
    </para>
    <para>
      To get your AUT running using remote debugging options you
      have to take the following steps:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Start the AUT Agent
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Connect the ITE with the AUT Agent, load the
          Project in the ITE and invoke the startup of the
          AUT in the ITE.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If ”suspend=y”, you now have to run your <quote>Remote Java
          Application</quote>-configuration in Eclipse, as the JVM is
          waiting for the debugger to connect before starting the
          application. As soon as you are connected you should see the
          default debug behaviour in your debug perspective of
          Eclipse.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Your AUT has now been launched with the ability to use
          remote debugging.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      If you wish to debug an RCP AUT which is launched with an
      executable file, you must pass these JRE arguments via the
      AUT arguments and ”-vmargs”. When using this option, make
      sure you overwrite all JRE options that are defined in the
      ”config.ini” of your RCP launcher.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>