<section id="information-on" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                           xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                           xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Information on Test Steps</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="capContextId">Test Steps</anchor>
  <para>
    Test Steps are the smallest unit in a test. They correspond to one
    action on one component.
  </para>
  <para>
    <para role="tip">Instead of creating Test Steps, we recommend using the
    library of Test Cases (<xref linkend="creating-tests-from-the-library-of-pre-defined-test-cases"/>). Each Test Case
    in the library contains one Test Step, with all the parameters
    already referenced. Using the library makes test creation much
    easier!</para>
  </para>
  <section id="specsteps">
    <title>Specifying Test Steps</title>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">You must have created a Test Case (<xref linkend="creating-test-cases"/>) in order to create Test Steps.</para>
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open the Test Case Editor by double-clicking on the
          Test Case you want to edit in the Test Case Browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Create a Test Step from the context-sensitive menu in the Test Case Editor:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menupath">Add</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menupath">New Test Step</emphasis>.
          </para>
          
          (This adds the Test Step after any other items in the Test Case Editor.)
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Alternatively, use the option in the context-sensitive menu
          to insert a Test Step. This inserts the new Test Step above
          the currently selected item.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The <emphasis>New Test Step</emphasis> (<xref linkend="newstep"/>) dialog will
          appear.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <figure id="newstep">
      <title>New Test Step Dialog</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/teststepdialog.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>New Test Step Dialog</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Filling in the Test Step dialog</emphasis><?linebreak?>
      <emphasis role="strong">Test Step name</emphasis>
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the <emphasis>Test Step Name</emphasis> field, enter a name for the
          Test Step. This name is just for recognition purposes, but
          should be easily identifiable at a later point.
        </para>
        <para>
          <emphasis role="strong">Component type</emphasis>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select the component you want to test from the combo box.
        </para>
        <para>
          <para role="tip">A component is an element of the user interface you can execute an action on, e.g. a button, a text field.</para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <emphasis role="strong">Component name</emphasis>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter a component name. This is your user-defined name that
          you will use to refer to this particular component. It will
          later be mapped to the real component in the AUT.
          Again, we suggest using conventions to name components.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you are entering component names, a combo box appears
          with a list of names you have already used.
        </para>
        <para>
          If any of the names are grayed out, this means they have
          been used for other component types and cannot be used for
          the currently selected component type.
        </para>
        <para>
          You can change, or <emphasis>reassign</emphasis> component names later
          when you reuse this Test Case. Doing this means that you can
          execute the same actions on different components in the
          interface. The section on the Component Names View
          (<xref linkend="entering-and-reassigning-component-names-in-the-component-names-view"/>) contains information on
          reassigning component names.
        </para>
        <para>
          <emphasis role="strong">Action</emphasis>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          From the combo box, choose the action you want to execute on
          this component.
          <para role="tip">Refer to the chapter on Components, Actions, and Parameters for information on components, the
          actions they support, and their parameters.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Test Step will appear as nested in the Test Case.
          <para role="tip">You can change the position of Test Steps using drag-and-drop.</para>
        </para>
        <para>
          You can see and edit the details of any selected Test Step
          in the Properties View.
        </para>
        <para>
          The next step is to add parameter values (data) for
          Test Steps in the Properties View (<xref linkend="working-with-data"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="editingsteps">
    <title>Editing Test Steps</title>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open the Test Case Editor by double-clicking the Test Case
          you want to edit in the Test Case Browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Single-click the Test Step you want to edit.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Properties View, you can:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              edit the Test Step name
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              add a comment
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              edit the component, component name and action for the
              Test Step
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              edit the parameter values for the Test Step
              (<xref linkend="working-with-data"/>)
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can also move the Test Step within the Test Case using
          drag-and-drop.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To delete the Test Step, select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Delete</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          from the context-sensitive menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">Select the component or action in the Properties View and
      press <emphasis role="input">»F1«</emphasis> to see
      context-sensitive help about this component or action from the
      reference manual.</para>
    </para>
  </section>
</section>