<section id="configure-prefs" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                            xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                            xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Preferences</title>
  <para>
    Open the preferences dialog (<xref linkend="gdprefs"/>) by selecting:
    
    <para>
      <emphasis role="menuPath">Window</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Preferences</emphasis>.
    </para>
  </para>
  <section id="test-preferences">
    <title>Test preferences</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="prefPageBasicContextId">Test Preferences</anchor>
    <figure id="gdprefs">
      <title>Preference Dialog</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/gdprefs.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Preference Dialog</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
      In the preferences dialog, select <emphasis>Test</emphasis> from
      the tree on the left hand side.
    </para>
    <para>
      From this page, you can configure your preferences for:
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Auto-scrolling and -expanding:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            When the checkbox is marked, the views and browsers
            automatically scroll in the direction you move the mouse
            when you are dragging and dropping. Trees will also be
            automatically expanded when you hover over them while
            dragging items.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Minimizing the ITE:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            When the checkbox is marked, the ITE is automatically
            minimized when test execution begins. This is useful if
            you are letting tests run on the same machine you are
            specifying on.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          AUT confirmation dialog:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            When the checkbox is marked, a dialog appears to check if
            you are sure when you click the ”<emphasis>stop
            AUT</emphasis>” button.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Original Test Case name:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            When the checkbox is activated, you can see the original
            name of a referenced Test Case in brackets behind a new
            name you enter for the Test Case. This can help you to see
            and search for Test Cases you have reused. 
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Test Step information:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            When this checkbox is activated, you see the details about
            the Test Step (the component name and type, and the
            action) in square brackets behind the Test Step name. If
            you do not want to see these details, you can deactivate
            this checkbox.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Show referenced children:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            When this option is not active, you can only see
            referenced parent Test Cases in the Test Case Browser. The
            referenced Test Cases contained in these Test Cases are
            not displayed. This action can be useful if you want to
            improve the speed of working with the ITE.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Project auto load:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            If you have selected a Project to be automatically loaded
            (<xref linkend="auto-loading-default-project"/>), then you can stop the
            auto-loading by deactivating the checkbox.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Delay for content assist in the Component Names View:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Enter the amount of time in milliseconds you want to wait
            after each character entry before displaying content
            assist in the Component Names View. Increase the delay to
            see the content assist less frequently. You can see the
            content assist at any time by pressing
            <emphasis role="input">»CTRL+SPACE«</emphasis>.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Switching to the Execution Perspective:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            When the test begins, the ITE can automatically change to
            the Execution Perspective. You can choose to always be
            asked, to always change, or to never change. 
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Data files location:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can specify a location where external data files (e.g.
            Excel files) are held, or use the workspace directory as
            the base location. <para role="tip">The advantage of using the
            workspace as a location for your data files is that you
            can view these in the navigator view directly in the ITE.
            Windows users can even open Excel files from the ITE using
            the In-Place editor.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
  <section id="aut-agent-preferences">
    <title>AUT Agent preferences</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="prefPageServerContextId">AUT Agent Preferences</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="autConfigPropDialogContextId">Adding/editing AUT configurations</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId">Configuring an AUT</anchor>
    <para>
      You can find the AUT Agent preference page under:
      
      <para>
        <emphasis>Test-AUT Agent</emphasis>
      </para>
      
      in the preferences dialog.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the AUT Agent preference page, you can add, edit and
          delete AUT Agents and port numbers.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The hostnames and port numbers you enter here are displayed
          in the drop-down list for the ”<emphasis>Connect to AUT
          Agent</emphasis>” button on the toolbar. You will be able to
          connect to these hostnames on these port numbers when you
          have started an AUT Agent on them
          (<xref linkend="start-aut-agent"/>). <para role="tip">The AUT Agent preference
          page can also be accessed from the AUT configuration dialog
          which you can open from the Project properties.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <figure>
      <title>AUT Agent Configuration Dialog</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/serverconfig.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>AUT Agent Configuration
        Dialog</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section id="embedded-aut-agent-preferences">
    <title>Embedded AUT Agent preferences</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="prefPageEmbeddedAgentContextId">Embedded AUT Preferences</anchor>
    <para>
      You can find the preference page for the embedded AUT Agent under:
      
      <para>
        <emphasis>Test-AUT Agent-Embedded AUT Agent</emphasis>
      </para>
      
      in the preferences dialog.
    </para>
    <para>
      On this page, you can enter the port number that the embedded
      AUT Agent (<xref linkend="connect-aut-agent"/>) should use when you connect
      to it (<xref linkend="connect-aut-agent"/>). The default is 60001.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="database-preferences">
    <title>database preferences</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="databaseConnectionConfigurationDialogContextId">Database connection preferences</anchor>
    <para>
      You can find the database connection preference page under:
      
      <para>
        <emphasis>Test-database Connections</emphasis>
      </para>
      
      in the preferences dialog.
    </para>
    <para>
      When you start the ITE for the first time, it is automatically
      configured to use an embedded database. If this is the only
      database configured, then the database login is performed
      automatically.
    </para>
    <para>
      In this preference page, you can configure other database
      connections for your productive database.
    </para>
    <para>
      <para role="warning">We do not recommend using the embedded database for
      productive use.</para>
    </para>
    <section id="adding-editing-and-removing-database-configurations">
      <title>Adding, editing and removing database
      configurations</title>
      <para>
        To add a new database:
      </para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            In the database Connections preference page, click
            ”<emphasis>Add</emphasis>”.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            In the dialog that appears, enter a meaningful
            configuration name.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select the type of database that this configuration is
            for. <para role="tip">The ITE is thoroughly tested with Oracle.
            PostGreSQL and MySQL have been successfully tried out, but
            we cannot guarantee their usage in productive
            environments.</para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Based on the database type you choose, you must enter more
            details about the database connection. Speak to your
            database administrator if you are unsure of the connection
            details.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>
        You can edit and delete database configurations using the
        buttons in the database Connections preference page.
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="editor-preferences">
    <title>Editor preferences</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="editorPrefPageContextId">Editor Preferences</anchor>
    <para>
      In the <emphasis>Test - Editors</emphasis> preferences, you can
      choose whether you want items (Test Cases and Test Steps) to be
      placed at the bottom of the tree or after the selected item when
      you use the <emphasis>add</emphasis> option.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="object-mapping-preferences">
    <title>Object mapping preferences</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="prefPageObjectMapContextId">Object Mapping Preferences</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="objectMapEditorContextId">Object Mapping</anchor>
    <figure>
      <title>Object Mapping Preference Dialog</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/objectmappingprefs.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Object Mapping Preference
        Dialog</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
      You can access the object mapping preferences from
      <emphasis>Test - Object Mapping</emphasis> in the preferences
      dialog.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select whether you want the ITE to display how many nodes
          are contained in each category in the Object Mapping Editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose which keystrokes or mouse buttons you want to use to
          collect components in the Object Mapping Mode.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">If your AUT does not accept keystrokes, set the object
      collection preference to a mouse button combined with a modifier
      key.</para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="observation-mode-preferences">
    <title>Observation mode preferences</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="prefPageObserveJavaContextId">Observation Mode Preferences</anchor>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">The observation mode can only be used for Java AUTs.</para>
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Start/stop check mode:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
             Choose which keystroke you want to use to start and stop
            the check mode when you are observing Test Cases in Java
            AUTs.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Check component:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Choose which keystroke you want to use to show the check
            dialog when you are in check mode. The check dialog lets
            you choose what property of the selected component you
            want to check.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Show console:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The console provides information on the actions that have
            been observed. This is especially useful if your AUT is
            running on a different machine to your client. 
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Trigger for replace text:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Replace text actions are observed when the focus moves
            from the text component to another component. Depending on
            your application, this may not happen automatically in
            some situations. Enter triggers here which you can use to
            signify that you wish to observe a replace text action,
            even if the focus does not move from the text component. 
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <figure>
      <title>Observation Mode Preference Dialog</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/obsprefsjava.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Observation Mode Preference
        Dialog</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section id="test-result-preferences">
    <title>Test result preferences</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="prefPageTestResultContextId">Test Result Preferences</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testResultSummaryViewContextId">Test Result Summary View</anchor>
    <para>
      You can open the test result preference page by selecting
      <emphasis>Test - Test Results</emphasis> from the preference
      dialog.
    </para>
    <figure>
      <title>Test Result Preference Dialog</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/testresultprefs.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Test Result Preference
        Dialog</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose whether you want the Test Result View to open when
          testing begins.
        </para>
        <para>
          The Test Result View follows the test execution and shows
          which Test Steps were successful and which failed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose whether you want to track the test execution progress
          in the Test Result View. When this option is activated, the
          Test Result View scrolls to follow the test progress.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose whether you want to automatically create a screenshot
          when a test encounters an error. Screenshots are
          automatically saved in the database and can be viewed using
          the Image View when you select the failed Test Step in the
          Test Result View. <para role="warning">Screenshots are only taken of the
          primary monitor. Multiple monitors are not supported for
          screenshots.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose whether you want to create HTML and XML reports for
          each execution. When you activate this choice, decide
          whether you want full reports or just the errors to be
          shown. Enter a directory for the reports.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter the amount of days that test result summaries should
          be displayed for. This gives you a better overview of the
          most recent results in the Test Result Summary View.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="importing-and-exporting-database-preferences">
    <title>Importing and exporting database preferences</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="databaseConnectionConfigurationDialogContextId">Database connection preferences</anchor>
    <para>
      You can export and import your database preferences for the ITE.
      This makes migrating to new versions easier, as you do not have
      to reenter any database preferences.
    </para>
    <para>
      To export your database preferences:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">File</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Export</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          from the main menu in the ITE.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the dialog that appears, select:
          <emphasis>General/Preferences</emphasis> and click
          ”<emphasis>Next</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select the <emphasis>Database Connections</emphasis> option
          and browse to a place in the file system where you want the
          preferences to be saved.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click ”<emphasis>Finish</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      To import your database preferences:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">File</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Import</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          from the main menu in the ITE.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the dialog that appears, select:
          <emphasis>General/Preferences</emphasis> and click
          ”<emphasis>Next</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Browse to the preference file you wish to import.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select the <emphasis>Database Connections</emphasis> option
          and click ”<emphasis>Finish</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="label-decoration-preferences">
    <title>Label decoration preferences</title>
    <para>
      You can open the label decoration preferences by selecting
      <emphasis>General - Appearance - Label Decorations</emphasis>
      from the preference dialog.
    </para>
    <para>
      From this preference page, you can alter your preferences for:
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Completeness Check Decorator:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
             We recommend leaving this decorator active, as it shows
            you red crosses and tooltips in the Test Suite Browser
            when Test Suites and Test Jobs are incomplete.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Test Result Duration Decorator:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Deactivate this option to not see the execution time
            required for each node in the Test Result View. The times
            shown are for the execution of each node, including its
            children. You can use this information to see whether
            specific Test Cases are taking longer than you expect them
            to.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>
          Test Result Parameter Decorator:
        </term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Deactivate this option to not see the parameter values
            used at this node (i.e. either entered at this level, or
            actually used at this place) in the Test Result View. You
            can use this information to easily see which data were
            used for your Test Cases, without having to click through
            each individual node in the Test Result View. This can be
            especially useful if you have one Test Case that runs
            multiple times with different datasets. 
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
  <section id="workspace-prefs">
    <title>Workspace preferences</title>
    <para>
      You can find the workspace preferences under:
      
      <para>
        <emphasis>General/Startup and Shutdown/Workspaces</emphasis>
      </para>
      
      in the preferences dialog (<xref linkend="WorkspacePrefs"/>).
    </para>
    <para>
      Here, you can specify whether or not to see the workspace prompt
      when starting the ITE.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can also configure how many workspaces to see in your recent
      workspaces list, and remove any you no longer wish to see.
    </para>
    <figure id="WorkspacePrefs">
      <title>Workspace Preferences</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/workspaceprefs.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Workspace
        Preferences</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section id="generalkeys-preferences">
    <title>General/Keys preferences</title>
    <para>
      In the <emphasis>General</emphasis> preferences, you can select
      the <emphasis>Keys</emphasis> option to be able to edit the key
      binding for shortcuts in the ITE. Here, you can create your own
      shortcuts or alter the current shortcuts.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="help-preferences">
    <title>Help preferences</title>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose whether you want to have help displayed in an
          external browser. This lets you see more information at
          once.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          For context-sensitive help for windows and dialogs, choose
          how you want the help to appear.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose how many search results should be shown when
          searching through the help system.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
</section>