<section id="working-with-suites" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Working with Test Suites</title>
  <section id="creating-a-test-suite">
    <title>Creating a Test Suite</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testExecViewContextId">Test Suite Browser</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="dialogTestsuiteNewContextId">New Test Suite Dialog</anchor>
    <para>
      Test Suites are used to organize and prepare Test Cases to be
      executed.
    </para>
    <para>
      To create a Test Suite, the Test Suite Browser must be visible. If it is not visible, change to the Specification Perspective and select:
      
      <para>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Window</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Show View</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Test Suite Browser</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">New</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">New Test Suite</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          from the context-sensitive menu in the Test Suite Browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Name the new Test Suite when prompted with a meaningful
          name. It is a good idea to have naming conventions for Test
          Suites.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Test Suite you created will appear in the Test Suite
          Browser under the category <emphasis>Test Suites</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Once you have created a Test Suite, you can:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Add Test Cases to it to be executed
              (<xref linkend="adding-items-to-editors"/>).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Configure the Test Suite in the Properties View
              (<xref linkend="configuring-test-suites-in-the-properties-view"/>).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Rename the Test Suite (<xref linkend="renaming-items-in-browsers"/>).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Delete Test Cases from it (<xref linkend="deleting-items-from-editors"/>).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Add the Test Suite to a Test Job to be executed along
              with other Test Suites (<xref linkend="working-with-jobs"/>).
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>
          <para role="tip">You can filter in the Test Suite Browser using the
          field at the top. Use star <emphasis role="input">*</emphasis> as a wild
          card.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">You can combine multiple Test Suites to create a Test Job
      (<xref linkend="working-with-jobs"/>). This is useful for testing
      multiple AUTs (or instances of the same AUT in one test.)</para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="configuring-test-suites-in-the-properties-view">
    <title>Configuring Test Suites in the Properties View</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerPropertiesViewContextId">Properties View</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testSuiteEditorContextId">Test Suite Editor</anchor>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="testExecViewContextId">Test Suite Browser</anchor>
    <para>
      To configure a Test Suite, you must first create one
      (<xref linkend="creating-a-test-suite"/>).
    </para>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">If you are editing the Test Suite, the working language
      (which is specified via the globe button on the toolbar) must be
      set to a language supported by the chosen AUT for the Test
      Suite. Otherwise the Test Suite will be uneditable. </para>
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open the Test Suite Editor by double-clicking on the Test
          Suite you want to configure.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Properties View, you can:
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Change the Test Suite name by entering a new name in the
              <emphasis>Test Suite name</emphasis> field.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Add a comment to the Test Suite
              (<xref linkend="adding-comments-to-items-in-editors"/>).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Enter a value in the <emphasis>step delay</emphasis>
              field.
            </para>
            <para>
              <para role="tip">The step delay is the time left between each Test
              Step during test execution. The default is 0
              milliseconds (<xref linkend="altering-the-speed-of-test-execution"/>).</para>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Select the AUT for this Test Suite. To be able to select
              an AUT (and object map, and execute your test) you must
              have added at least one AUT to the Project
              (<xref linkend="define-aut"/>).
            </para>
            <para>
              <para role="tip">You don’t have to choose an AUT for a Test Suite
              as soon as you have created it, but you will have to
              choose one before object mapping, for example.</para>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Choose a default reentry type for each of the four error
              types from the combo-boxes.
            </para>
            <para>
              Event Handlers are Test Cases used to deal with errors
              during test execution. When an error occurs, the current
              Test Case is searched for an Event Handler for that
              error type. If none is found, the parent Test Case is
              searched, and so on. If no Event Handler for the test is
              found, then a default Event Handler (specified in the
              Test Suite properties)is activated.
            </para>
            <para>
              As a general rule, you should avoid default Event
              Handlers being executed. See the sections on Event
              Handlers for information on the event types
              (<xref linkend="event-types"/>), reentry types (<xref linkend="reentry-types"/>) and
              creating your own Event Handlers.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Save the changes in the Test Suite Editor.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
</section>