<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="tips-and-tricks-observation-mode" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                             xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                             xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Tips and tricks for using the observation mode</title>
  <para>
    We have designed the observation mode to help you get started
    with your tests and to help you understand what sort of user
    actions correspond to actions in the library.
  </para>
  <para>
    The ITE is first and foremost a keyword-driven tool, and the
    library of Test Cases installed means that you have various
    benefits over simple recording:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can create tests without needing the AUT - you don’t
        have to wait for each version of the AUT to begin test
        specification.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Your tests aren’t so dependent on the actual implementation
        of the AUT, so they can be a lot more general in terms of
        data, component implementations etc. and therefore a lot
        more robust and maintainable.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Using keywords encourages you to think about your test
        structure a lot more, which also helps maintenance later.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    Nevertheless, we understand that you may want to observe some
    Test Cases. Here are some tips that might help you:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Think about your test structure at the beginning: what
        modules will you want to reuse? Start by observing small
        Test Cases, e.g. a Test Case to login, a Test Case to open a
        dialog etc.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Check while you are observing that the actions you carry out
        are observed in the way you meant.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Supplement your observed Test Cases with other Test Cases
        from the library of Test Cases installed.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Refactor as you go! If you have recorded a Test Case with
        specific data, but you will want to use it for any type of
        data, then add a reference for the data.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>