<section xml:id="known-issues-and-other-information-8.1" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                   xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                   xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>Known issues and other information</title>
  <para>
   <emphasis role="strong">We are "retiring" the name GUIdancer</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
  	<listitem>
  	<para>
  	To reduce confusion when working with the standalone versions, we will be retiring the
  	name GUIdancer in the coming releases. 
  	</para>
  	<para>
  	This reflects the situation that the Jubula and GUIdancer standalones have been 
  	functionally identical for over a year and only differ in their branding.
  	</para>
  	</listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Support for Java 8 as a runtime
    environment</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We now run our regression tests for RCP and Swing AUTs on all platforms
        with Java 8 as a runtime environment.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Support for iOS 6 dropped</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We no longer support iOS 6 for testing. The iOS support is now
        for 7 applications.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Relevance now a property of Test
    Suites</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Whether or not a test run is relevant is now determined by a
        property on each Test Suite. This better reflects the
        situation that specific Test Suites will always be relevant
        and others never.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The meaning of relevance has not changed. However, the entry
        from the preferences has been removed and the parameter for
        the testexec is no longer accepted.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        All Test Suites in newly imported Projects are automatically
        set to true for relevance.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Newly created Test Suites are created as being relevant.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Dashboard URL has been changed</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The dashboard URL has been changed to:
      </para>
      <programlisting>
      http://HOSTNAME:SERVERPORT/testresults/dashboard
      </programlisting>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
  	<emphasis role="strong">Updated JRE in the Windows and Linux installers</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
  	<listitem>
  		<para>
  		The Windows and Linux installers now use JRE 1.7.0_72. The ITE is executed with this
  		version on Windows and Linux.
  		</para>
  	</listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Tree view removed from object mapping editor</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We have removed the tree view from the object mapping editor and 
        improved the layout of the split view and added a filter for assigned names
        to replace the functionality in the tree view.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Incompatible and recommended changes regarding custom toolkit extensions</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        There has been a minor but incompatible change in the <programlisting>org.eclipse.jubula.toolkit.common.IToolkitProvider</programlisting> interface regarding the name 
        of the interface itself (lower k instead of upper K) as well as a method renaming: <programlisting>public ResourceBundle getI18nResourceBundle();</programlisting> is now 
        <programlisting>public ResourceBundle getResourceBundle();</programlisting>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        With addressing <link xl:href="http://eclip.se/454545" /> we've adjusted our recommended namespace for custom toolkit remote control extensions.
        Though this change is backwards compatible and using the old namespace for AdapterFactories, adapter and tester classes will still work we do strongly
        recommend to re-locate those custom written remote control classes. 
        Use e.g. the <emphasis role="strong">org.eclipse.jubula.ext.*</emphasis> namespace to avoid collisions with signed classes of the ITE in the future.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>With the provisioning of an API for all toolkits we've altered the <programlisting>Bundle-SymbolicName</programlisting> of all of our toolkit provider.
      As this should not affect any custom written ITE toolkit extension (as no explicit bundle dependency to our bundles is necessary) you can easily adjust your bundle 
      dependencies by replacing the old ID <programlisting>org.eclipse.jubula.toolkit.provider.&lt;toolkitName&gt;</programlisting> with the new 
      one <programlisting>org.eclipse.jubula.toolkit.&lt;toolkitName&gt;.provider</programlisting>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>