<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2016 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
  
  Contributors:
      BREDEX GmbH - initial API and implementation and/or initial documentation
-->
<section xml:id="new-features-and-developments-8.4.0" version="5.0"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <title>New Features and Developments</title>
<para>
 <emphasis role="strong">Invoke External Method</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
    <para>
      It is now possible to invoke external (AUT - independent) methods through the Reflection component.
      The external JAR files must be placed in the directory <emphasis>&lt;installation-directory&gt;/ite/externaljars</emphasis>.
    </para>
    <para>
      We introduced new nodes altering the test execution flow: Conditional Statements and Loops.
    </para>
    <para>
      Component name types are calculated and treated differently from this release onwards.
      The type becomes only decorative, so actions resulting in invalid component name types
      are allowed from now on, however, the user is warned before any action resulting in an
      invalid type. Component names with invalid type are decorated by error markers, just like
      component names which are mapped into a component which does not realize one of the
      actions which might be executed on the component name.
    </para>
    <para>
      A new feature is added to the Component Name Browser: it is now possible to display the usage counter
      for component names. This shows the number of places in the current project where the component name is
      used. Users can turn this feature on and off in the <emphasis>Test - Editors</emphasis> preference window.
    </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
 <emphasis role="strong">Check actions with timeout parameter</emphasis>
</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
 <para>
  Most of the check actions do now have a timeout parameter. If there is a
  timeout value greater than 0 the check action is checking
  multiple times if the wanted status has occurred. If this did not
  happen until the timeout is reached the check is marked as check
  failed.
 </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>
