<section id="release-notes-for-version-4.1" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                          xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                          xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>Release Notes for version 4.1.01039</title>
  <section id="new-features-and-developments-4.1">
    <title>New features and developments</title>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">New option in delete Project
      dialog</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you delete a Project, you can now decide whether you want
          to keep the test results for the Project or delete them as
          well.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Performance improvements</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          We have further improved the performance for the saving and
          loading of Projects. The validation of Test Suites now runs as
          a background job so that test specification can continue while
          the tests are being validated.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Test Suites must be validated before they can be executed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Generated names penalty removed</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The generated names penalty has been removed from the object
          mapping configuration area and from the object recognition
          calculation.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Optional automatic screenshots when errors
      occur</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can now define whether or not screenshots should
          automatically be taken when an error occurs.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Screenshots taken in this manner are saved into the database
          and can be viewed in the Image View by clicking on the failed
          Test Step.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can alter this preference in the Test Result preference
          page.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the command line client, screenshots are automatically
          taken unless you include the parameter <emphasis role="input">-s</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">New relevance flag for test
      results</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can now specify at the beginning of each test execution
          whether the test results are relevant for your test reports.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can alter this preference in the Test Results preference
          page.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the command line client, test executions are automatically
          relevant unless you include the parameter <emphasis role="input">-r</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">MAC OSX no longer in BETA</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          We have now removed the BETA status of our MAC support.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Please be aware that pure SWT tests are not supported on MAC
          systems.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Testing RCP AUTs also has some limitations on MAC, e.g. the
          action to select a value from a combo box does not work, and
          there are problems with the selection of tabs by their values.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The license server will now run on MAC machines, as long as
          the development kit for the environment is installed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="other-information-4.1">
    <title>Other information</title>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Compatibility with 4.0</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The database is compatible with version 4.0, so your 4.0
          database can continue to be used with 4.1.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The server and client components have been changed, so these
          will need to be reinstalled for 4.1.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          There have been no changes to the license mechnism or license
          administrator - you do not need to reinstall your license
          server.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Eclipse plugin removed</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The functionality to run the ITE as an Eclipse plugin has been
          removed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">HTML actions deprecated</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The action <emphasis>follow link</emphasis> in HTML is
          deprecated. Use the action <emphasis>click</emphasis> on
          <emphasis>Graphics Component</emphasis> instead to follow
          links.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The action <emphasis>select window</emphasis> is also
          deprecated, and has not yet been replaced with a new action in
          this release.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">New database configurations in DB
      Configuration</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          We have added separate database configurations in the DB
          Configuration Tool for Oracle 8,9 and 10 as well as the
          embedded database and Oracle XE.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          There are also two new options: MySQl and Postgresql. These
          are shown as unsupported: we have tested that the ITE can
          connect to them and open Projects, but do not let our full
          tests run on them at this time.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">New colors for Test Cases</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The unbound modules are now colored blue to make them easier
          to distinguish from other Test Cases.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          We have also made Test Cases that cannot be directly edited
          slightly grayer to make it easier to see which Test Cases are
          editable.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="known-issues-4.1">
    <title>Known issues</title>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Console output for DBTool</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The DBTool does not yet produce an output when parameters are
          false or when errors occur.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Edit parameters dialog</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When editing parameters via the edit parameters dialog, it is
          currently necessary to save the Test Case and reopen it to see
          the changes in the Properties View.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Merging component names in the Object
      Mapping Editor</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          At the moment, the merging of component names does not work in
          the Object Mapping Editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can use the Component Names Browser to merge component
          names instead.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</section>