<section id="release-notes-for-version-4.2" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                          xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                          xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>Release Notes for version 4.2.01053</title>
  <section id="new-features-and-developments-4.2">
    <title>New features and developments</title>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Eclipse 3.6 supported</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Tests can be written for Eclipse applications that are written
          in 3.6
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Viewing test results</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Full test result details that are still in the database can
          now be opened in the Test Result View from the Test Result
          Summary View.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          This lets you review tests that ran overnight directly in the
          ITE.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Automatic database migration</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The ITE now contains a database migration wizard.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When a connection to a database is made in a new version, the
          ITE automatically recognizes whether the database version is
          incompatile.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If so, you can start the migration wizard. You specify which
          Projects should be imported into the new database (the
          Projects must have been exported from the previous version).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The migration wizard converts the database automatically to
          the new version.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Commenting out Test Cases</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can now comment out Test Cases and Test Steps in editors.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Items that have been commented out are inactive and are
          neither validated for Test Suite completeness, nor executed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">New parameters for table
      actions</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Actions on tables now have new parameters for <emphasis>row
          operator</emphasis> and <emphasis>column operator</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can now select rows and columns based on their title and
          also determine how you want the selection to occur (equals,
          matches, simple match, not equals).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">New parameter for select
      actions</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Actions that select items from tables, lists and trees have a
          new parameter for <emphasis>mouse button</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can now define which mouse button should be used to select
          the item.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Number of failed Test Steps
      shown</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Test Result Summary View now also has the information
          about how many Test Steps failed in a test run.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Information about whether test result
      details are available</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The Test Result Summary View now also has the information
          about whether the details for a test run are still in the
          database.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If the results are still available, then the Test Result View
          can be reopened.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Spring to next/previous error</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Test Result View which opens when you open the results
          for a test run from the Test Result Summary View, you can use
          two new toolbar buttons to spring to the next/previous error.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Showing comments for Test Cases</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Any comments you write on Test Cases are now visible as a
          tooltip when you hover over the Test Case in the browsers or
          in the search result view.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Pause on error</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          There is a new button on the toolbar to pause the test
          execution if an error occurs.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          This can be switched on and off during a test run and allows
          you to easily stop the test to see what went wrong.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The test can be continued by clicking the <emphasis>pause test
          execution</emphasis> button on the toolbar.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Using running AUT details to define an
      AUT</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          AUTs that have been started using the
          <emphasis>gdrun</emphasis> command can now be automatically
          defined in the ITE.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can select the option to create an AUT definition from the
          running AUTs view for any AUT that is currently unknown.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Show referenced children</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          There is a new option in the preferences to show referenced
          children in Test Cases in the Test Case Browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          This preference is activated by default.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Deactivating the preference means that any children of
          referenced Test Cases are not displayed in the Test Case
          Browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          This can help in particularly large Projects to inprove
          performance.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">New action</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          There is a new action to wait for the menu component.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="other-information-4.2">
    <title>Other information</title>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">XML and HTML reports scheduled for
      removal</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The XML and HTML reports that can be generated by the ITE
          (configurable in the preferences) are scheduled for removal in
          the next versions.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          There will be an alternative feature to create a HTML report
          from the test result report, as long as the test details are
          still in the database.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          For queries about this plan, please contact the support team.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Deprecated unbound modules earlier than
      3.0 scheduled for removal</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The unbound modules that have been deprecated in versions
          earlier than 3.0 are also scheduled for removal in the
          upcoming version.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          We always recommend updating to the latest version of the
          unbound modules and removing any references to deprecated
          modules in your tests.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">New unbound modules for tables and for
      select actions on lists, trees and tree-tables</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Because we have added new parameters to actions on these
          components, there are new unbound modules for the actions.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The old unbound modules have been set to deprecated.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          We recommend updating any deprecated modules in your tests
          with the new modules.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can see what the new module is by looking in the
          deprecated module - these now contain the new actions.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Merging in the Object Mapping
      Editor</emphasis>
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The option to merge components in the Object Mapping Editor
          has been temporarily deactivated for this release.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</section>