<section id="creating-an-accessibility-plug-in" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                              xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>Creating an accessibility plug-in</title>
  <section id="setting-up-your-workspace">
    <title>Setting up your Workspace</title>
    <para>
      Although you can use the IDE of your choice to develop your
      accessibility plug-in, this guide will use Eclipse with PDE
      plug-ins.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Once you have created your new workspace, change that
          workspace’s <emphasis role="strong">Target
          Platform</emphasis> by using the description mentioned in
          the extension manual, as well as all plug-ins that make up
          your AUT.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Create a new <emphasis role="strong">Plug-in
          Project</emphasis>. The default values proposed by the
          wizard are acceptable, so simply enter a name for your new
          accessibility project and complete the wizard without
          additional modifications.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You now have a workspace with a properly configured target
          platform as well as a new plug-in project. You can now begin
          developing your GEF toolkit extension.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="walkthrough">
    <title>Walkthrough</title>
    <para>
      The first step for implementing your accessibility plug-in is to
      create identifiers for each type of GEF component that you wish
      to make accessible for tests. An identifier is a Java class that
      implements <emphasis role="input">IEditPartIdentifier</emphasis> from the package
      named
      <emphasis>org.eclipse.jubula.rc.rcp.e3.gef.identifier</emphasis>
      and provides additional and/or more precise information about a
      specific <emphasis role="input">EditPart</emphasis> from the package named
      <emphasis>org.eclipse.gef</emphasis>. The granularity of your
      identifier classes will depend on the class hierarchy of the
      edit parts in the AUT. For example, if many of the edit parts
      share a common superclass, then you can write a single
      Identifier for that superclass that will be able to provide
      accessibility for all edit parts that inherit from that
      superclass. See the example in <xref linkend="gefreference"/>, which
      shows a sample implementation.
    </para>
    <para>
      The next step is to create an adapter factory. This extension
      provides information regarding which identifier to use for each
      edit part.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open the <emphasis role="input">plugin.xml</emphasis> file from your
          accessibility plug-in and select the
          <emphasis role="strong">Extension</emphasis> tab.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Add an instance of the
          <emphasis>org.eclipse.core.runtime.adapters</emphasis>
          extension.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Add a <emphasis role="strong">factory</emphasis> to the new
          extension for each type of GEF component for which you wish
          to provide accessibility. Each factory must implement
          <emphasis role="input">IEditPartIdentifier</emphasis> from the package named
          <emphasis>org.eclipse.jubula.rc.rcp.e3.gef.identifier</emphasis>
          to provide adapters from the GEF component that implements
          <emphasis role="input">EditPart</emphasis> from
          <emphasis>org.eclipse.gef</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Once you have defined your adapter factory, you will need to
          implement it. Your adapter factory, which must implement
          <emphasis role="input">IAdapaterFactory</emphasis> from the package named
          <emphasis>org.eclipse.core.runtime</emphasis>, provides
          appropriate instances of your created identifiers for a
          given edit part. See <xref linkend="gefreference"/> for a sample
          implementation.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Once you have created your identifiers<?linebreak?> and adapter
          factories, you can export and deploy your plug-in to use it
          in your AUT.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          When starting your AUT after adding
          or replacing your accessibility plug-in, it is recommended
          that the AUT starts with the <emphasis role="input">-clean</emphasis>
          parameter.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
</section>