<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="overwriting-data-for-test-cases-and-test-suites" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                            xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                            xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Overwriting data for Test Cases and Test Suites</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="guidancerPropertiesViewContextId">Properties View</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="guidancerSpecTestCaseEditorContextId">Test Case Editor</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="guidancerExecTestCaseEditorContextId">Test Suite Editor</anchor>
  <para>
    When you reuse Test Cases, you reuse them with any concrete
    values they contain, and with any default values that you have
    entered for their referenced parameters.
  </para>
  <para>
    Data which has been entered for referenced parameters can be
    overwritten when you reuse a Test Case.
  </para>
  <para>
    Reusing Test Cases happens in two ways:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        by adding the Test Case to another Test Case
        (<xref linkend="adding-items-to-editors"/>). The Test Case is then
        <emphasis>nested in the Test Case</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        by adding the Test Case to a Test Suite
        (<xref linkend="adding-items-to-editors"/>). The Test Case is then
        <emphasis>nested in the Test Suite</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Single-click the reused Test Case in the editor for the Test
        Case or Test Suite where you have reused it.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the Properties View, you can see the parameters you
        referenced from in this Test Case. The data source for this
        Test Case is shown as <emphasis>referenced Test
        Case</emphasis> to denote that the data have not been
        changed after reusing the Test Case.
      </para>
      <para role="tip">
        A grey diamond next to the <emphasis>parameter
        value</emphasis> field means that the values in it were
        entered in the original specification of the Test Case.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can enter parameter values here or reference the
        parameters again. They would then become parameters of the
        <emphasis>parent</emphasis> Test Case.
      </para>
      <para role="tip">
        If you enter values here, you can see a yellow
        diamond next to the <emphasis>parameter value</emphasis>
        field. This means that the original data have been
        overwritten. The data source changes to <emphasis>local Test
        Case</emphasis>
      </para>
      <para>
        If you add references here, you will be able to enter or
        overwrite data when you reuse the parent Test Case.
      </para>
      <para role="tip">
        Once you change the parameter values of a reused Test
        Case, any changes to the parameters in the original
        specification of that Test Case will not affect your new
        values. You can reset any local changes to the data of the
        Test Case by removing all Excel files or Central Test Data
        Sets and then selecting <emphasis>Referenced Test
        Case</emphasis> from the data source combo box.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
</section>