<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="using-an-excel-file-as-an-external-data-source" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                           xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                           xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Using an Excel file as an external data source</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="guidancerPropertiesViewContextId" xml:id="using-an-excel-file-as-an-external-data-source.guidancerPropertiesViewContextId" xreflabel="Properties View"/>
  <para>
    In the Properties View, you can add Excel files as a data source to
    Test Cases which contain parameters referenced from the
    Test Cases or Test Steps they contain.
  </para>
  <para role="warning">
    The addition of data via Excel is discouraged, because any problems with the data can only be found once the test is running. We recommend using the central test data sets in the ITE to manage data within the Project (<xref linkend="using-central-data-sets"/>).
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Navigate to the Properties View for the Test Case you want to
        add the Excel file to.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Enter the path to the Excel file in the
        <emphasis>Excel data file</emphasis> field.
      </para>
      <para>
        The path to the Excel file can be absolute or relative (if
        you have specified a data files path (<xref linkend="gdprefs"/>)).
      </para>
      <para role="tip">
        The Excel file must be configured in a specific way in order it to be read (<xref linkend="configuring-the-excel-file"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you reuse this Test Case, the Excel file you enter will
        be reused along with the Test Case. When you reuse the
        Test Case, you can choose whether you leave this file or
        change it for another one.
      </para>
      <para role="tip">
        If you store your Excel files in your workspace, you will be able to open these directly in the ITE from the navigator view using the in-place editor.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        A Test Case with an Excel file as data is marked with a
        small Excel icon in the browsers to help you find it more
        easily later.
      </para>
      <para role="warning">
        Please note that the Excel file is read at the start of the test execution. Any changes to the file after this will not affect the test data. For information on using the date function in Excel, see the section later <xref linkend="using-the-today-function-in-excel"/>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <section xml:id="configuring-the-excel-file">
    <title>Configuring the Excel file</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The worksheet in Excel must be named with the language
          code for the language your data are in.
        </para>
        <para>
          For example, if the data of your first sheet are for
          French, then name the first sheet: <emphasis role="input">fr_FR</emphasis>
          (<xref linkend="excel"/>).
        </para>
        <figure xml:id="excel">
          <title>Example Excel Table</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/excelexample.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>Example Excel
            Table</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
          You can create sheets for every language you need. Make
          sure that each sheet is named with the language code. The
          ITE reads the sheet which corresponds to the working
          language when the test is being executed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Name the top cell of each column with a parameter name
          from your Test Case.
        </para>
        <para>
          For example, if you entered the reference
          ”<emphasis>=VALUE1</emphasis>”, then you must enter <emphasis role="input">VALUE1</emphasis>
          in the top cell of the column which will contain data for
          that parameter.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          Values are case sensitive.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Make sure that all the parameters for your Test Case have
          a column.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Do not leave any gaps in the table.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You must have an entry for each parameter used in the
          Test Case.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can then fill in the values or formulae you want to
          use for these parameters. Each row in the table represents
          one set of data for the parameters used.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          We recommend that you format cells as text <emphasis>before</emphasis> adding the test data. This ensures that Excel's number formatting won't modify the test data in unexpected and undesirable ways. Especially for the boolean values <emphasis>true</emphasis> and <emphasis>false</emphasis>, make sure you format the column as text.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If your Excel table contains data which change from
          day-to-day, then make sure you open the file before
          starting your test. Otherwise, the data from the
          last-opened state will be used.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          If you store your Excel files in your workspace, you will be able to open these directly in the ITE from the navigator view using the in-place editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          See the section later on using the <emphasis>today</emphasis> function
          in Excel to get the current date (<xref linkend="using-the-today-function-in-excel"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Excel files may not contain autofilters in any of the
          worksheets to be used as data sources. Remove any filters
          from all your Excel sheets before running a test.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="using-the-today-function-in-excel">
    <title>Using the =TODAY() function in Excel</title>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Because Excel stores the ”<emphasis>=today()</emphasis>” function as
          a six-digit number, you must use a particular process to
          use this function to check a date as part of a test.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter the function <emphasis role="input">=today()</emphasis> in a a different
          sheet to the one you are using for your data sets. You can
          enter it in the same sheet if you want to, but make sure
          that it has its own column. It must not be in one of the
          columns you will use as a data set.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          For example, your =today() function is in sheet one, cell
          G4.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You want your date to appear as dd.mm.yyyy.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the column for your data set, enter the following
          formula:
        </para>
        <blockquote>
          <para>
            =text(Sheet1!G4, ”dd.mm.yyyy”)
          </para>
        </blockquote>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          This will mean that the date will be treated as it appears
          with Excel.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          If you are using the =today() function, don't forget to open the Excel file before  starting your test. Otherwise, the data from the last-opened state will be used.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          If you store your Excel files in your workspace, you will be able to open these directly in the ITE from the navigator view using the in-place editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
</section>