<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section id="working-on-tasks-in-the-ite-contexts" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                 xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Working on tasks in the ITE: contexts</title>
  <para>
    Once you have configured a task repository for your workspace
    (<xref linkend="configuring-task-repositories"/>), you can work on tasks from
    that repository.
  </para>
  <section id="opening-and-editing-tasks-in-the-ite">
    <title>Opening and editing tasks in the ITE</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To be able to see tasks in a repository, select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Window</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Show View</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Other</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          from the menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the <emphasis>Mylyn</emphasis> section, select
          <emphasis>Task List</emphasis> and click
          ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”. The <emphasis>Task
          List</emphasis> View will appear.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Double-click on a task to open this task in the editor
          area.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Once a task is open, you can work on it as you would in an
          external system – add comments, change status etc.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="activate-task">
    <title>Working on tasks in the ITE</title>
    <para>
      Mylyn supports context- or task-based working. When you work
      on a task, you only see items relevant to that task, so that
      coming back to the task later involves less context-switching.
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Mylyn supports context-based working. You can work on
          existing tasks in a configured repository, or you can
          create tasks to work on.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          To work on a task, you must <emphasis>activate</emphasis> it. To activate a task, select the task in the <emphasis>Task List</emphasis> and select:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Activate</emphasis>
          </para>
          
          from the context-sensitive menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you activate a task for the first time, the browsers
          and editors will seem very empty. This is because nothing
          is yet a part of the context for this task.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can navigate through the browsers by pressing
          <emphasis role="input">»Alt+Click«</emphasis> to expand each
          level, or you can press the <emphasis>Focus on
          task</emphasis> button in the browsers to show the whole
          tree (not focusing on the task), or just the items in the
          current context (focusing on the task).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Items are automatically added to your context when you
          select them in a browser, when you open them in an editor,
          or when you perform other actions that cause them to be
          made relevant (e.g. Test Case creation, showing a Test
          Case specification etc.). Items that are used particularly
          frequently are marked as <emphasis>landmarks</emphasis>
          and shown in bold.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can manually alter which items are in your context
          using the context-sensitive menu for a specific item. You
          can manually make items landmarks, or remove them from the
          context.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The context that is created for you will be re-created
          when you reactivate the task at a later point.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</section>