<section id="new-features-and-developments-8.0" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                              xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>New Features and Developments</title>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Support for JavaFX AUTs</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We have added support for testing JavaFX AUTs.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        There is an example Simple Adder AUT in the
        <emphasis>&lt;installation-directory&gt;/examples/AUTs</emphasis>
        folder. You can use this to perform example tests as described
        in the cheat sheets.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can see the overview of the support via
        <link xl:href="http://eclip.se/421595">http://eclip.se/421595</link>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The toolkit is extensible, and we welcome feedback and
        contributions.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">ALM integration: Support for commenting on
    HP ALM tasks after a test run</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now connect your ITE to a HP ALM repository (version
        11+) to view tasks from the repository in the ITE.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can also add comments to tasks in a HP ALM repository when
        a test has run.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        To use the HP ALM integration, you must use a separate
        connector for HP ALM which may incur license costs. Visit the
        Tasktop website for more details
        <link xl:href="http://www.tasktop.com">http://www.tasktop.com</link>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">ALM integration: Reporting to ALM systems
    after headless execution now supported</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When a test has run via testexec, you can now trigger the
        reporting to ALM tools manually from the Test Result Summary
        View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This allows you to add the test results from your continuous
        integration tests to your issues, bugs and features in your
        ALM system.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">ALM integration: Amount of reported items
    shown</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When reporting to ALM systems takes place, you can now see how
        many tasks were reported to, how many results were written to
        each task, and a total amount of tasks written to in the
        console.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Support for embedded AUT Agent in
    testexec</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When executing tests via the command line using the
        <emphasis>testexec</emphasis> tool, you can now choose to use
        an embedded AUT Agent for the test.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This means that you do not have to start a separate AUT Agent
        on the machine you are testing on.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        To use an embedded AUT Agent, don’t enter the
        <emphasis>-server</emphasis> parameter. You can either enter a
        port number for the embedded AUT Agent to be started on, or
        you can also leave out the <emphasis>-port</emphasis>
        parameter to start the AUT Agent on a dynamically chosen port.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Create New Version is now available in the
    dbtool</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now create new versions of a Project using the dbtool.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Use
        <emphasis role="input">-createVersion &lt;project-name&gt; &lt;old-version&gt; &lt;new-version&gt;</emphasis>
        to create a new version of an existing Project.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Change tracking in Projects</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now configure in the Project properties that changes
        to Test Cases, Test Suites and Test Jobs in the Project are
        tracked. You can configure a system / environment property
        that is shown alongside the timestamp of the change to track
        e.g. who made the changes.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When change tracking is activated, when you save an editor for
        a Test Case, Test Suite or Test Job, the timestamp of the save
        as well as the property will be saved and displayed in the
        properties view.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can specify the amount of changes to track per node, or
        the length of time that change tracking information should be
        kept. Once the time has passed or the amount of changes has
        been reached, the next saving of the node will result in
        invalid change information being discarded.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can remove all change tracking information from the
        Project via the Project properties.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Support for iOS 7</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now also test AUTs written with iOS 7.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New information in Object Mapping Mode :
    property information</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        When you collect a component in the Object Mapping Mode in a
        Swing or SWT/RCP AUT, you can now see information on the
        properties of that component in the Properties View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The information is shown as a list of properties with their
        values. If a value cannot be accessed, this is communicated.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The information is not saved - to see the properties again,
        you must re-collect the component in the Object Mapping Mode.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This can be used to help you write tests that use the actions
        <emphasis>check property</emphasis> or <emphasis>store
        property</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Component match heuristic shown for each
    component in test results</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the HTML and XML test result reports, and in the result
        reports in the ITE, you can now see the value with which the
        component was found when the test was executed.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This lets you see whether a component is ”easily” found, or
        whether a small change may lead to it no longer being found,
        so that a preventative remapping may be worthwhile.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Graphics component support for
    Canvas</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now map org.eclipse.ui.forms.widgets that inherit
        directly or indirectly from canvas.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This includes, e.f. org.eclipse.ui.forms.widgets.Hyperlink.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can use actions such as click and check existence (and
        other actions on the graphics component level) on these
        components.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Show where used also available for Test
    Suites</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now use ”show where used” on Test Suites to find out
        which Test Jobs they have been reused in.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong"><emphasis role="input">»F3«</emphasis> always
    opens selected item</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now press <emphasis role="input">»F3«</emphasis> on any
        Test Case, Test Suite, or Test Job to open the specification
        of that item.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This now includes the actual original specification of the
        item itself, to avoid confusion in larger Projects.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Luna AUTs supported</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        AUTs that use the Eclipse Luna platform can also be tested
        with the ITE. This was also possible in version 7.2.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Export improved</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The export mechanism has been improved to use less memory,
        allowing larger Projects to be exported.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Toggling relevance of test runs</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now toggle the relevance of multiple test runs at
        once.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New option for content assist in the
    Component Names View</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now configure a delay for the content assist in the
        Component Names View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the Preferences (in the <emphasis>Test</emphasis> section,
        you can enter a delay in milliseconds. This amount of time
        will be waited after each character entry before opening the
        content assist.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you have many component names, and / or don’t require the
        content assist as often, then you can increase this value to
        be able to type more of your name before seeing content
        assist.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We have also adapted the behaviour of the content assist to
        not appear if you remove all of the content of the
        <emphasis>new name</emphasis> field in the Component Names
        View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can press <emphasis role="input">»ctrl+space«</emphasis> at
        any time to open the content assist.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Log files now split after 10MB</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Log files that get larger than 10MB are now automatically
        split and zipped.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Closing HTML AUTs via the close
    button</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you close a HTML AUT by closing the browser, the ITE will
        correctly notice the closure after 5 seconds (configurable)
        and will remove the AUT from the running AUTs view.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The mechanism works by polling the AUT, and if it is no longer
        there after the configured time, the AUT is considered to be
        stopped.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If your AUT may sometimes be unreachable for longer than the default 5 seconds, you can change this time by using a process or system property:<?linebreak?>
        <emphasis role="input">TEST_MAX_AUT_RESPONSE_TIME=&lt;timeInMs&gt;</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Further information on this is available in this issue:<?linebreak?>
        <link xl:href="http://bugzilla.bredex.de/1391">http://bugzilla.bredex.de/1391</link>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">p2 update site for IDE integration
    available in installer</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the <emphasis>development</emphasis> folder of the
        installation, you can now find a p2 update site containing the
        Jubula Feature and Launch Integration.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>