<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="test-result-preferences" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Test result preferences</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="prefPageTestResultContextId" xml:id="test-result-preferences.prefPageTestResultContextId" xreflabel="Test Result Preferences"/>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="testResultSummaryViewContextId" xml:id="test-result-preferences.testResultSummaryViewContextId" xreflabel="Test Result Summary View"/>
  <para>
    You can open the test result preference page by selecting
    <emphasis>Test - Test Results</emphasis> from the preference
    dialog.
  </para>
  <figure>
    <title>Test Result Preference Dialog</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/testresultprefs.png"/>
      </imageobject>
      <textobject><phrase>Test Result Preference
      Dialog</phrase></textobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Choose whether you want the Test Result View to open when
        testing begins.
      </para>
      <para>
        The Test Result View follows the test execution and shows
        which Test Steps were successful and which failed.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Choose whether you want to track the test execution progress
        in the Test Result View. When this option is activated, the
        Test Result View scrolls to follow the test progress.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Choose whether you want to automatically create a screenshot
        when a test encounters an error. Screenshots are
        automatically saved in the database and can be viewed using
        the Image View when you select the failed Test Step in the
        Test Result View.
        </para>
        <para>
        You can see the position of the mouse pointer on the screenshot. 
        The mouse position is shown as a square inverted-color area, 
        with the middle pixel being the position of the mouse pointer.
        To reproduce the original image, you select the area and invert 
        the colors in an image-editing tool.
        </para>
         <para role="warning">Screenshots are only taken of the
        primary monitor. Multiple monitors are not supported for
        screenshots.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Choose whether you want to create HTML and XML reports for
        each execution. When you activate this choice, decide
        whether you want full reports or just the errors to be
        shown. Enter a directory for the reports.
      </para>
    </listitem>
     <listitem>
      <para>
        Choose whether you want to create Monitoring reports for
        each execution. Reports will be created in the report directory.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Enter the amount of days that test result summaries should
        be displayed for. This gives you a better overview of the
        most recent results in the Test Result Summary View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
</section>