<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="test-preferences" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                             xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                             xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Test preferences</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="prefPageBasicContextId">Test Preferences</anchor>
  <figure xml:id="gdprefs">
    <title>Preference Dialog</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/gdprefs.png"/>
      </imageobject>
      <textobject><phrase>Preference Dialog</phrase></textobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para>
    In the preferences dialog, select <emphasis>Test</emphasis> from
    the tree on the left hand side.
  </para>
  <para>
    From this page, you can configure your preferences for:
  </para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Auto-scrolling and -expanding:
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When the checkbox is marked, the views and browsers
          automatically scroll in the direction you move the mouse
          when you are dragging and dropping. Trees will also be
          automatically expanded when you hover over them while
          dragging items.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Minimizing the ITE:
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When the checkbox is marked, the ITE is automatically
          minimized when test execution begins. This is useful if
          you are letting tests run on the same machine you are
          specifying on.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        AUT confirmation dialog:
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When the checkbox is marked, a dialog appears to check if
          you are sure when you click the ”<emphasis>stop
          AUT</emphasis>” button.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Original Test Case name:
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When the checkbox is activated, you can see the original
          name of a referenced Test Case in brackets behind a new
          name you enter for the Test Case. This can help you to see
          and search for Test Cases you have reused. 
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Test Step information:
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When this checkbox is activated, you see the details about
          the Test Step (the component name and type, and the
          action) in square brackets behind the Test Step name. If
          you do not want to see these details, you can deactivate
          this checkbox.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Show referenced children:
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When this option is not active, you can only see
          referenced parent Test Cases in the Test Case Browser. The
          referenced Test Cases contained in these Test Cases are
          not displayed. This action can be useful if you want to
          improve the speed of working with the ITE.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Project auto load:
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If you have selected a Project to be automatically loaded
          (<xref linkend="auto-loading-default-project"/>), then you can stop the
          auto-loading by deactivating the checkbox.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Delay for content assist in the Component Names View:
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter the amount of time in milliseconds you want to wait
          after each character entry before displaying content
          assist in the Component Names View. Increase the delay to
          see the content assist less frequently. You can see the
          content assist at any time by pressing
          <emphasis role="input">»CTRL+SPACE«</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Switching to the Execution Perspective:
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When the test begins, the ITE can automatically change to
          the Execution Perspective. You can choose to always be
          asked, to always change, or to never change. 
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
        Data files location:
      </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can specify a location where external data files (e.g.
          Excel files) are held, or use the workspace directory as
          the base location.
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          The advantage of using the
          workspace as a location for your data files is that you
          can view these in the navigator view directly in the ITE.
          Windows users can even open Excel files from the ITE using
          the In-Place editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>