<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section id="addressing-correct-component-ios" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                             xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                             xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Addressing the correct component in your iOS tests</title>
  <para>
    One of the specifics of iOS AUTs is that individual components
    such as labels on buttons are separately collectible. You can
    specify tests that will tap e.g. the label on a button, but this
    may not necessarily result in the button itself being tapped. In
    order to tap the button, it may be necessary to ensure that the
    action you perform is actually sent to the button, and not the
    label.
  </para>
  <para>
    Another example of this is when dealing with components such as
    lists and tabbed controls. You can map the individual items
    within the list or the tabbed control in order to check them or
    tap them, but it is also possible to map the whole tabbed
    control or list in order to address the items within the
    component based on their content or index. Depending on what you
    want to test, you may want one option or the other. As a general
    rule, aiming to address the higher-level component (the list
    instead of the button, for example), is usually preferable.
  </para>
  <para>
    The different types of object mapping gestures (see
    <xref linkend="object-mapping-ios"/>) ensure that you can always see which
    components are available. Part of your test design will involve
    identifying the component you want to test and choosing the
    correct technical name to map to your component name.
  </para>
</section>