<section id="how-to-read-this-manual" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>How to read this manual</title>
  <para>
    We have designed this tool to make testing easier and faster.
    However, it is a powerful application, and some of its features
    are quite sophisticated. We therefore recommend having a look at
    this manual. You can also access the manual from within the ITE by
    pressing <emphasis role="input">»F1«</emphasis>.
  </para>
  <para>
    In the reference manual, you will find information on more
    technical aspects, such as a description of the supported
    components and actions. The reference manual is also shown in the
    context-sensitive help when you press
    <emphasis role="input">»F1«</emphasis>.
  </para>
  <section id="layout">
    <title>Layout</title>
    <para>
      This manual is divided into the following chapters:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The <xref linkend="introduction"/> provides a
          background and introduction.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The <xref linkend="samples"/> exemplifies the
          capabilities of the tool, using Project examples. We
          recommend this chapter if you learn best by example.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The <xref linkend="tasks"/> provides step-by-step
          instructions for performing most of the common tasks for
          writing and executing tests. This chapter is best suited for
          those who learn by doing.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The <xref linkend="toolkit"/> gives advice and hints on working
          with AUTs written in the different supported toolkits.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The <xref linkend="user-interface"/>
          presents the user interface, describing its flexible design.
          This chapter is useful if you are not yet familiar with the
          GUI concept of the <emphasis>Eclipse</emphasis> platform.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The <xref linkend="concepts"/> introduces the
          concepts behind of the tool. It will familiarize you with
          the structure, components, and functionality of the tool.
          This chapter is useful (and recommended) for gaining
          in-depth knowledge of how everything works.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Finally, the <xref linkend="glossary"/> provides
          explanations of all technical terms and abbreviations used
          throughout this manual.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="conventions-used">
    <title>Conventions Used</title>
    <para>
       Throughout the manual,
      particular conventions are used to improve readability and
      clarity:
    </para>
    <section id="typesetting-conventions">
      <title>Typesetting Conventions</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Menu paths are shown with a grey background:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Open</emphasis>
            </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Buttons and menu options are italicized and in inverted commas:
            
            <para>
              ”<emphasis>OK</emphasis>”
            </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Input statements are shown in typewriter format:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="input">Hello</emphasis>
            </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Keyboard shortcuts and commands are in French brackets:
            
            <para>
              <emphasis role="input">»ENTER«</emphasis>
            </para>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        In addition, important warnings and informative tips are
        marked as follows:
      </para>
      <para>
        <para role="warning">This is a warning.</para> 
        <para role="tip">This is a tip.</para>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
</section>