<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="actionPrepareForAUTTermination" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                           xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                           xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <?dbhtml dir="actionPrepareForAUTTermination"?>
  <title>Prepare for AUT Termination</title>
  
  <para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Use this action together with an action to close your AUT and action to synchronize the termination and re-start of the AUT . 
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Using these actions, you can close your AUT using e.g.<?linebreak?>
          File    -->     Exit<?linebreak?>
          and have it automatically restarted.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  
  <para role="warning">
    Using the Restart option in Eclipse AUT's is not supported.
  </para>
  
    <para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Use this action shortly before an action in your test that will cause the AUT to shutdown. It must not be directly before the action to close the AUT .
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  
  <para role="warning">
    The shutdown method you choose must run through the JVM shutdown hooks to properly terminate the AUT. Do not use the restart action to shut your AUT down.
  </para>
  
  <para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Using this action ensures that the step to terminate the AUT is correctly recognized and that it can be successfully re-started using the synchronize termination and re-start action. This is achieved by delaying the time between opting to close the AUT and actually closing it so that the correct communication can take place. The default delay time is set to 2000 milliseconds, and can be altered using either an environment variable (see User Manual) or as a JVM property in the AUT configuration (see User Manual) <emphasis>TEST_AUT_KEEP_ALIVE_DELAY</emphasis>. Any test step delay specified in your Test Suite is added to this delay.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  
  <para role="warning">
    This action is currently supported on the Swing and RCP toolkits. Neither toolkit supports the terminating of AUT's using the press any key actions to press e.g. »ALT+F4«. External key combinations can be used to terminate the AUT using e.g. »ALT+F4« on RCP AUT's, but not Swing AUT's.
  </para>
  
  <para>
    This action has no parameters.
  </para>
  
</section>