<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="actionInteractAlert" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                     xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <?dbhtml dir="interactAlert"?>
  <title>Interact with Alert/Prompt/Confirmation</title>
 
 	<para><emphasis>Interact with dialog</emphasis></para>
 	<para>
     	<itemizedlist>
      		<listitem>
        		<para>
         			 Use this action to interact with (accept or dismiss) a prompt, alert or confirmation.
        		</para>
        		<para>
        			Alerts, prompts and confirmations are not shown during test execution, but they must 
        			still be handled in the test. You must use the actions to deal with the prompt, alert or
        			confirmation just before the item appears. The actions are designed to deal with the next prompt, alert or confirmation
        			that appears and not while it is already open. 
        		</para>
        		<para>
      				This action will execute the selected type of interaction which you can set by using 
      				<emphasis>Select Interaction with dialog</emphasis>.
      			</para>
      			<para>
      				You cannot use this action without executing the <emphasis>Select Interaction with dialog</emphasis>
      				right before this action. 
      			</para>
      		</listitem>
      	</itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis>Select Interaction with dialog</emphasis></para>
    <para>
    	<itemizedlist>
    		<listitem>
    			<para>
    				Use this action to select the desired type of interaction with a prompt, alert or confirmation.
    			</para>
    			<para>
    				The behavior you specify for interacting with one alert, prompt or confirmation will be taken as 
      				default for the next one. To avoid confusion in your tests, we recommend explicitly dealing with each 
      				prompt, alert or confirmation separately, even if the action for two consecutive ones is the same.
    			</para>
    			<para>
    				Use this action right before <emphasis>Interact with dialog</emphasis>.
    			</para>
    		</listitem>
    		<listitem>
        		<para>
          			Parameters:
          
          			<itemizedlist>
            			<listitem>
              				<para>
                				<xref linkend="type"/>
              				</para>
            			</listitem>
          			</itemizedlist>
        		</para>
      		</listitem>
    	</itemizedlist>
    </para>
</section>