<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="the-data-sets-view" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                               xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                               xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>The Data Sets View</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="guidancerDataSetViewContextId" xml:id="the-data-sets-view.guidancerDataSetViewContextId" xreflabel="Data Sets View"/>
  <para>
	The Data Sets View is in the lower right-hand corner of the
	Functional Test Specification Perspective by default. It lets you add, modify,
	delete and see any data for Test Cases. For each Test Case
	containing references or for each central test data set, you can
	add data sets in this view. When data in the Data Sets View are
	uneditable, they are shown in gray. Values in black may be edited.
  </para>
  <para>
    To make entering data easier, pressing
    <emphasis role="input">»ENTER«</emphasis> will spring to the next
    cell or row, or to the ”<emphasis>Add</emphasis>” button if no
    more rows have been added. The
    <emphasis role="input">»Tab«</emphasis> key springs to the
    ”<emphasis>Add</emphasis>” button.
  </para>
  <para>
    To simplify navigation, the toolbar of the Data Sets View contains the <emphasis role="strong">Jump to Central Test Data Set</emphasis> command.
    If the currently selected cell references a central data set through a <emphasis role="strong">?getCentralTestDataSetValue</emphasis>
    function call (see in <xref linkend="using-functions-as-data-for-test-cases"/>) then this command tries to identify the data set and opens
    its Editor. In case the referenced row and cell are identifiable, these are automatically selected in the
    Data Sets View (<xref linkend="the-data-sets-view"/>).
  </para>
  <para>
    The toolbar also contains the <emphasis role="strong">Show Where Used CTDS</emphasis> command.
    This can be used when a certain cell of a Central Test Data Set is selected.
    In this case all resolvable references through the <emphasis role="strong">?getCentralTestDataSetValue</emphasis> function call
    are found, and listed in the Search Result View.
    Those references which exact reference the given cell are marked by the icon <imagedata fileref="images/startOM.png"/>,
    and those which only reference the column are marked by the icon <imagedata fileref="images/stopOM.png"/>.
    Please note that only the literal references are found (e.g. those which do not use parameters, variables or other function calls).
  </para>
  
</section>