<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="creating-tasks-in-external-repositories-from-test-result-reports" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                                             xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                                             xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Creating tasks in external repositories from test result reports</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" xml:id="testResultViewContextId">Test Results View</anchor>
  <para>
    You can create a new task with pre-filled information directly
    from an open test result report in the Test Result View. This is
    useful if a test has failed and you want to create e.g. an issue
    in your bug-tracking system for the failure.
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In an open test result report, select the node that best describes the test failure (e.g. a Test Case or Test Step that has failed, or the whole Test Suite, then right-click and select:
      </para>
      
      <para>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Create a Mylyn Task</emphasis>
      </para>
      
      <para>
        from the context-sensitive menu.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the dialog that appears, select a repository in which to
        create the task. A <emphasis>local</emphasis> repository is
        available by default, but you can also add connections to
        Bugzilla and Trac repositories by clicking ”<emphasis>Add
        Task Repository</emphasis>” in the New Task Dialog.
        Connectors to other repositories can also be added. See the
        Mylyn documentation for more details on adding repositories.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Click ”<emphasis>Finish</emphasis>” once you have selected
        your repository.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The editor for a new task will appear. It is pre-filled with
        information relevant to the node that you selected. Edit the
        task to make it descriptive enough for a bug report and save
        the editor.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Once you have created a task, you can activate it to start
        saving your context for this task. See the later section
        (<xref linkend="activate-task"/>) for details.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
</section>