<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="automatically-reporting-to-external-repositories-after-test-runs" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                                             xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                                             xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Automatically reporting to external repositories after test runs</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="guidancerPropertiesViewContextId" xml:id="automatically-reporting-to-external-repositories-after-test-runs.guidancerPropertiesViewContextId" xreflabel="Properties View"/>
  <para>
    You can automatically update tasks in an external repository when a test has run. 
    You can report the test results by writing a comment on a task in the external repository 
    with a link to the test result in the ITE. 
    You can also update fields / attributes on tasks based on information 
    you specify in your Project.
  </para>
  <section xml:id="configuring-a-task-repository">
    <title>Configuring a task repository for your Project</title>
    <para>
      Once you have configured one or more repositories for your
      workspace (<xref linkend="configuring-task-repositories"/>), you can select
      one of these to be the test-relevant repository for your
      Project.
    </para>
    <para>
      This will let you:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Add a task ID from this repository to Test Cases and Test
          Suites in the Project to signify that this item is the
          test for this task (<xref linkend="adding-task-id-alm"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Automatically report test results to the task defined when
          a test runs.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          View the test results for the relevant item in the
          ITE as a link from the task repository.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">To configure a task repository for
      your Project:</emphasis>
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Project Properties, select <emphasis>Mylyn
          ALM</emphasis> from the tree on the left
          (<xref linkend="TasksALMProjectProperties"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the page that appears, you can select a repository from
          the combo-box. You can validate the repository settings
          using the button.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can (optionally) enter the URL of the ITE that is configured to use
          the correct database for your test results. If you enter its URL here, then 
          you will be able to click on test result links from 
          your task repository to open the test result in the ITE automatically.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <figure xml:id="TasksALMProjectProperties">
      <title>ALM Settings</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/almproperties.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>ALM Settings</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="configuring-reporting-to-tasks-via-properties">
  <title>Configuring reporting to tasks</title>
  	<para>
  	When a test has run, you can update relevant tasks in your repository with information:
  	</para>
  	<itemizedlist>
  	<listitem>
  	<para>
  	A comment that contains the status of the test run, and a link to the results for that test.
  	</para>
  	</listitem>
  	<listitem>
  	<para>
  	You can update fields / attributes for a task based on whether the test succeeded or failed.
  	</para>
  	<para role="tip">Tests that have a status other than <emphasis>passed</emphasis> (e.g. failed, 
  	stopped, still testing) are considered as failed</para>
  	</listitem>
  	</itemizedlist>
  	<para>
  	For each item (Test Case, Test Suite) in your test run that 
  	is linked to a task 
  	(<xref linkend="adding-task-id-alm"></xref>)
  	the rules you specify in the Project properties will be carried out to report test 
  	results to that task.
  	</para>

<orderedlist>
	<listitem>
	<para>
	In the Project Properties, select <emphasis>Mylyn ALM</emphasis> from the tree on 
	the left.
	</para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	<para>
	In the page that appears, you can configure how to report results. 
	You have the same options for what to do on success and on failure.
	</para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
		<para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
			<para>
			You can activate the checkbox to add a comment to each linked task. 
			The comment contains information about the test run (date, status) 
			and also a link to the test results. 
			The test results can be seen in the specified ITE (<xref linkend="configuring-a-task-repository"/>).
			</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			<para>
			You can add rules in the table to update attributes for the task. Enter a descriptive name 
			(this is only used for display purposes in the Properties), the ID for the attribute you want to 
			update and the value that the attribute should be updated with. 
			As values for the update, you can enter:
			</para>
			<para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
					<para>
					plain text, e.g. "passed"
					</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
					<para>
					a value from a column in the Test Result Summary View for this run.
					The value for a column is gained by entering the column name as a variable. 
					Some examples are:  
					</para>
					<para>
					$summary_autHostname, $summary_testRunState (gives e.g. "OK" or "FAILED"), $summary_testsuiteName, $summary_testJobName, 
					$summary_testsuiteEndTime,
					$summary_testsuiteDate (for full date format), $summary_statusString (gives e.g. "Successfully tested" or "Error in Children"),
					 $summary_testsuiteDuration, 
					$summary_testsuiteStartTime, $summary_date (for DD.MM.YYYY), $summary_autOS
					</para>
					<para>
					but you can use any column value by entering the column name as a variable preceded by "summary_". 
					</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
					<para>
					a value from the executed node. The value is entered as a variable, e.g.
					</para>
					<para>
					$node_taskId, $node_timeStamp, $node_typeOfNode (e.g. Test Case), $node_name, 
					$node_parameterDescription, $node_date (for DD.MM.YYYY), $node_url (see below)
					</para>
					<para>
					Use the $node_url parameter to receive the URL that will 
					link to this node (Test Case or Test Suite) in the ITE 
					(x<xref linkend="automatically-reporting-to-external-repositories-after-test-runs"/>). 
					</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
			</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	<para>
	To see which attributes are available in your ALM repository, you can view the information for 
	individual tasks from the Task View (<xref linkend="viewing-task-attributes"/>)
	</para>
	</listitem>	
</orderedlist>
	<section xml:id="viewing-task-attributes">
	<title>Viewing task attributes</title>
	<para>
	In order to define rules for reporting to ALM systems, you will need to enter the ID 
	for any attributes you wish to update (<xref linkend="configuring-reporting-to-tasks-via-properties"/>).
	</para>
	<para>
	You can see which attributes a task has by using the <emphasis role="menuPath">Show attributes</emphasis>
	option from the Task View.
	</para>
	<orderedlist>
		<listitem>
		<para>Open the Task View if it is not already open by selecting:</para>
		<para>
		<emphasis role="menuPath">Window</emphasis> --&gt; <emphasis role="menuPath">Show View</emphasis> --&gt; 
		<emphasis role="menuPath">Task View</emphasis>.
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		If you have not already configured your repository for your workspace, do so in the 
		Task Repositories View
		(<xref linkend="configuring-task-repositories"></xref>).
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		Navigate to the task whose attributes you want to see and select:
		</para>
		<para>
		<emphasis role="menuPath">Show attributes</emphasis> from the context menu.
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		The Task Attribute Viewer will appear. In this dialog, you can see the IDs 
		for the attributes for this task, which you can use to define rules for test 
		result reporting in the Project Properties 
		(<xref linkend="configuring-reporting-to-tasks-via-properties"/>).
		You can copy attributes using the keyboard.
		</para>
		</listitem>
	</orderedlist>
	
	</section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="adding-task-id-alm">
    <title>Adding task IDs to Test Suites and Test Cases</title>
    <para>
      You can add a task ID to Test Cases and Test Suites in your
      Project.
    </para>
    <para>
      The task ID should be a valid ID in the repository that you
      have specified as the repository for this Project
      (<xref linkend="configuring-a-task-repository"/>). Adding the task ID to an
      item in your Project means that this item is the relevant test
      for that task in your repository. You will be able to report
      test results for this item.
    </para>
    <para>
      To add a task ID to a Test Case or Test Suite:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open the item in the editor by double-clicking it.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Properties View, in the cell for <emphasis>Task
          ID</emphasis>, enter the task ID from the external
          repository. You can only enter task IDs at the place of
          specification – you cannot overwrite them when you reuse
          the item.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Save the editor.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you have added a task ID to a node, you can open the task for this node from the browser by selecting:
        </para>
          
        <para>
          <emphasis role="menuPath">Open with</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Mylyn Task Editor</emphasis>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para role="tip">
      You should ensure that you add task IDs to the right
      node-level to provide you with the relevant amount of
      information for the tasks in your repository. This will
      usually be at the level of Use Cases within a Test Suite.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="test-execution-with-reporting-to-external-repositories">
    <title>Test execution with reporting to external
    repositories</title>
    <para>
      If your Project is joined to an external repository
      (<xref linkend="configuring-a-task-repository"/>),
      and you have added task IDs to one or more items in your
      Project (<xref linkend="adding-task-id-alm"/>), then you will be able to
      report the test results to the repository after the test has
      run. The test run can be either via the ITE or via the command
      line <emphasis>testexec</emphasis>.
    </para>
    <para role="tip">
      If you run a "relevant" test via the ITE which should report to
      ALM systems, the reporting is triggered automatically once the
      test has run. If the reporting for the test run encounters an
      error, then you will be able to manually trigger the reporting
      later <xref linkend="test-execution-with-reporting-to-external-repositories"/>. To report to ALM
      systems after running a test via testexec, you must also
      manually trigger the recording
      (<xref linkend="test-execution-with-reporting-to-external-repositories"/>).
    </para>
    <para>
      When reporting is triggered, the following happens:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          A connection is made to the ALM system configured in the
          Project properties.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The test results are then analyzed to see if any comments
          need to be added in the external repository.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If there is reporting to be done, the ITE
          reports to each necessary task as batch jobs. These batch jobs contain 
          the desired field updates and comments. Although this is displayed as one operation in the console view
          you will get <emphasis>N</emphasis> transactions for <emphasis>N</emphasis> comments/field updates.
          If multiple items in one test run reference the 
          same task ID, or if an item with a task ID is executed multiple times in the 
          same test run, then only one comment will be written, but this one will contain information about 
          all executed items with this ID. 
          However, field updates will occur for each item linked to the task ID. 
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          Tests that have
          a status other than <emphasis>passed</emphasis> (e.g.
          failed, stopped, still testing) are considered as
          <emphasis>failed</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can see the status of the ALM reporting in the console
          view.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
       	 Once reporting has been done, you can see the changes in the external repository. 
       	 If you added a comment, you can click on the link provided to open the test result
       	  report in the ITE that you specified for your Project. 
       	  The ITE must be already running for this action to succeed. 
       	  The test results must also still be present in  
          the database (<xref linkend="re-opening-the-test-result-view-for-a-test-run"/>).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The test result report is opened at the node which
          referenced the current task ID.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can see the status of the reporting in the Test Result
          Summary View (<xref linkend="test-execution-with-reporting-to-external-repositories"/>).
        </para>
        <para role="tip">
          The integration for writing to external repositories can be
          used with Bugzilla 3.6+ and JIRA 5.0+. Other
          repositories for which there are Mylyn connectors may also
          work, but these have not been tested.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="strong">Reporting to ALM repositories after a
      test started via testexec</emphasis>
      For tests started via testexec,
      the reporting does not happen automatically. Instead, you must
      choose to report to ALM from the Test Result Summary View.
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In a Project that is configured to report to an ALM
          repository, when a test has run via testexec, you can open
          the Reporting Perspective and locate the test run in the
          Test Result Summary View.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the <emphasis>ALM Report Status</emphasis> column, you
          will see whether there are any reports pending. You can
          see various statuses in this column:
        </para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>
              Not configured:
            </term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                if you have not configured ALM reporting for the
                Project, or if the relevance of the Test Suite was set
                to false when the test was started.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>
              Not yet reported:
            </term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                if reporting was configured for the Project, and
                there is information available to be reported that
                has not yet been reported, e.g. from a test run via
                testexec. You will also see this status if you have
                run a test via the ITE that could not report to the
                ALM system due to e.g. a connection problem. This
                allows you to report test results later, once the
                problem has been resolved.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>
              Reported:
            </term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                this status will be shown if you have run a test
                with reporting configured via the ITE, which reports
                automatically. It will also be shown if you have
                chosen to report to the ALM system after running a
                test via testexec. This status will also be shown
                even if the test run was not linked to any tasks,
                but reporting is configured for the Project. It can
                be understood as <emphasis>any reporting that was
                necessary has been carried out</emphasis>.
                If an error occurs while reporting to one of the tasks, 
                the status will still show <emphasis>reported</emphasis> 
                even though not all tasks were correctly updated
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>
              Report discarded:
            </term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                if reporting information was available, but the
                information was discarded and therefore not
                reported. You can do this by selecting the option to
                discard a pending report from the context menu. This
                status will also be shown for any test runs in a
                Project that you import that had the status
                <emphasis>Not yet reported</emphasis> when the
                Project was exported.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>
              Marked as non-relevant:
            </term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                you will see this status for any test runs that were
                marked as relevant when the test was started and
                which have information to report (status:
                <emphasis>Not yet reported</emphasis>),but which you
                then mark as non-relevant by toggling the relevance
                in the Test Result Summary View. This status means
                that you could report or discard the information,
                but only if you re-toggle the test run to be
                relevant.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select any test runs whose results you want to report to
          ALM, and click on the ”<emphasis>Report to ALM</emphasis>”
          button on the toolbar. You can also select this option
          from the context-sensitive menu. If you select multiple
          test runs, the reporting will take place sequentially for
          each test run.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When you select this option, the reporting will be
          triggered as described above. If the reporting is
          successful, the status in the <emphasis>ALM Report
          Status</emphasis> column changes from <emphasis>Not yet
          reported</emphasis> to <emphasis>Reported</emphasis>. If
          an error occurs, then the status remains as <emphasis>Not
          yet reported</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If you do not want to report the test results to an ALM
          tool, you can discard the reporting information by
          selecting the option to discard a pending report from the
          context menu. This changes the status in the <emphasis>ALM
          Report Status</emphasis> column from <emphasis>Not yet
          reported</emphasis> to <emphasis>Report
          discarded</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
</section>