<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section id="using-the-data-sets-view" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                     xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Using the Data Sets View to enter data loops and to translate data</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerDataSetViewContextId">Data Sets View</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerCentralTestDataEditorContextId">Central Test Data</anchor>
  <para>
    The Data Sets View lets you do three things:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Enter multiple data sets for a parameter from a Test Case
        (<xref linkend="adding-multiple-data-sets"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Enter data sets for a central test data set
        (<xref linkend="entering-data-for-central-test-data-sets"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Translate your parameter values into other languages
        (<xref linkend="translating-test-data"/>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <para role="tip">You can also create central test data sets for your
    Project to reuse in Test Cases (<xref linkend="using-central-data-sets"/>).</para>
  </para>
  <section id="adding-multiple-data-sets">
    <title>Data Sets View: adding multiple data sets to a Test
    Case</title>
    <para>
      If your Test Case has parameters which have been referenced
      from the Test Cases and Test Steps it contains, you can enter
      <emphasis>data sets</emphasis> in the Data Sets View.
    </para>
    <para>
      This means that the Test Case will loop and be executed for
      each set of data you enter.
    </para>
    <para>
      To enter data sets for a Test Case:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open the Test Case Editor or Test Suite Editor by
          double-clicking on the Test Case or Test Suite you want to
          edit in the browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the editor, single-click the Test Case you want to add
          data to.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Data Sets View, make sure the language in the combo
          box on the right is the right language for your data.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select ”<emphasis>Add</emphasis>” to add a row.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Enter the values for the parameters in the row. <para role="tip">You
          can also add references in the Data Sets View if you want
          to specify the concrete values for your data sets when you
          reuse this Test Case. </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Use the buttons in the Data Sets View to add more rows,
          delete rows (if no row is selected, the last row is
          deleted) and insert rows above the currently selected row.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="translating-test-data">
    <title>Data Sets View: translating test data</title>
    <para>
      You can add data for other languages supported by your AUT by
      changing the language in the combo box in the Data Sets View.
    </para>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">You can add supported languages in the Project
      properties dialog (<xref linkend="projectproperties"/>).</para>
    </para>
    <para>
      The other combo boxes are there to help you see the Data Sets
      View in different ways. You can see all the data for one
      parameter, for one data set or for one language.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>