<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="tasksdblogin" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                         xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Logging in to the database</title>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Projects are stored in a database. Before you can access a
        Project, you have to log in to the database.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The log-in dialog for the database (<xref linkend="dblogin"/>)
        appears automatically the first time you need it (e.g. when
        you try to open or create a Project).
      </para>
      <figure xml:id="dblogin">
        <title>Database login</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/dblogin.png"/>
          </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>Database login</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para role="tip">
        If you are using the default demo (embedded)
        database, you will automatically be logged into the
        database.
      </para>
      <para role="warning">
        We do not recommend using the embedded database for
        productive use.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Select the database you want to use and enter your username
        and password.
      </para>
      <para role="tip">
        If you previously had another ITE version installed,
        you may see the information that your current database
        version is not compatible with the latest version. If this
        is the case, please follow the migration instructions in the
        Installation Manual.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you want to save your database password, select the checkbox to store it in the secure store. You can edit your password settings in the preferences via:
      </para>
      
      <para>
        <emphasis>General/Security/Secure Store</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Once you have opted to save your password, you can also choose whether you want to perform an automatic login to this database when you use this workspace. If you select this option, then the next time you open the ITE and e.g. select:
      </para>
      
      <para>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Open</emphasis>
      </para>
      
      <para>
        you will be automatically connected to this database with the username and password you entered.
      </para>
      <para role="tip">
        You cannot perform auto-login for an embedded database unless it is the only database configured.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can change your auto-login details or select another database at any time by selecting:
      </para>
      
      <para>
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Select database...</emphasis>
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
</section>