<section id="new-features-and-developments-5" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                            xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                            xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>New features and developments</title>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Code coverage</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Jubula now lets you run code coverage for Java applications
        written in Java 1.5 or higher.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The code coverage tool <emphasis>JaCoCo</emphasis> is
        supported out-of-the-box and can be added to your AUT
        configuration in the AUT configuration dialog.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can view the results of the code coverage monitoring from
        the Test Result Summary View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Teststyle</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Jubula has a new feature to improve the quality and structure
        of the tests you write.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The <emphasis>Teststyle</emphasis> plugin lets you define
        guidelines for your Project and informs you when a guideline
        is not upheld.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can set the message level (information, warning, error)
        for the guidelines as well as the context they should be valid
        for.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <emphasis>Teststyle</emphasis> is added by default to all
        Projects. You can alter the Teststyle settings via the Project
        properties.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New license mechanism</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The license mechanism in Jubula has been changed.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Jubula no longer uses a license server to manage floating
        licenses. The new individual user licenses can be requested
        from the Jubula team as part of your maintenance contract.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The licenses can be entered in the Preferences, under:
        <emphasis>Jubula - Licenses</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">ID Attribute Name for HTML AUTs</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Each supported component in HTML AUTs can have its own
        attribute used to identify it during test execution.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In your AUT configuration, you can define an attribute name
        which should be used as an identifier for components.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        For example if your attribute name is: <emphasis role="input">testid</emphasis><?linebreak?>
        (e.g. <emphasis role="input">&lt;div testid=''Username''&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</emphasis>)<?linebreak?>
        then you would enter <emphasis>testid</emphasis> in the AUT configuration.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Test debugging - continue without Event
    Handler</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        There is a new option in Jubula to make running interactive
        tests more comfortable.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        On the toolbar, there is a new button to ”<emphasis>Continue
        without Event Handler</emphasis>”. You can use this button in
        combination with the ”<emphasis>Pause on Error</emphasis>”
        option.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If a test you are running encounters an error, the test is
        paused die to the <emphasis>Pause on Error</emphasis> option.
        You can then click ”<emphasis>Continue without Event
        Handler</emphasis>” to ignore the error and continue as if no
        error had occurred.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Copy ID to clipboard and open Test Case
    via its ID</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        There is a new option in the Test Case Browser to copy the
        unique ID for a Test Case to the clipboard.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can use this ID to refer to the Test Case from external
        systems such as bug-tracking systems or requirements
        management systems.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can open a Test Case based on its ID by pressing
        <emphasis role="input">»Shift+F9«</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Support information package</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        To reflect the changes to the support system, the option to
        send a support email has been updated to create a .zip file as
        a support information package.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Should you find an error, you can upload the information
        package to Bugzilla as a part of the error description.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New database configuration</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The configuration tool and database configuration tool are no
        longer a part of the installation package.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The configuration options for the database connections are now
        in the preferences under: <emphasis>Test - Database
        Connections</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The embedded database is configured as the default. You can
        add other database configurations using the buttons and the
        dialog to add database connection details.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can export and import your database preferences using the
        <emphasis role="menuPath">File</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Export</emphasis> menu.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New -data parameter in the test executor
    and dbtool</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        As the database configurations are now in the preferences, you
        must enter a workspace (where the correct preferences are
        saved) for test execution via the test executor and for
        working with the dbtool.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The workspace parameter is
        <emphasis role="input">»-data &lt;path to workspace&gt;«</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The workspace parameter cannot currently be entered in the
        configuration file for the test executor, it must be entered
        directly into the command line interface.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Project migration to the new
    version</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We have changed our database abstraction layer from Hibernate
        to JPA/Eclipse Link.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        For this reason, the migration of your Projects to the new
        version cannot be carried out automatically by the database
        migration tool.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Instructions on migrating your Projects and clearing your
        database scheme are in the Installation Manual.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Amount of results shown in the Test Result
    Summary View is now configurable</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now configure how many results should be shown in the
        Test Result Summary View based on how old they are.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the <emphasis>Test result</emphasis> preferences, you can
        specify how many days’ worth of test result summaries should
        be shown. The default is set to 30 days.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can see the current setting in the Test Result Summary
        View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Results not displayed are not removed from the database and
        are still considered for report generation. They are simply
        not visible to make filtering and sorting over more recent
        results more comfortable.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Two new BIRT reports</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        There are two new reports that can be generated from the Test
        Result Summary View.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The first is a report that shows code coverage for the chosen
        Test Suites.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The second is a report that shows any comments written for
        unsuccessful Test Suites which can be used as a daily summary
        of the test status.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">BIRT reports show comment title for
    executed Test Steps</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you have a BIRT report which shows the executed Test Steps
        for a Test Suite, you can hover over the point on the graph
        marking the number of executed Test Steps to see the title of
        any comment you wrote for the test run.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If the expected Test Steps and executed Test Steps are the
        same (i.e. the whole test ran), you will not see the comment.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Test execution speed increased</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We have significantly increased the speed at which tests are
        executed.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Should you want to slow a test down to watch it, then you can
        set a <emphasis>step delay</emphasis> in the Properties View
        for the Test Suite.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You may notice that some tests require explicit
        synchronization (e.g. waiting for windows to appear or to
        close) to ”keep up” with the increased speed. If you prefer,
        then adding a <emphasis>step delay</emphasis> of 1000(ms)
        should produce the test execution speed from previous
        versions.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Extensions must be adapted</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        As there have been changes to our API, any extensions you are
        using in your Projects must be adapted to the new changes.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The largest change is that package prefixes have been changed.
        Instead of <emphasis role="input">com.bredexsw.guidancer</emphasis>, the new
        name is <emphasis role="input">org.eclipse.jubula</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Other changes include modified class names (the GD prefix has
        been removed or replaced by JB).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Your client and RC (server) extensions must be adjusted and
        recompiled with the new Jar files.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Support for div containers in
    HTML</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We now support components created using
        &lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; containers on the level of
        <emphasis>Graphics Component</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This means you will be able to perform certain checks on such
        components and also send clicks to them.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Support for lists in HTML</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        You can now check the existence of entries in lists created in
        HTML using the &lt;ol&gt; and &lt;ul&gt; tags.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Support for sliders, date and time,
    spinner and scale components in SWT</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The SWT components <emphasis>slider, date and time,
        spinner</emphasis> and <emphasis>scale</emphasis> components
        in SWT are now supported as <emphasis>Graphics
        Components</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This means you will be able to perform certain checks on the
        components as well as click them or in them.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New names for various Jubula
    components</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        We have renamed various parts of Jubula:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            What we previously referred to as the client (the
            application where tests are written) is now known as the
            Integrated Test Environment (ITE).
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The <emphasis>gdrun</emphasis> command for starting AUTs
            is now called <emphasis>autrun</emphasis>. The command is
            also now called <emphasis role="input">autrun</emphasis> and must be changed
            in any scripts that use it.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The command line client for test execution is now called
            the <emphasis>test executor</emphasis>. The command is
            called <emphasis role="input">testexec</emphasis> and must be changed in any
            scripts that use it.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The RCP Accessor is now called the RCP Remote Control
            Plugin.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The environment variables that can be used in Jubula have
            also been renamed:
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                <emphasis>GD_COMP_NAME</emphasis> (used for setting a
                unique name for RCP components) is now called
                <emphasis>TEST_COMP_NAME</emphasis>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                <emphasis>GDAutStarterPort</emphasis> (used to set a
                default port number for the system) is now called
                <emphasis>TEST_AUT_AGENT_PORT</emphasis>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                <emphasis>GDUDV_</emphasis> (used to set your own
                environment variables is now called
                <emphasis>TEST_UDV</emphasis>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The pre-defined test execution variables are now
                preceded with <emphasis>TEST_</emphasis> instead of
                <emphasis>GD_</emphasis>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New perspective names</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The perspectives have been renamed. Each perspective type
        (specification, reporting, execution) is preceded by
        <emphasis>Functional Testing</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New and moved menu options</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The ITE now contains a menu point:<emphasis role="menuPath">File</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        This menu allows you to import and export database preferences
        to Jubula, to save, rename, refresh and exit the ITE.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The previous <emphasis role="menuPath">Project</emphasis> menu is now called
        <emphasis role="menuPath">Test</emphasis>. Here you will find the menu options that
        used to be under <emphasis role="menuPath">Project</emphasis>, including creating,
        deleting, importing and exporting Projects.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Moved preferences</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The preferences for the test can now be found in the
        preference dialog under the option <emphasis>Test</emphasis>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">New BIRT version</emphasis>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        If you create your own reports for Jubula from this version,
        then you must use version 2.6.1 of the BIRT viewer and engine.
        Our reports are created with this version of BIRT and Eclipse
        version 3.6.1.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>