<section id="geftest" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Testing GEF AUTs</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="projectWizardContextId">Creating a Project</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="autConfigSettingWizardPagePageContextId">Configuring an AUT</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="autConfigPropDialogContextId">Adding/editing AUT configurations</anchor>
  <para>
    The GEF toolkit is a sub-toolkit of RCP. To be able to test AUTs
    that contain GEF components, you must select
    <emphasis>RCP</emphasis> as the toolkit in the Project properties.
  </para>
  <para>
    The same points about the RCP Remote Control plugin and the
    keyboard files mentioned in the section on RCP AUTs (<xref linkend="rcpaut"/>)
    are also valid for testing AUTs with GEF components.
  </para>
  <para>
    Testing GEF components is a little different to testing other
    components, because we highly recommend that the software
    developers use our accessibility plug-in in the AUT to make the
    testing of GEF components more robust.
  </para>
  <para>
    <para role="tip">GEF testing is supported from GEF version 3.0 up to but not
    including 4.0. We test our GEF support on GEF version 3.7.2.</para>
  </para>
  <section id="testing-gef-components">
    <title>Testing GEF components</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="inspectorViewContextId">GEF Inspector View</anchor>
    <para>
      Like other tests, tests for GEF components are based on the component, action, parameter
      principle. However, it is important to note that individual figures are not addressed
      using component names. The only component that is mapped in GEF
      is the <emphasis>figure canvas</emphasis>. The figures on the canvas are
      tested by referring to their textpath. See the Reference Manual
      for more details on the GEF actions.
    </para>
    <para>
      <para role="tip">The observation mode cannot be used to record actions in the canvas.</para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="using-the-gef-inspector">
    <title>Using the GEF inspector</title>
    <anchor role="helpid" id="inspectorViewContextId">GEF Inspector View</anchor>
    <para>
      The GEF Inspector View in the ITE allows you to collect information
      about the textpath to an item from within your RCP AUT. For many
      of the actions on GEF figures, you will need to know the
      textpath. Using the accessibility plug-in will mean that the
      textpaths will be easier to determine without the inspector. See
      the extension manual for further information on creating your
      own accessibility plug-in.
    </para>
    <para>
      To use the inspector, you must have started the AUT
      (<xref linkend="starting-the-aut"/>).
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open the GEF Inspector View if it is not already open via:
          
          <para>
            <emphasis role="menuPath">Window</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Show View</emphasis>--&gt;<emphasis role="menuPath">Other</emphasis>
          </para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the Inspector View, select the AUT you want to inspect in from
          the drop-down menu next to the <emphasis>activate
          inspector</emphasis> button.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click on an item to inspect it. <para role="tip">Make sure that the
          AUT is in focus before inspecting the figure. You may need
          to click in the title bar once to do this.</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the GEF Inspector View, the path to the item will be shown. If
          the code for your AUT uses the accessibility code, then the
          textpath will be less complex and more readable.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can copy the textpath from the Inspector View via the
          context-menu and paste it as a parameter in your Test Cases.
          <para role="tip">You will need to activate the inspector for each item
          you want to inspect</para>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
</section>