<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section xml:id="no-component-type-exists-message-in-component-names-view" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                                     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                                     xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>No component type exists message in Component Names View</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" condition="compNameViewContextId" xml:id="no-component-type-exists-message-in-component-names-view.compNameViewContextId">Component Names View</anchor>
  <para>
    This situation occurs when a component name that has been
    propagated and then renamed at the place of reuse is no longer
    accessible, either because:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        the name with which the component was propagated has been
        changed, or
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        the checkbox to propagate the component name has been
        deactivated.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    In such situations, you will see the message in the Component Names View :
  </para>
  
  <para>
    <emphasis>No Component Type Exists!</emphasis>.
  </para>
  
  <para role="tip">
    Saving the Test Case will remove the message, however,
    you may want to take steps to transfer the component name before
    removing the message.
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        An example of a situation where this occurs:
      </para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You have a Test Case <emphasis>TC1</emphasis> that has a
            component name propagated from it:
            <emphasis>nn_nn_grc</emphasis>.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You reused the <emphasis>TC1</emphasis> Test Case in
            another Test Case called <emphasis>TC2</emphasis>, and
            renamed the component name to
            <emphasis>LoginDialog_OK_btn</emphasis> at the place of
            reuse.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You then either:
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                change the component name in the original Test Case
                to ”<emphasis>LoginDialog_AnyButton_btn</emphasis>”,
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                or you deactivate the checkbox for propagating the
                component name from the original Test Case.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the Component Names View for the reused Test Case in
        <emphasis>TC2</emphasis>, you will see a warning message
        that the component name has no type.
      </para>
      <para role="warning">
        The warning field is not editable.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Depending on whehter you renamed the component name or
        removed the checkbox, you can now do one of two things:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            If you renamed the component name in the original Test
            Case (<emphasis>TC1</emphasis>, then you can locate the
            newly propagated name in the Component Names View and
            enter the <emphasis>new name</emphasis> for the no
            longer existent component type in the <emphasis>new
            name</emphasis> field for the newly propagated name.
            This essentially points the previous component name
            hierarchy onto the new one.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            If you deactivated the checkbox, or if you do not want
            to transfer the name as mentioned above, you can simply
            make any change to the Test Case and then save it. The
            message will disappear.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>