<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section id="entering-and-reassigning-component-names-in-the-component-names-view" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                                                 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                                                 xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Entering and reassigning component names in the Component Names View</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="compNameViewContextId">Component Names View</anchor>
  <para>
    <para role="tip">The following section deals with entering component names
    in the Component Names View when you have added Test Cases from
    the library. For information on component names in Test Steps,
    see the Test Steps section (<xref linkend="specsteps"/>).</para>
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Once you have added a Test Case from the library of Test
        Cases (<xref linkend="creating-tests-from-the-library-of-pre-defined-test-cases"/>), you will need to enter a
        component name for the component you want to test.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the Component Names View, you will see the <emphasis>old
        name</emphasis> for this component, which was given in the
        Test Step contained in the library Test Case. The old name
        is just a placeholder and should be
        <emphasis>reassigned</emphasis> (<xref linkend="compnamesview"/>).
      </para>
      <figure id="compnamesview">
        <title>The Component Names View</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/compnamesview.png"/>
          </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The Component Names
          View</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        <para role="tip">When you enter a component name in the Component
        Names View, you create a new reference to a component in the
        AUT. This component name appears in the Object Mapping
        Editor to be mapped to a component in your AUT. A Test Case
        containing component names to be reassigned can therefore be
        used at a variety of different places to test different
        actual components. If you want to rename a component name,
        you can do so in the Component Names Browser
        (<xref linkend="renaming-component-names"/>).</para>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In the <emphasis>new name</emphasis> field, enter your name
        for this component, e.g.
        <emphasis role="input">MainWindow_NavigationTree_tre</emphasis>.
      </para>
      <para>
        We recommend using naming conventions for component names.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Press <emphasis role="input">»CTRL+SPACE«</emphasis> to see a
        list of component names you have already used for this type
        of component:
      </para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            <mediaobject role="icon" file="images/localName.png"/> <emphasis>Local</emphasis>
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              component names are names you have used in this Test
              Case for this component type .
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            <mediaobject role="icon" file="images/globalName.png"/> <emphasis>Global</emphasis>
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              component names are names you have used for this
              component type, but not in this Test Case.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>
        <para role="tip">You can configure how frequently the content assist
        in the Component Names View should open in the preferences.</para>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The component name you enter here will be collected by the
        Object Mapping Editor when you carry out object mapping so
        that you can assign it to a component in the AUT.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Every time you want to carry out an action on this
        component, use this name.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para>
    <para role="tip">See the section on the component hierarchy for some tips
    on using component names in your tests
    (<xref linkend="understanding-the-component-hierarchy"/>).</para>
  </para>
</section>