<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section id="understanding-the-component-hierarchy" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                                  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                                  xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <title>Understanding the component hierarchy</title>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="guidancerComponentNameBrowserContextId">Component Name Browser</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="compNameViewContextId">Component Names View</anchor>
  <anchor role="helpid" id="objectMapEditorContextId">Object Mapping</anchor>
  <para>
    The component hierarchy is designed to allow flexible test
    specification and robust tests.
  </para>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Abstract components</emphasis>
  </para>
  <para>
    You can write tests very abstractly at the beginning, only
    adding detail later. You will notice that the library contains
    categories such as <emphasis>Component with Text Input</emphasis> and
    <emphasis>Graphics Component</emphasis>.
  </para>
  <para>
    These are <emphasis>abstract components</emphasis> – actions in these categories can be used on a wide range of actual components in the AUT. You can use a <emphasis>Click</emphasis> action on the <emphasis>Graphics Component</emphasis> to click any component in the AUT. You just need to enter different component names for it in the Component Names View.
  </para>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Using the same component name for different component types</emphasis>
  </para>
  <para>
    What happens if you want to specify a test that clicks in a
    table and then selects a cell in the table?
  </para>
  <para>
    The click action is on the <emphasis>Graphics Component</emphasis> and the
    select cell action is on the <emphasis>Table</emphasis> component – but you
    don’t want to have two different component names.
  </para>
  <para>
    This isn’t a problem. You can use the same component name for
    different components as long as these are compatible. So, in
    this case, the <emphasis>Graphics Component</emphasis> and the
    <emphasis>Table</emphasis> component can both use the component name e.g.
    <emphasis>TableView_MainTable_tbl</emphasis>.
  </para>
  <para>
    <para role="warning">You cannot use the same component name for incompatible types, for example, trees and tables.</para>
  </para>
</section>