<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2014 BREDEX GmbH.
  All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
  are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
  which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
  http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
-->

<section id="actionActivateApplication" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
                                                      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                                                      xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >
  <?dbhtml dir="actionActivateApplication"?>
  <title>Activate application</title>
  
  <para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          When the ITE and AUT Agent are running on the same computer, you may need to bring the AUT into focus before a test can begin.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Exactly how to activate the application can vary from one system to another.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          This action offers various different ways of activating the application.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          This action is performed by clicking in the location indicated in the activation method parameter.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In the AUT configuration (see user manual), the default is that no activation is carried out.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          You can set an activation method for the whole AUT in its configuration, and use this in your Test Steps (e.g. set the activation method parameter to "AUT_DEFAULT") or you can use a different activation method.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          In this way, you can centrally define a default for a given operating system, which you can easily change when you test on another operating system.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Using the activate action, you can also specify activation methods which differ from the default.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  
  <para role="tip">
    This action is used to ensure that an AUT has the current focus. It cannot be used to maximize a minimized AUT.
  </para>
</section>